<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="atom-to-html.xsl"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Starred articles</title>
<generator uri="http://tt-rss.org/">Tiny Tiny RSS/17.4 (3b8d9bc)</generator>
<updated>2017-10-04T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost/tt-rss/public.php?op=rss&amp;id=-1&amp;key=vyn7su59c7b50850ac3</id>
<link href="http://localhost/tt-rss/public.php?op=rss&amp;id=-1&amp;key=vyn7su59c7b50850ac3" rel="self"/>

<link href="http://localhost/tt-rss" rel="alternate"/>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-12-07:/347261</id>
	<link href="http://phys.org/news/2016-12-strong-gravity-earth.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">How strong is the force of gravity on Earth?</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Gravity is a pretty awesome fundamental force. If it wasn't for the Earth's comfortable 1 g, which c...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Gravity is a pretty awesome fundamental force. If it wasn't for the Earth's comfortable 1 g, which causes objects to fall towards the Earth at a speed of 9.8 m/s&sup2;, we'd all float off into space. And without it, all us terrestrial species would slowly wither and die as our muscles degenerated, our bones became brittle and weak, and our organs ceased to function properly.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-12-07T14:20:01+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2016-12-07T14:20:01+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="space exploration"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="http://cdn.phys.org/newman/csz/news/tmb/2016/howstrongist.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-12-02:/345982</id>
	<link href="http://www.skyandtelescope.com/astronomy-news/nasa-cassini-ring-grazing-orbits/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">The Beginning of the End for Cassini</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cassini's final main engine burn this weekend sets the stage for a stunning grand finale.
An artist'...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><span><strong><em>Cassini's final main engine burn this weekend sets the stage for a stunning grand finale.</em></strong></span></p>
<div><img src="http://www.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/2861_cassini_proximal_768.jpg" alt="Cassini at Saturn" width="480" height="274" srcset="http://www.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/2861_cassini_proximal_768.jpg 480w, http://www.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/2861_cassini_proximal_768-300x171.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 480px) 100vw, 480px"><p>An artist's conception of NASA's Cassini spacecraft on its final ring-grazing orbits.<br><em>NASA / JPL / Cassini</em></p></div>
<p>After more than a decade exploring the ringed planet and its moons, NASA's Cassini spacecraft is preparing for a <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/feature/jpl/nasa-saturn-mission-prepares-for-ring-grazing-orbits" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">daring set of orbits</a> which will set it up for mission's end later next year.</p>
<p>The recent 125th&nbsp;flyby of Saturn's giant moon Titan (T-125) was the prelude to Cassini's final acts, which will play out over the next year. That pass placed Cassini in a high-inclination orbit tilted 60&deg; relative to the ring plane. Cassini will perform 20 passes just 620 miles (1000 kilometers) outside the F ring of Saturn in a phase known as the <a href="https://saturn.jpl.nasa.gov/news/2966/ring-grazing-orbits/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Ring-Grazing Orbits</a>, which runs from <a href="https://saturn.jpl.nasa.gov/news/2861/2016-saturn-tour-highlights/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">late November 2016</a> through April 2017.</p>
<div><img src="http://www.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/Cassini_finalorbits_trajectory.gif" alt="Cassini's final orbits" width="600" height="311"><p>Extended mission solstice orbits (blue) versus the upcoming ring grazing orbits (tan). <br><em>NASA / JPL / Cassini</em></p></div>
<p>Cassini already reached <em>apoapse</em>, or its farthest point from Saturn, on Wednesday, November 30th. The first ring crossing is coming right up this weekend on Sunday, December 4th, at 7:09 a.m. EST / 13:09 UT. During the first periapse pass on Sunday, Cassini will also burn its main engine for the 183rd&nbsp;and final time for the mission. All later fine course corrections will be made using thrusters only.</p>
<p>Things get even more interesting after April, when the series of Grand Finale Orbits will begin, taking the spacecraft through the 1240-mile-wide (2000-kilometer-wide) gap between the planet's cloud tops and rings for 22 final orbits. The Grand Finale Orbits start with the spacecraft's 126th&nbsp;and final pass near Titan, which will set the spacecraft up for much tighter final orbits.</p>
<p></p>
<p>After a mission spanning two full decades, Cassini is scheduled to burn up in Saturn's atmosphere on September 15th, 2017.</p>
<h3>Saturn's Science Closeup</h3>
<p>The interesting science returns will come from observations of the F&nbsp; and outer A rings. "The F-ring is amazing," says Cassini project scientist Linda Spilker (Jet Propulsion Laboratory). "500 kilometers wide, this ring is ever-changing with bright streamers and tenuous filaments sometimes flowing out from it. At other times, the moon Prometheus dips in and out of the F ring, creating channels in the ring material."</p>
<p>Three new science campaigns will get underway this weekend:</p>
<ul>
<li>Measurement of Saturn's magnetic and gravitational fields to probe the planet's internal structure and rotation rate;</li>
<li>An evaluation on the total mass of the planet's ring system in an effort to determine its age;</li>
<li>And finally, an analysis on the innermost radiation belts and possible direct sampling of the ring particles and Saturn's upper atmosphere.</li>
</ul>
<div><img src="http://www.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/7562_PIA20509.jpg" alt="Saturn plus rings" width="600" height="600" srcset="http://www.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/7562_PIA20509.jpg 600w, http://www.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/7562_PIA20509-113x113.jpg 113w, http://www.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/7562_PIA20509-190x190.jpg 190w, http://www.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/7562_PIA20509-360x360.jpg 360w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px"><p>A looming Saturn and its extensive ring system. The moon Mimas is visible to the lower left.<br><em>NASA / JPL-Caltech / Space Science Institute</em></p></div>
<p>Cassini's Radio Science package will transmit towards Earth during each plane crossing, providing a long sweeping profile on each occultation pass. The spacecraft will also get great views of Saturn's poles, including the strange hexagon feature that graces the planet's north pole. Cassini's Visual and Infrared Mapping Spectrometer is set to chronicle its nine-hour passage over the north pole, giving us unparalleled views. Cassini will also measure the upper boundaries of Saturn's atmosphere in preparation for direct sampling on final passes late next year.</p>
<p>Cassini will target Saturn's moons as well. Expect to see closeups of the active ice geysers dotting the south pole of <a href="https://saturn.jpl.nasa.gov/science/enceladus/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Enceladus</a> one more time. Cassini will also image red-striped Tethys and the tiny shepherd moons Pan, Pandora, Atlas, and Daphnis, giving us the best views of these worldlets yet. Flybys of Pan and Daphnis occur in January and March respectively, from about 22,000 kilometers away.</p>
<div><img src="http://www.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/7554_PIA20508_full.jpg" alt="Prometheus and F ring" width="600" height="600" srcset="http://www.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/7554_PIA20508_full.jpg 600w, http://www.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/7554_PIA20508_full-113x113.jpg 113w, http://www.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/7554_PIA20508_full-190x190.jpg 190w, http://www.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/7554_PIA20508_full-360x360.jpg 360w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px"><p>Saturn's moon Prometheus and the outer F ring. <br><em>NASA / JPL-Caltech / Space Science Institute</em></p></div>
<p>And speaking of moons, Cassini will be on the lookout for structures in the rings known as <em>propellers</em>, which betray the presence on tiny moons braiding and disrupting the rings. Scientists have named some of the propellers discovered so far after famous aviators, such as Amelia Earhart.</p>
<h3>Cassini: Decades of Exploration</h3>
<p>Launched atop a Titan IV rocket on October 15, 1997, Cassini arrived at Saturn on July 1, 2004 after a slingshot maneuver past Venus, Earth and Jupiter. The mission also delivered the <a href="http://sci.esa.int/cassini-huygens/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">European Space Agency's Huygens lander</a> to Titan, which performed the most distant landing ever on January 14, 2005.</p>
<p>Powered by a plutonium-238 fueled Radioisotope Thermoelectric Generator (RTG), Cassini has delivered some amazing science.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Two of Cassini's most astonishing discoveries are the global liquid water ocean on Enceladus, with possible hydrothermal vents on its seafloor which point to an ocean that may be habitable,&rdquo; says Spilker. &ldquo;The second is the lakes and seas of liquid methane at Titan's north pole and the incredibly Earth-like surface that we see on Titan.&rdquo;</p>
<p>So enjoy this final year at Saturn: there isn't another mission to the ringed planet in the planetary exploration pipeline. The concept of a floating <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Titan_Mare_Explorer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Titan Mare Explorer</a> (TiME) was in the running during the last 2011&nbsp;<a href="http://astroguyz.com/2011/03/10/10-03-11-a-planetary-exploration-wish-list/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Planetary Decadal Survey</a>, but never made it past the proposal stage.</p>
<p>It'll be a long time before we visit Saturn again.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://www.skyandtelescope.com/astronomy-news/nasa-cassini-ring-grazing-orbits/" target="_blank">The Beginning of the End for Cassini</a> appeared first on <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://www.skyandtelescope.com" target="_blank">Sky &amp; Telescope</a>.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-12-02T16:01:25+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>David Dickinson</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.skyandtelescope.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.skyandtelescope.com"/>
		<updated>2016-12-02T16:01:25+00:00</updated>
		<title>Sky &amp; Telescope</title></source>

	<category term="astronomy blogs"/>

	<category term="astronomy in space with david dickinson"/>

	<category term="news"/>

	<category term="solar system"/>

	<category term="spacecraft and space missions"/>

	<category term="cassini"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-12-01:/345577</id>
	<link href="http://phys.org/news/2016-12-nasa-sun-observing-iris-mission.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">NASA's Sun-observing IRIS mission</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While it seems static from our vantage point on Earth 93 million miles away, the sun is constantly c...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While it seems static from our vantage point on Earth 93 million miles away, the sun is constantly changing. Under the influence of complex magnetic forces, material moves throughout the solar atmosphere and can burst forth in massive eruptions.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-12-01T18:47:30+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2016-12-01T18:47:30+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="space exploration"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-11-23:/343354</id>
	<link href="http://physicsworld.com/cws/article/news/2016/nov/22/gravity-measured-using-a-bose-einstein-condensate-on-a-chip" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Gravity measured using a Bose–Einstein condensate on a chip</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>New high-precision gravimeter could be deployed in a backpack</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>New high-precision gravimeter could be deployed in a backpack<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/PhysicsWorld/~4/DJrB_iB1HdU" height="1" width="1" alt=""></p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-11-22T16:23:27+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://physicsworld.com/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://physicsworld.com/"/>
		<updated>2016-11-22T16:23:27+00:00</updated>
		<title>physicsworld.com: all content</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-11-14:/340660</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-11/e-tsm111416.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Tiny super magnets could be the future of drug delivery</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Elsevier) Microscopic crystals could soon be zipping drugs around your body, taking them to disease...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>Elsevier</i>) Microscopic crystals could soon be zipping drugs around your body, taking them to diseased organs. In the past, this was thought to be impossible -- the crystals, which have special magnetic properties, were so small that scientists could not control their movement. But now a team of Chinese researchers has found the solution, and their discovery has opened new applications that could use these crystals to improve -- and perhaps even save -- many lives.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-11-14T05:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2016-11-14T05:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Chemistry, Physics and Materials Sciences</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-11-03:/337759</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-11/tiof-gia110216.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">GRAPES-3 indicates a crack in Earth's magnetic shield</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Tata Institute of Fundamental Research) The GRAPES-3 muon telescope, the largest and most sensitive...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>Tata Institute of Fundamental Research</i>) The GRAPES-3 muon telescope, the largest and most sensitive cosmic ray monitor recorded a burst of galactic cosmic rays that indicated a crack in the Earth's magnetic shield. The burst occurred when a giant cloud of plasma ejected from the solar corona struck Earth at a very high speed causing massive compression of the Earth's magnetosphere and triggering a severe geomagnetic storm.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-11-03T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2016-11-03T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Chemistry, Physics and Materials Sciences</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-11-02:/337500</id>
	<link href="http://phys.org/news/2016-11-magndata-database-magnetic.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">MAGNDATA: Towards a database of magnetic structures</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The quantitative characterisation of the magnetic ordering realised in magnetic phases is an essenti...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The quantitative characterisation of the magnetic ordering realised in magnetic phases is an essential part of research into the magnetic properties of solids.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-11-02T13:45:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2016-11-02T13:45:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="condensed matter"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="http://cdn.phys.org/newman/csz/news/tmb/2016/magndatatowa.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-10-26:/335417</id>
	<link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/10/161025115757.htm" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">3-D-printed magnets: How can you produce a magnet with exactly the right magnetic field?</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>How can you produce a magnet with exactly the right magnetic field? A research team now has a soluti...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>How can you produce a magnet with exactly the right magnetic field? A research team now has a solution: for the first time, they have created magnets with a 3D printer.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-10-25T15:57:57+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/"/>
		<updated>2016-10-25T15:57:57+00:00</updated>
		<title>Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily</title></source>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://images.sciencedaily.com/2016/10/161025115757.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-10-26:/335381</id>
	<link href="http://phys.org/news/2016-10-gravitational-wave-observatory-space.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Next step towards a gravitational-wave observatory in space</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, ESA has invited European scientists to propose concepts for the third large mission in its sc...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, ESA has invited European scientists to propose concepts for the third large mission in its science programme, to study the gravitational Universe.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-10-26T10:18:57+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2016-10-26T10:18:57+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="astronomy"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="http://cdn.phys.org/newman/csz/news/tmb/2016/nextsteptowa.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-10-19:/333534</id>
	<link href="http://www.skyandtelescope.com/astronomy-news/nasa-juno-jupiter-engine-anomaly/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">NASA’s Juno Suffers Engine Anomaly, Briefly Enters Safe Mode</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Engineers have decided to keep the Jupiter probe, Juno, in its current orbit until an issue with its...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><span><strong><em>Engineers have decided to keep the Jupiter probe, Juno, in its current orbit until an issue with its engine can be addressed.</em></strong></span></p>
<table border="1" width="100%" cellspacing="3" cellpadding="3" align="center" bgcolor="#E6E6E6">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><i><b>Update (October 19): </b></i>Juno sure likes to keep us hopping! An anomaly caused the spacecraft to enter electronic hibernation at 1:47 a.m. EDT. The spacecraft acted as expected during the transition into this "safe mode," restarted successfully, and is healthy. High-rate data has been restored, and the spacecraft is conducting flight software diagnostics. All instruments are off, and the planned science data collection for today's close flyby of Jupiter did not occur. Scott Bolton (NASA) explained at the ongoing meeting of the Division of Planetary Sciences that the problem was with valves in propulsion system. Find more information from <a href="http://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/news.php?feature=6653" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">NASA's recent press release</a>. Meanwhile, data from the first perijove flyby are still revealing intriguing results, showing that Jupiter's belt-zone structure extends at least <a href="http://www.jpl.nasa.gov/spaceimages/details.php?id=PIA21107" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">400 km deep</a>!</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<div><img src="http://www.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/PIA19639-16.jpg" alt="Juno" width="400" height="228" srcset="http://www.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/PIA19639-16.jpg 480w, http://www.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/PIA19639-16-300x171.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px"><p>An artist's concept of Juno at Jupiter. <br> <em>NASA / JPL-Caltech</em></p></div>
<p>NASA has announced that its Juno mission will stay in its current, wide-ranging orbit for at least one more pass.</p>
<p>The announcement came prior to a so-called period reduction maneuver (PRM) which was set to occur today. This would bring Juno closer to Jupiter, shortening its orbit from the current 53.4 days to just two weeks. An anomaly experienced by a set of valves controlling the spacecraft's fuel pressurization system triggered the decision. This PRM burn will be the last time Juno is scheduled to fire its main engines.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Telemetry indicates that two main helium check valves that play an important role in the firing of the spacecraft's main engine did not operate as expected during a command sequence that was initiated yesterday,&rdquo; says Juno project manager Rick Nybakken (Jet Propulsion Laboratory) in a <a href="http://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/news.php?feature=6648" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">recent press release</a>. &ldquo;The valves should have opened in a few seconds, but it took several minutes. We need to better understand this issue before moving forward with a burn of the main engine.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The burn was one of the first major events for the mission after Jupiter emerged from behind the Sun and its glare on September 26th. The decision to postpone the burn came after NASA consulted with the Lockheed Martin Space Systems engineers who designed the spacecraft. The next opportunity for Juno to carry out this firing is during its next pass near Jupiter on December 11th.</p>
<div><img src="http://www.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/Science-orbits-1.jpg" alt="orbits" width="600" height="399" srcset="http://www.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/Science-orbits-1.jpg 600w, http://www.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/Science-orbits-1-286x190.jpg 286w, http://www.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/Science-orbits-1-541x360.jpg 541w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px"><p>The original plan: two wide "capture" orbits, when Juno gravitationally latches on to Jupiter, then 35 closer-in science orbits. <br> <em>NASA / JPL-Caltech</em></p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>In its <a href="http://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/news.php?feature=6581" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">present orbit</a>, Juno ranges from an altitude above Jupiter of 4,300 km (perijove) out to 8.1 million km (apojove), more than 20 times the Earth-Moon distance and far beyond the orbit of Callisto. Following Kepler's Laws, Juno spends most of its time along this elongated orbit at its most distant point, briefly sweeping in toward the planet &mdash; and through its most intense exposure to high-energy charged particles trapped in Jupiter's magnetosphere &mdash; on each pass.</p>
<h3>What's Next for Juno</h3>
<p>This turn of events also means that the spacecraft's cameras and science instruments will stay on for this week's close pass of Jupiter &mdash; they were due to be shut off during the engine burn. NASA is now scrambling to make the most of this week's pass. We should see science returns similar to the<a href="http://www.skyandtelescope.com/astronomy-blogs/astronomy-space-david-dickinson/juno-makes-its-first-jupiter-pass/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> first perijove pass</a> this past August.</p>
<p>&ldquo;It is important to note that the orbital period does not affect the quality of the science that takes place during one of Juno's close flybys of Jupiter,&rdquo; said principal investigator Scott Bolton (Southwest Research Institute) in the October 14th <a href="http://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/news.php?feature=6648" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">press release</a>. &ldquo;The mission is very flexible that way. The data we collected during our first flyby on August 27th was a revelation, and I fully anticipate a similar result from Juno's October 19th flyby.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Launched from Cape Canaveral Air Force Station on August 5, 2011, Juno <a href="http://www.skyandtelescope.com/astronomy-news/juno-reaches-jupiter/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">entered orbit around Jupiter</a> on July 4th this year. Designed to probe Jupiter's interior as well as its gravity field and magnetosphere, the probe's first pass has already returned some amazing science. The most tantalizing part of keeping the spacecraft in such a wide-ranging pass is the long wait between science collection phases. Also, Juno sustains cumulative radiation exposure and subsequent damage on each pass, another reason that researchers are eager to get down to business.</p>
<p>This change in plans will force the <a href="http://www.skyandtelescope.com/astronomy-news/observing-news/juno-pro-am-workshop-05252016/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">amateur astronomer campaign</a>&nbsp;observing Jupiter to reschedule their observations as well. A <a href="http://www.planetary.org/blogs/guest-blogs/2016/0830-will-junos-instruments-observe-jupiters-moons.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">plan outlined by Candice Hansen on the Planetary Society blog</a> to capture some far images of selected moons (an extra project, as the mission wasn't designed for satellite science) has also been put on hold for the time being.</p>
<p>Juno is set to end its mission in February 2018 after 37 orbits, burning up in the atmosphere of Jupiter. It's unclear at this point just how firm this end of mission date is, and if the health of the spacecraft could force the date to move up or move back.</p>
<p>At this point, it's also unclear just what caused the engine anomaly. NASA plans to hold a press conference today (October 19th) at 4:00 p.m. EDT / 20:00 GMT to address Juno's current status.</p>
<p></p>
<p>We'll have updates then. Remember: space is hard, and life as a solar-powered spacecraft in the outer solar system is even harder.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://www.skyandtelescope.com/astronomy-news/nasa-juno-jupiter-engine-anomaly/" target="_blank">NASA&rsquo;s Juno Suffers Engine Anomaly, Briefly Enters Safe Mode</a> appeared first on <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://www.skyandtelescope.com" target="_blank">Sky &amp; Telescope</a>.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-10-19T17:38:27+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>David Dickinson</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.skyandtelescope.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.skyandtelescope.com"/>
		<updated>2016-10-19T17:38:27+00:00</updated>
		<title>Sky &amp; Telescope</title></source>

	<category term="astronomy blogs"/>

	<category term="astronomy in space with david dickinson"/>

	<category term="news"/>

	<category term="solar system"/>

	<category term="spacecraft and space missions"/>

	<category term="juno"/>

	<category term="jupiter"/>

	<category term="jupiter exploration"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-10-18:/333231</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-10/s-ptb101816.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Pushing the boundaries of magnet design</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Springer) A Russian team has been pushing the boundaries of magnet design, as published in a recent...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>Springer</i>) A Russian team has been pushing the boundaries of magnet design, as published in a recent study in EPJ Plus. They have developed methods to counter the spontaneous loss of magnetization, based on their understanding of the underlying physical phenomenon. Roman Morgunov from the Russian Academy of Sciences and colleagues have now developed a simple additive-based method for ensuring the stability of permanent magnets over time, with no loss to their main magnetic characteristics.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-10-18T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2016-10-18T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Chemistry, Physics and Materials Sciences</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-10-03:/328578</id>
	<link href="http://phys.org/news/2016-10-millisecond-pulsars.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Millisecond pulsars</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When a star with a mass of roughly ten solar masses finishes its life, it explodes as a supernova, l...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When a star with a mass of roughly ten solar masses finishes its life, it explodes as a supernova, leaving behind a neutron star as remnant "ash." Neutron stars have masses of one-to-several suns but they are tiny in diameter, only tens of kilometers. They spin rapidly, and when they have associated magnetic fields, charged particles caught in them emit electromagnetic radiation in a lighthouse-like beam that can sweep past the Earth with great regularity every few seconds or less. These kinds of neutron stars are called pulsars, and they are dramatic, powerful probes of supernovae, their progenitor stars, and the properties of nuclear matter under the extreme conditions that exist in these stars.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-10-03T12:00:01+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2016-10-03T12:00:01+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="astronomy"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="http://cdn.phys.org/newman/csz/news/tmb/2016/millisecondp.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-09-21:/325525</id>
	<link href="http://phys.org/news/2016-09-multi-stimuli-responsive-nanocapsules-drugs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Multi stimuli-responsive nanocapsules selectively deliver drugs to exactly where they are needed</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A nanoparticle-based drug delivery system that can sense and respond to different conditions in the ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A nanoparticle-based drug delivery system that can sense and respond to different conditions in the body, as well as to an externally applied magnetic field, could enhance doctors' ability to target drugs to specific sites of disease.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-09-21T11:30:01+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2016-09-21T11:30:01+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="bio &amp; medicine"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="http://cdn.phys.org/newman/csz/news/tmb/2016/multistimuli.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-09-13:/323254</id>
	<link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/09/160912141948.htm" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">NASA's THEMIS sees Auroras move to the rhythm of Earth's magnetic field</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the first time, scientists have directly mapped Earth's fluctuating magnetic field and resulting...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the first time, scientists have directly mapped Earth's fluctuating magnetic field and resulting electrical currents to aurora, thanks to northern lights observations from NASA's THEMIS mission.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-09-12T18:19:48+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/"/>
		<updated>2016-09-12T18:19:48+00:00</updated>
		<title>Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily</title></source>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://images.sciencedaily.com/2016/09/160912141948.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-08-23:/316890</id>
	<link href="http://physicsworld.com/cws/article/news/2016/aug/23/magnetic-bacteria-target-hard-to-treat-tumours" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Magnetic bacteria target hard-to-treat tumours</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>New technique transports drugs into solid cancers</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>New technique transports drugs into solid cancers<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/PhysicsWorld/~4/iPGPVvWiJWE" height="1" width="1" alt=""></p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-08-23T14:07:36+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://physicsworld.com/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://physicsworld.com/"/>
		<updated>2016-08-23T14:07:36+00:00</updated>
		<title>physicsworld.com: all content</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-08-16:/314641</id>
	<link href="http://phys.org/news/2016-08-pulsar-based-spacecraft-closer-reality.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Pulsar-based spacecraft navigation system one step closer to reality</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Pulsars are highly magnetized, rotating neutron stars that emit electromagnetic radiation at regular...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Pulsars are highly magnetized, rotating neutron stars that emit electromagnetic radiation at regular intervals. They are often dubbed "lighthouses" of the universe as their emission is beamed; thus, the pulse of radiation is seen only each time the beam sweeps across the line of sight. A spacecraft navigation method known as XNAV, based on X-ray signals emitted from pulsars, has recently taken a leap forward, thanks to a study conducted by U.K. scientists from the National Physical Laboratory (NPL) and the University of Leicester.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-08-16T11:09:37+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2016-08-16T11:09:37+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="astronomy"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="http://cdn.phys.org/newman/csz/news/tmb/2016/pulsarbaseds.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-08-08:/312235</id>
	<link href="http://phys.org/news/2016-08-mini-nasa-satellite-environmental.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Mini NASA satellite begins environmental testing</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Construction of NASA's Dellingr CubeSat - a miniature satellite that provides a low-cost platform fo...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Construction of NASA's Dellingr CubeSat - a miniature satellite that provides a low-cost platform for missions - is complete, and the satellite has just left the lab for environmental testing. This is a key step after any satellite has been built to make sure it can withstand intense vibrations, the extremes of hot and cold, and even the magnetic fields of space - all the rigorous conditions the CubeSat will encounter during launch and spaceflight.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-08-08T15:53:13+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2016-08-08T15:53:13+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="space exploration"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="http://cdn.phys.org/newman/csz/news/tmb/2016/mininasasate.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-08-03:/310896</id>
	<link href="http://phys.org/news/2016-08-physicists-enable-one-dimensional-atom-chains.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Physicists enable one-dimensional atom chains to grow</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Physicists at Friedrich-Alexander Universit&auml;t Erlangen-N&uuml;rnberg and the Vienna University of Technol...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Physicists at Friedrich-Alexander Universit&auml;t Erlangen-N&uuml;rnberg and the Vienna University of Technology have successfully created one-dimensional magnetic atom chains for the first time. Their break-through provides a model system for basic research in areas such as magnetic data storage, as well as in chemistry. Their results were recently published in the renowned journal Physical Review Letters.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-08-03T13:52:59+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2016-08-03T13:52:59+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="condensed matter"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="http://cdn.phys.org/newman/csz/news/tmb/2016/physicistsen.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-08-04:/311284</id>
	<link href="http://phys.org/news/2016-08-ceres-gravity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">What's inside Ceres? New findings from gravity data</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the tens of thousands of photos returned by NASA's Dawn spacecraft, the interior of Ceres isn't v...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the tens of thousands of photos returned by NASA's Dawn spacecraft, the interior of Ceres isn't visible. But scientists have powerful data to study Ceres' inner structure: Dawn's own motion.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-08-04T09:39:18+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2016-08-04T09:39:18+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="space exploration"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="http://cdn.phys.org/newman/csz/news/tmb/2016/whatsinsidec.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-08-02:/310450</id>
	<link href="http://phys.org/news/2016-08-physicists-gravitational-neutron-star-collisions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Physicists prepare to detect gravitational waves from neutron star collisions</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Phys.org)&mdash;Last February, scientists made the groundbreaking discovery of gravitational waves produc...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Phys.org)&mdash;Last February, scientists made the groundbreaking discovery of gravitational waves produced by two colliding black holes. Now researchers are expecting to detect similar gravitational wave signals in the near future from collisions involving neutron stars&mdash;for example, the merging of two neutron stars to form a black hole, or the merging of a neutron star and a black hole.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-08-02T12:30:02+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2016-08-02T12:30:02+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="general physics"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="http://cdn.phys.org/newman/csz/news/tmb/2016/neutronstarm.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-08-01:/310100</id>
	<link href="http://phys.org/news/2016-08-image-majestic-solar-eruption-larger.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Image: Majestic solar eruption larger than Earth</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A gigantic ribbon of hot gas bursts upwards from the Sun, guided by a giant loop of invisible magnet...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A gigantic ribbon of hot gas bursts upwards from the Sun, guided by a giant loop of invisible magnetism. This remarkable image was captured on 27 July 1999 by SOHO, the Solar and Heliospheric Observatory. Earth is superimposed for comparison and shows that from top to bottom the loop of gas, or prominence, extends about 35 times the diameter of our planet into space.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-08-01T12:50:09+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2016-08-01T12:50:09+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="space exploration"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="http://cdn.phys.org/newman/csz/news/tmb/2016/imagemajesti.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-05-11:/391800</id>
	<link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2017/05/170511142012.htm" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Antibiotic-resistant microbes date back to 450 million years ago, well before the age of dinosaurs</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Leading hospital 'superbugs,' known as the enterococci, arose from an ancestor that dates back 450 m...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Leading hospital 'superbugs,' known as the enterococci, arose from an ancestor that dates back 450 million years -- about the time when animals were first crawling onto land (and well before the age of dinosaurs), according to a new study.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-05-11T18:20:12+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/"/>
		<updated>2017-05-11T18:20:12+00:00</updated>
		<title>Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily</title></source>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://images.sciencedaily.com/2017/05/170511142012.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-05-17:/393216</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-05-flies-insect-fossils-amber-india.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Time flies: Insect fossils in amber shed light on India's geological history</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new species of fungus gnat in Indian amber closely resembles its fossil relatives from Europe, dis...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new species of fungus gnat in Indian amber closely resembles its fossil relatives from Europe, disproving the concept of a strongly isolated Indian subcontinent.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-05-17T11:00:03+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-05-17T11:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="archaeology &amp; fossils"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/timefliesins.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-05-22:/394664</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-05/uocm-3mf051717.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">3.3-million-year-old fossil reveals origins of the human spine</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(University of Chicago Medical Center) Analysis of a 3.3 million-year-old fossil skeleton reveals th...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>University of Chicago Medical Center</i>) Analysis of a 3.3 million-year-old fossil skeleton reveals the most complete spinal column of any early human relative, including vertebrae, neck and rib cage. The findings, published this week in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, indicate that portions of the human spinal structure that enable efficient walking motions were established millions of years earlier than previously thought.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-05-22T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-05-22T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Earth Science</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-06-29:/405668</id>
	<link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2017/06/170629143004.htm" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Genetic 'fossils' reveal long-term viral partnerships in grass</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Defective viruses incorporated into grass genomes may adapt to form partnerships with other genome-i...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Defective viruses incorporated into grass genomes may adapt to form partnerships with other genome-incorporated viruses in order to complete their life cycle, according to a new study. The findings suggest that partner viruses evolve in concert, enabling them to maintain their relationship over time.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-06-29T18:30:04+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/"/>
		<updated>2017-06-29T18:30:04+00:00</updated>
		<title>Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily</title></source>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/2017/06/170629143004-large.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-07-07:/407585</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-07-co2-neutral-hydrogen-biomass.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">CO2-neutral hydrogen from biomass</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Without fossil fuels, there can be no blast furnace process &ndash; but hydrogen could play a more importa...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Without fossil fuels, there can be no blast furnace process &ndash; but hydrogen could play a more important role in the future. An environmentally friendly process is being developed at TU Wien by which biomass can be used to produce a hydrogen-rich gas that can then be employed in various ways in the iron and steel industry. TU Wien and voestalpine now aim to conduct further joint research on the subject. The long-term vision is a renewable energy source, firmly anchored in the design of an integrated iron and steel works.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-07-07T11:52:52+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-07-07T11:52:52+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="materials science"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/co2neutralhy.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-08-16:/419708</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-08-million-year-old-fish-fossil-reveals-jaw.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">400-million-year-old fish fossil reveals jaw structure linked to humans</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new study from ANU on a 400 million year old fish fossil has found a jaw structure that is part of...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new study from ANU on a 400 million year old fish fossil has found a jaw structure that is part of the evolutionary lineage linked to humans.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-08-16T11:36:21+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-08-16T11:36:21+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="archaeology &amp; fossils"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/6-400millionye.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-09-11:/427655</id>
	<link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2017/09/170911122701.htm" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Scientists track the brain-skull transition from dinosaurs to birds</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The dramatic, dinosaur-to-bird transition that occurred in reptiles millions of years ago was accomp...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The dramatic, dinosaur-to-bird transition that occurred in reptiles millions of years ago was accompanied by profound changes in the skull roof of those animals -- and holds important clues about the way the skull forms in response to changes in the brain -- according to a new study. It is the first time scientists have tracked the link between the brain's development and the roofing bones of the skull.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-09-11T16:27:01+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/"/>
		<updated>2017-09-11T16:27:01+00:00</updated>
		<title>Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily</title></source>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/2017/09/170911122701-large.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-09-29:/433961</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-09-bioreactors-chip-renew-algal-biofuels.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Bioreactors on a chip renew promises for algal biofuels</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For over a decade, companies have promised a future of renewable fuel from algae. Investors interest...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For over a decade, companies have promised a future of renewable fuel from algae. Investors interested in moving the world away from fossil fuel have contributed hundreds of millions of dollars to the effort, and with good reason. Algae replicate quickly, requiring little more than water and sunlight to accumulate to massive amounts, which then convert atmospheric CO2 into lipids (oils) that can be harvested and readily processed into biodiesel.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-09-29T15:02:42+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-09-29T15:02:42+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="biotechnology"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/bioreactorso.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-04:/435299</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-10/uocf-nnc100417.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">New nanomaterial can extract hydrogen fuel from seawater</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(University of Central Florida) A new hybrid nanomaterial harvests solar energy and uses it to extra...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>University of Central Florida</i>) A new hybrid nanomaterial harvests solar energy and uses it to extract hydrogen from seawater, cheaply and efficiently. Future commercialization could mean a new source of environmentally friendly fuel and less dependence on fossil fuels.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-04T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-10-04T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Chemistry, Physics and Materials Sciences</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-03-01:/370349</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-03-world-oldest-fossils-unearthed.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">4 billion years: World's oldest fossils unearthed</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Remains of microorganisms at least 3,770 million years old have been discovered by an international ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Remains of microorganisms at least 3,770 million years old have been discovered by an international team led by UCL scientists, providing direct evidence of one of the oldest life forms on Earth.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-03-01T18:00:01+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-03-01T18:00:01+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="archaeology &amp; fossils"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/58b6f477969ff.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-02-28:/369772</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-02-scientists-electric-circuits.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Scientists create electric circuits inside plants</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Plants power life on Earth. They are the original food source supplying energy to almost all living ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Plants power life on Earth. They are the original food source supplying energy to almost all living organisms and the basis of the fossil fuels that feed the power demands of the modern world. But burning the remnants of long-dead forests is changing the world in dangerous ways. Can we better harness the power of living plants today?</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-02-28T13:00:01+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-02-28T13:00:01+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="biotechnology"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/scientistscr.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-04-24:/386565</id>
	<link href="http://www.livescience.com/58808-earliest-fungus-like-fossils-found.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Earliest Fungus-Like Fossils Date Back 2.4 Billion Years</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The fossils are 2 billion years older than previous finds and could dramatically alter the timeline ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The fossils are 2 billion years older than previous finds and could dramatically alter the timeline of the emergence of life on Earth.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-04-24T08:02:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.livescience.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.livescience.com"/>
		<updated>2017-04-24T08:02:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>LiveScience.com</title></source>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/jpeg" 
		length="1"
		href="https://img.purch.com/rc/160x100/aHR0cDovL3d3dy5saXZlc2NpZW5jZS5jb20vaW1hZ2VzL2kvMDAwLzA5MS81NDIvb3JpZ2luYWwvZnVuZ3VzLWZvc3NpbHMtc291dGgtYWZyaWNhLmpwZw=="/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-04-20:/385491</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-04/su-gep042017.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Genetic evidence points to nocturnal early mammals</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Stanford University) New genetic evidence suggesting that early mammals had good night-time vision ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>Stanford University</i>) New genetic evidence suggesting that early mammals had good night-time vision adds to fossil and behavioral studies indicating that early mammals were nocturnal.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-04-20T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-04-20T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Earth Science</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-03-13:/373501</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-03-science-carbon-dioxide-climate.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">The science of carbon dioxide and climate</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The vast majority of scientists around the world agree that our climate is changing at a faster rate...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The vast majority of scientists around the world agree that our climate is changing at a faster rate than ever recorded in human history because of our use of fuels such as coal and oil, so-called fossil fuels.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-03-13T13:21:58+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-03-13T13:21:58+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="environment"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/3-thescienceof.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-03-07:/371758</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-03-prehistoric-ancestor-leukaemia-virus.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Prehistoric ancestor of leukaemia virus found in bats</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ancient DNA traces from the family of viruses that cause a rare type of leukaemia have been found in...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ancient DNA traces from the family of viruses that cause a rare type of leukaemia have been found in the genomes of bats, filling the "last major gap" in retrovirus fossil record.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-03-07T09:02:51+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-03-07T09:02:51+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="cell &amp; microbiology"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/prehistorica.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-01-23:/359061</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-01-electrocatalysis-advance-green-transition.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Electrocatalysis can advance green transition</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The world population is growing, as is energy demand, and we have long been able to see the conseque...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The world population is growing, as is energy demand, and we have long been able to see the consequences of climate change caused by the world's consumption of fossil resources. The IEA reports that global demand for energy was around 18 terawatts (TW) in 2013. This corresponds to 18,000,000 megawatts. Demand is expected to rise to around 25 TW in 2040. This means that our carbon emissions will be approximately 40 gigatonnes (GT) a year&mdash;compared to 32 GT in 2013.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-01-23T14:07:49+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-01-23T14:07:49+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="materials science"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/electrocatal.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-05:/435669</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-10/uota-ses100517.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Scientists enlist supercomputers, machine learning to automatically identify brain tumors</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(University of Texas at Austin, Texas Advanced Computing Center) Researchers from the University of ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>University of Texas at Austin, Texas Advanced Computing Center</i>) Researchers from the University of Texas at Austin developed a brain tumor identification method that combines biophysical models of tumor growth with machine learning algorithms. The researchers scored in the top 25 percent of participants in the Multimodal Brain Tumor Segmentation Challenge 2017 (BRaTS'17) and used supercomputers at the Texas Advanced Computing Center to accelerate the training and analysis process.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-05T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-10-05T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Chemistry, Physics and Materials Sciences</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-05:/435683</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-10-d-quantum-gas-atomic-clock.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">3-D quantum gas atomic clock offers new dimensions in measurement</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>JILA physicists have created an entirely new design for an atomic clock, in which strontium atoms ar...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>JILA physicists have created an entirely new design for an atomic clock, in which strontium atoms are packed into a tiny three-dimensional (3-D) cube at 1,000 times the density of previous one-dimensional (1-D) clocks. In doing so, they are the first to harness the ultra-controlled behavior of a so-called "quantum gas" to make a practical measurement device.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-05T18:00:05+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-05T18:00:05+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="quantum physics"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/jilas3dquant.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-05:/435769</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-10/aaft-nna100217.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">New Neandertal and archaic human genomes advance our understanding of human evolution</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(American Association for the Advancement of Science) Two new studies on ancient genomes provide val...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>American Association for the Advancement of Science</i>) Two new studies on ancient genomes provide valuable insights into the lives of our ancestors and their cousins, the Neandertals. First, scientists have sequenced a new genome of a female Neandertal, which is only the second genome of the species to be fully sequenced with such a high level of quality.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-05T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-10-05T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Earth Science</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-01-09:/355305</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-01/osu-wtr010917.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">What teeth reveal about the lives of modern humans</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Ohio State University) When anthropologists of the future find our fossilized teeth, what will they...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>Ohio State University</i>) When anthropologists of the future find our fossilized teeth, what will they be able to conclude about our lives? Debbie Guatelli-Steinberg has an idea.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-01-09T05:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-01-09T05:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Earth Science</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-12-31:/353263</id>
	<link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/12/161230185406.htm" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Fossil fuel formation: Key to atmosphere’s oxygen?</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the development of animals, nothing -- with the exception of DNA -- may be more important than o...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the development of animals, nothing -- with the exception of DNA -- may be more important than oxygen in the atmosphere. A study now links the rise in oxygen to a rapid increase in the burial of sediment containing large amounts of carbon-rich organic matter.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-12-30T23:54:06+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/"/>
		<updated>2016-12-30T23:54:06+00:00</updated>
		<title>Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily</title></source>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://images.sciencedaily.com/2016/12/161230185406.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-12-20:/351071</id>
	<link href="http://phys.org/news/2016-12-sauropods-gobbled-gigantism.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">How sauropods gobbled their way to gigantism</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sauropod dinosaurs are the biggest of all the wonderful behemoths to have ever roamed the Earth. Sta...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sauropod dinosaurs are the biggest of all the wonderful behemoths to have ever roamed the Earth. Standing on four solid tree trunk legs, these giants are emblazoned in our hearts, minds and history books as towering Mesozoic monoliths, with long swooping necks, whiplash tails, fermentation-factory torsos, and weirdly tiny heads totally at odds with their immense bulk.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-12-20T14:10:01+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2016-12-20T14:10:01+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="archaeology &amp; fossils"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="http://cdn.phys.org/newman/csz/news/tmb/2016/howsauropods.png"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-12-08:/347796</id>
	<link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/12/161208141637.htm" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Amber specimen offers rare glimpse of feathered dinosaur tail</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Researchers have discovered a dinosaur tail complete with its feathers trapped in a piece of amber. ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Researchers have discovered a dinosaur tail complete with its feathers trapped in a piece of amber. The finding helps fill in details of the dinosaurs' feather structure and evolution.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-12-08T19:16:37+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/"/>
		<updated>2016-12-08T19:16:37+00:00</updated>
		<title>Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily</title></source>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://images.sciencedaily.com/2016/12/161208141637.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-11-29:/344855</id>
	<link href="http://phys.org/news/2016-11-geologist-uncovers-billion-year-old-fossils-bacteria.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Geologist uncovers 2.5 billion-year-old fossils of bacteria that predate the formation of oxygen</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Somewhere between Earth's creation and where we are today, scientists have demonstrated that some ea...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Somewhere between Earth's creation and where we are today, scientists have demonstrated that some early life forms existed just fine without any oxygen.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-11-29T17:48:33+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2016-11-29T17:48:33+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="earth sciences"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="http://cdn.phys.org/newman/csz/news/tmb/2016/1-lifebeforeox.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-11-21:/342680</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-11/g-lfg111716.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Living fossil genome unveiled</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(GigaScience) Published today in GigaScience, is the genome sequence of Ginkgo biloba, the oldest ex...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>GigaScience</i>) Published today in GigaScience, is the genome sequence of Ginkgo biloba, the oldest extant tree species. Researchers at BGI, Zheijiang University and Chinese Academy of Sciences carried out the work. Ginkgo is considered a 'living fossil,' as it evolved 270 million years ago and has changed little since. Given its unique position in the evolutionary tree of life and longevity as a species, the ginkgo genome will provide a resource investigating evolution and plant defenses.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-11-21T05:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2016-11-21T05:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Agriculture</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-11-08:/339076</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-11/idad-soo110816.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Solved: One of the mysteries of globular clusters</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Instituto de Astrof&iacute;sica de Canarias (IAC)) A study shows that the most massive stars in the last s...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>Instituto de Astrof&iacute;sica de Canarias (IAC)</i>) A study shows that the most massive stars in the last stages of their lives are those which contaminate the interstellar medium with new chemical elements, giving rise to successive generations of stars in these 'astronomical fossils'.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-11-08T05:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2016-11-08T05:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Space and Planetary Science</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-11-02:/337671</id>
	<link href="http://www.nature.com/ncomms/2016/161102/ncomms13364/full/ncomms13364.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_evolution" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Tetrapod limb and sarcopterygian fin regeneration share a core genetic programme</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[]]></content>
	<updated>2016-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/subjects/evolution</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.nature.com/subjects/evolution"/>
		<updated>2016-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>Evolution : nature.com subject feeds</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-08-29:/318656</id>
	<link href="http://www.linuxsecurity.com/content/view/168450?rdf" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Mozilla launches free website security scanning service</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>LinuxSecurity.com:  In order to help webmasters better protect their websites and users, Mozilla has...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<b>LinuxSecurity.com</b>:  In order to help webmasters better protect their websites and users, Mozilla has built an online scanner that can check if web servers have the best security settings in place.]]></content>
	<updated>2016-08-29T09:16:36+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.linuxsecurity.com/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.linuxsecurity.com/"/>
		<updated>2016-08-29T09:16:36+00:00</updated>
		<title>LinuxSecurity.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-05:/435494</id>
	<link href="http://www.esa.int/Our_Activities/Space_Science/Mars_Express/Colourful_dunes_on_wind-swept_Mars" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Colourful dunes on wind-swept Mars</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dunes are prominent indicators of prevailing winds, as can be seen on this crater floor...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.esa.int/var/esa/storage/images/esa_multimedia/images/2017/10/dune_field_in_a_crater_perspective_view/17176667-1-eng-GB/Dune_field_in_a_crater_perspective_view_small.jpg" width="170" height="96" align="left" hspace="8"><br>
		<p>
Dunes are prominent indicators of prevailing winds, as can be seen on this crater floor on Mars, imaged by ESA&rsquo;s Mars Express on 16 May.
</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-05T09:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.esa.int/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.esa.int/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-05T09:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>ESA Top News</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-08-18:/315574</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/news/top-10-iot-application-areas-based-real-iot-projects" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">The Top 10 IoT Application Areas – Based on Real IoT Projects</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As part of a larger effort to track the IoT ecosystem, we set out, mining hundreds of homepages, and...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>As part of a larger effort to track the IoT ecosystem, we set out, mining hundreds of homepages, and managed to assemble and verify&nbsp;<strong>640 actual enterprise&nbsp;<a href="https://iot-analytics.com/product/list-of-640-iot-projects/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IoT projects&nbsp;</a></strong><em>(Note: We did not include any consumer IoT projects such as wearable devices or hobby projects).</em>&nbsp;In a second step we took the time to collect all published information about these IoT projects and put them into a structured&nbsp;<a href="https://iot-analytics.com/product/list-of-640-iot-projects/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">list</a></p></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-08-18T07:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>IoT Analytics</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2016-08-18T07:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-08-16:/314721</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/news/lets-encrypt-why-create-free-automated-and-open-ca" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Let's Encrypt: Why Create a Free, Automated, and Open CA?</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>During the summer of 2012,&nbsp;Eric Rescorla&nbsp;and I decided to start a&nbsp;Certificate Authority (CA). A CA a...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>During the summer of 2012,&nbsp;<a href="https://blog.mozilla.org/press/bios/eric-rescorla/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Eric Rescorla</a>&nbsp;and I decided to start a&nbsp;<a href="https://opensource.com/business/16/8/%E2%80%9Dhttps://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Certificate_authority%E2%80%9D" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Certificate Authority (CA)</a>. A CA acts as a third-party to issue digital certificates, which certify public keys for certificate holders.</p></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-08-16T14:33:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>OpenSource.com</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2016-08-16T14:33:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-08-05:/311835</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/news/graph-databases-beginners-graph-search-algorithm-basics" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Graph Databases for Beginners: Graph Search Algorithm Basics</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While&nbsp;graph databases&nbsp;are certainly a rising tide in the world of technology, graph theory and graph...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>While&nbsp;<a href="http://neo4j.com/blog/why-graph-databases-are-the-future/#definition" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">graph databases</a>&nbsp;are certainly a rising tide in the world of technology, graph theory and graph algorithms are mature and well-understood fields of computer science.</p>
<div>
<p>In particular, graph search algorithms can be used to mine useful patterns and results from persisted graph data. As this is a practical introduction to graph databases, this blog post will discuss the basics of graph theory without diving too deeply into mathematics.</p></div></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-08-05T13:30:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>DZone</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2016-08-05T13:30:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-08-05:/311836</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/learn/nvidia-jetson-tx1-developer-kit-tiny-low-power-ultra-fast-computer" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">The NVIDIA Jetson TX1 Developer Kit: A Tiny, Low Power, Ultra Fast Computer</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Title:&nbsp;The NVIDIA Jetson TX1 Developer Kit: A Tiny, Low Power, Ultra Fast Computer5 AugLearn mo...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div>Title:&nbsp;</div><div><div property="dc:title">The NVIDIA Jetson TX1 Developer Kit: A Tiny, Low Power, Ultra Fast Computer</div></div></div><div><div><div>5 Aug</div></div></div><div><div><div><div><a href="http://localhost/learn/nvidia-jetson-tx1-developer-kit-tiny-low-power-ultra-fast-computer%20" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Learn more</a></div></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-08-05T13:00:24+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>monkeyiq</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2016-08-05T13:00:24+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-09-25:/432152</id>
	<link href="https://opensource.com/article/17/9/color-naming-word-embeddings" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Using machine learning to name colors</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On a recent trip to Michigan, my friend Tim Sosa&nbsp;mentioned a blog post he read in which the author, ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://opensource.com/sites/default/files/lead-images/colors-colorful-box-rectangle.png" width="520" height="292" alt="Using machine learning to name colors" title="Using machine learning to name colors"><p>On a recent trip to Michigan, my friend <a href="https://twitter.com/TimDrawsFish" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tim Sosa</a>&nbsp;mentioned a <a href="http://lewisandquark.tumblr.com/post/160776374467/new-paint-colors-invented-by-neural-network" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">blog post he read</a> in which the author, Janelle Shane, describes how she built a neural network that <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2017/05/when-a-robot-names-a-new-color-of-paint/527421/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">generates color names from RGB values</a>. I thought the idea was really neat, but I found the results underwhelming.</p>
<br>
<a href="https://opensource.com/article/17/9/color-naming-word-embeddings" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">read more</a>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-09-25T07:02:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>malcorn</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://opensource.com/frontpage</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://opensource.com/frontpage"/>
		<updated>2017-09-25T07:02:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>Opensource.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-09-26:/432731</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/news/mastering-file-searches-linux" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Mastering File Searches on Linux</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are many ways to search for files on Linux systems and the commands can be very easy or very s...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>There are many ways to search for files on Linux systems and the commands can be very easy or very specific &mdash;&nbsp;narrowing down your search criteria to find what just you're looking for and nothing else. In today's post, we're going to examine some of the most useful commands and options for your file searches. We're going to look into:</p></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-09-26T09:07:40+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Network World</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-09-26T09:07:40+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-09-27:/432986</id>
	<link href="https://opensource.com/article/17/9/7-best-practices-giving-conference-talk" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">7 best practices for giving a conference talk</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You want your first speaking experience to be a happy one, so I've prepared tips that may help you w...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://opensource.com/sites/default/files/lead-images/osdc_share_pixels.png" width="520" height="292" alt="7 best practices for giving a conference talk" title="7 best practices for giving a conference talk"><p>You want your first speaking experience to be a happy one, so I've prepared tips that may help you when writing and presenting your talk.</p>
<h2>1. Know your audience</h2>
<p>The <a href="http://seagl.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SeaGL</a> audience, for example, is an interesting mix of those new to tech and folks who have been around technology for a long time. Because the conference is held at a community college, you can expect the Friday audience in particular to have a large number of students.</p>
<br>
<a href="https://opensource.com/article/17/9/7-best-practices-giving-conference-talk" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">read more</a>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-09-27T07:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>vmbrasseur</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://opensource.com/frontpage</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://opensource.com/frontpage"/>
		<updated>2017-09-27T07:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>Opensource.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-04:/435024</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-10-brain-computer-interface-music-composition.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">A new brain-computer interface for music composition</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If that melody has just come to you, and if you know your way around a score, you might be able to t...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If that melody has just come to you, and if you know your way around a score, you might be able to think it into being now a group of researchers have developed a new brain-computer interface (BCI) application.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-04T12:50:01+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-04T12:50:01+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="engineering"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/anewbraincom.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-04:/435029</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-10-bumblebees-human-intelligence-memory.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Studying bumblebees to learn more about human intelligence and memory</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Phys.org)&mdash;A team of researchers at Queen Mary University in the U.K. has found that bumblebees with...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Phys.org)&mdash;A team of researchers at Queen Mary University in the U.K. has found that bumblebees with more "synaptic complexes" in their brains are able to learn new things more quickly and also have better memories than those with fewer of them. In their paper published in Proceedings of the Royal Society B the group describes studying neural connections in individual bee brains and comparing what they found with cognitive abilities.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-04T12:30:02+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-04T12:30:02+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="plants &amp; animals"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/bumblebee.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-04:/434987</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-10/fos--aar100417.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">ALMA and Rosetta detect freon-40 in space</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Faculty of Science - University of Copenhagen) Observations made with the Atacama Large Millimeter/...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>Faculty of Science - University of Copenhagen</i>) Observations made with the Atacama Large Millimeter/submillimeter Array (ALMA) and ESA's Rosetta mission by an international team, including researchers from the Niels Bohr Institute, have revealed the presence of the organohalogen Freon-40 in gas around both an infant star and a comet. This discovery suggests that organohalogens may not be as good markers of life as had been hoped, but that they may be significant components of the material from which planets form.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-04T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-10-04T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Chemistry, Physics and Materials Sciences</title></source>


</entry>


</feed>
<!-- vim:ft=xml
	  -->
