<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="atom-to-html.xsl"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Starred articles</title>
<generator uri="http://tt-rss.org/">Tiny Tiny RSS/17.4 (3b8d9bc)</generator>
<updated>2017-10-10T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost/tt-rss/public.php?op=rss&amp;id=-1&amp;key=vyn7su59c7b50850ac3</id>
<link href="http://localhost/tt-rss/public.php?op=rss&amp;id=-1&amp;key=vyn7su59c7b50850ac3" rel="self"/>

<link href="http://localhost/tt-rss" rel="alternate"/>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-18:/440630</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-10-mission-mars-oxygen-plasma-technology.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">A mission to Mars could make its own oxygen via plasma technology</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Plasma technology could hold the key to creating a sustainable oxygen supply on Mars, a new study ha...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Plasma technology could hold the key to creating a sustainable oxygen supply on Mars, a new study has found.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-18T11:34:42+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-18T11:34:42+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="plasma physics"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-18:/440673</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-10-quantum-computingbreaking-qubit-simulation-barrier.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Quantum computing—breaking through the 49 qubit simulation barrier</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Quantum computing is at the threshold of tackling important problems that cannot be efficiently or p...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Quantum computing is at the threshold of tackling important problems that cannot be efficiently or practically computed by other, more classical means. Getting past this threshold will require us to build, test and operate reliable quantum computers with 50 or more qubits.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-18T12:10:03+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-18T12:10:03+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="quantum physics"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/3-quantumcompu.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-18:/440609</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-10-chemists-drug-synthesis-method.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Chemists develop a promising drug synthesis method</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Scientists from RUDN University with their colleagues from Yaroslavl have developed a new way to syn...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Scientists from RUDN University with their colleagues from Yaroslavl have developed a new way to synthesize 1,2,4-oxadiazole derivatives used in many drugs. 1,2,4-oxadiazoles include ataluren, the active ingredient of a drug used in a treatment for genetic disorders. The results of the work are published in Tetrahedron Letters.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-18T09:57:36+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-18T09:57:36+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="materials science"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/59e632c5e9f72.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-18:/440488</id>
	<link href="https://www.livescience.com/60707-what-is-synesthesia.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">What Is Synesthesia?</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Synesthesia is a neurological condition that causes the brain to process data in the form of several...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Synesthesia is a neurological condition that causes the brain to process data in the form of several senses at once; for example, hearing sounds while also seeing them as colorful swirls.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-18T05:24:31+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.livescience.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.livescience.com"/>
		<updated>2017-10-18T05:24:31+00:00</updated>
		<title>LiveScience.com</title></source>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/jpeg" 
		length="1"
		href="https://img.purch.com/rc/160x100/aHR0cDovL3d3dy5saXZlc2NpZW5jZS5jb20vaW1hZ2VzL2kvMDAwLzA5Ni8xNjMvb3JpZ2luYWwvc3luZXN0aGVzaWEuanBn"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-18:/440459</id>
	<link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2017/10/171017091913.htm" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Schizophrenia disrupts the brain's entire communication system, researchers say</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some 40 years since CT scans first revealed abnormalities in the brains of schizophrenia patients, i...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some 40 years since CT scans first revealed abnormalities in the brains of schizophrenia patients, international scientists say the disorder is a systemic disruption to the brain's entire communication system. The study sets the stage for future research on the debilitating mental illness that affects more than 21 million people worldwide. It is the largest analysis of 'white matter' differences in a psychiatric disorder to date.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-17T13:19:13+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-17T13:19:13+00:00</updated>
		<title>Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily</title></source>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/2017/10/171017091913-large.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-17:/440362</id>
	<link href="https://www.ted.com/talks/elizabeth_wayne_we_can_hack_our_immune_cells_to_fight_cancer?rss=" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">We can hack our immune cells to fight cancer | Elizabeth Wayne</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After decades of research and billions spent in clinical trials, we still have a problem with cancer...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After decades of research and billions spent in clinical trials, we still have a problem with cancer drug delivery, says biomedical engineer Elizabeth Wayne. Chemotherapy kills cancer -- but it kills the rest of your body, too. Instead of using human design to fight cancer, why not use nature's? In this quick talk, Wayne explains how her lab is creating nanoparticle treatments that bind to immune cells, your body's first responders, to precisely target cancer cells without damaging healthy ones.<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/TEDTalks_video/~4/GNpUOtjnbqQ" height="1" width="1" alt=""></p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-17T14:00:55+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Elizabeth Wayne</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.ted.com/talks</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.ted.com/talks"/>
		<updated>2017-10-17T14:00:55+00:00</updated>
		<title>TEDTalks (video)</title></source>

	<category term="higher education"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://pi.tedcdn.com/r/pe.tedcdn.com/images/ted/87473a5991f9829bb77f36984771788260a6e306_2880x1620.jpg?h=360&amp;origin=rss&amp;w=480"/>

	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="video/mp4" 
		length="19266381"
		href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/TEDTalks_video/~5/OiOUMC7U0q8/ElizabethWayne_2017U.mp4"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-17:/440266</id>
	<link href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2017/10/17/richard-feynman-arline-letter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Love After Life: Nobel-Winning Physicist Richard Feynman’s Extraordinary Letter to His Departed Wife</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Where the hard edge of physics meets the vulnerable metaphysics of the human heart. 

Few people hav...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Where the hard edge of physics meets the vulnerable metaphysics of the human heart. </h3>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Genius-Life-Science-Richard-Feynman/dp/0679747044/?tag=braipick-20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img width="320" height="498" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/richardfeynman_gleick.jpg?fit=320%2C498&amp;ssl=1" alt="Love After Life: Nobel-Winning Physicist Richard Feynman&rsquo;s Extraordinary Letter to His Departed Wife" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/richardfeynman_gleick.jpg?w=321&amp;ssl=1 321w, https://i1.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/richardfeynman_gleick.jpg?resize=240%2C374&amp;ssl=1 240w, https://i1.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/richardfeynman_gleick.jpg?resize=320%2C498&amp;ssl=1 320w" sizes="(max-width: 320px) 100vw, 320px"></a></p><p>Few people have enchanted the popular imagination with science more powerfully and lastingly than physicist <strong>Richard Feynman</strong> (May 11, 1918&ndash;February 15, 1988) &mdash; the &ldquo;Great Explainer&rdquo; with the uncommon gift for bridging the essence of science with the most human and humane dimensions of life.</p>
<p>Several months after Feynman&rsquo;s death, while working on what would become <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Genius-Life-Science-Richard-Feynman/dp/0679747044/?tag=braipick-20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong><em>Genius: The Life and Science of Richard Feynman</em></strong></a> (<a href="http://www.worldcat.org/title/genius-the-life-and-science-of-richard-feynman/oclc/25316182&amp;referer=brief_results" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>public library</em></a>) &mdash; the masterly biography plumbing <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2016/05/11/richard-feynman-genius-james-gleick/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">the wellspring of Feynman&rsquo;s genius</a> &mdash; James Gleick discovered something of arresting strangeness and splendor. </p>
<p>&ldquo;My heart stopped,&rdquo; Gleick tells me. &ldquo;I have never had an experience like that as a biographer, before or since.&rdquo;</p>
<p>In a mass of unread papers sent to him by Feynman&rsquo;s widow, Gweneth, Gleick found a letter that discomposed his most central understanding of Feynman&rsquo;s character. A generation after computing pioneer Alan Turing <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2017/02/17/alan-turing-morcom-letters/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">tussled with the binary code of body and spirit in the wake of loss</a>, Feynman &mdash; a scientist perhaps <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2013/01/01/ode-to-a-flower-richard-feynman/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">uncommonly romantic</a> yet resolutely rational and unsentimental in his reverence for the indomitable laws of physics that tend toward decay &mdash; penned a remarkable letter to a physical nonentity that was, for the future Nobel-winning physicist, the locus of an irrepressible metaphysical reality. </p>
<figure><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Genius-Life-Science-Richard-Feynman/dp/0679747044/?tag=braipick-20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/feynman_young.jpg?resize=355%2C630&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/feynman_young.jpg?w=355&amp;ssl=1 355w, https://i0.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/feynman_young.jpg?resize=240%2C426&amp;ssl=1 240w, https://i0.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/feynman_young.jpg?resize=320%2C568&amp;ssl=1 320w" sizes="(max-width: 355px) 100vw, 355px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a><figcaption>Richard Feynman as a youth</figcaption></figure>
<p>In high school, the teenage Richard spent summers at the beach in his native Far Rockaway. There, he grew besotted with a striking girl named Arline &mdash; a girl he knew he would marry. Both complement and counterpoint to his own nature, Arline met Richard&rsquo;s inclination for science with ardor for philosophy and art. (The art class he took just to be near her would lay the foundation for his <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2013/01/17/richard-feynman-ofey-sketches-drawings/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">little-known, lifelong passion for drawing</a>.) By his junior year, Richard proposed. Arline accepted. With the eyes of young love, they peered into a shared future of infinite possibility for bliss. </p>
<figure><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Genius-Life-Science-Richard-Feynman/dp/0679747044/?tag=braipick-20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/feynman_arline2.jpg?resize=419%2C689&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/feynman_arline2.jpg?w=419&amp;ssl=1 419w, https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/feynman_arline2.jpg?resize=240%2C395&amp;ssl=1 240w, https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/feynman_arline2.jpg?resize=320%2C526&amp;ssl=1 320w" sizes="(max-width: 419px) 100vw, 419px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a><figcaption>Richard and Arline, 1940s</figcaption></figure>
<p>But they were abruptly grounded when a mysterious malady began afflicting Arline with inexplicable symptoms &mdash; a lump would appear and disappear on her neck, fevers would roil over her with no apparent cause. Eventually, she was hospitalized for what was believed to be typhoid. </p>
<p>Gleick writes:</p>
<blockquote><p>Feynman began to glimpse the special powerlessness that medical uncertainty can inflict on a scientific person. He had come to believe that the scientific way of thinking brought a measure of calmness and control in difficult situations &mdash; but not now.</p></blockquote>
<p>Just as Feynman began bombarding the doctors with questions that steered them toward a closer approximation of the scientific method, Arline began to recover just as mysteriously and unpredictably as she had fallen ill. But the respite was only temporary. The symptoms returned, still shorn of a concrete explanation but now unambiguously pointing toward the terminal &mdash; a prognosis Arline&rsquo;s doctors kept from her. Richard refused to go along with the deception &mdash; he and Arline had promised each other to face life with unremitting truthfulness &mdash; but he was forced to calibrate his commitment to circumstance. </p>
<p>Gleick writes:</p>
<blockquote><p>His parents, Arline&rsquo;s parents, and the doctors all urged him not to be so cruel as to tell a young woman she was dying. His sister, Joan, sobbing, told him he was stubborn and heartless. He broke down and bowed to tradition. In her room at Farmingdale Hospital, with her parents at her side, he confirmed that she had glandular fever. Meanwhile, he started carrying around a letter &mdash; a &ldquo;goodbye love letter,&rdquo; as he called it&mdash;that he planned to give her when she discovered the truth. He was sure she would never forgive the unforgivable lie. </p>
<p>He did not have long to wait. Soon after Arline returned home from the hospital she crept to the top of the stairs and overheard her mother weeping with a neighbor down in the kitchen. When she confronted Richard &mdash; his letter snug in his pocket &mdash; he told her the truth, handed her the letter, and asked her to marry him.</p></blockquote>
<figure><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Genius-Life-Science-Richard-Feynman/dp/0679747044/?tag=braipick-20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/feynman_arline1.jpg?resize=680%2C454&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/feynman_arline1.jpg?w=961&amp;ssl=1 961w, https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/feynman_arline1.jpg?resize=240%2C160&amp;ssl=1 240w, https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/feynman_arline1.jpg?resize=320%2C213&amp;ssl=1 320w, https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/feynman_arline1.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/feynman_arline1.jpg?resize=600%2C400&amp;ssl=1 600w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a><figcaption>Arline and Richard, 1940s</figcaption></figure>
<p>Marriage, however, proved to be a towering practical problem &mdash; Princeton, where Feynman was now pursuing a Ph.D., threatened to withdraw the fellowships funding his graduate studies if he were to wed, for the university considered the emotional and pragmatic responsibilities of marriage a grave threat to academic discipline. </p>
<p>Just as Feynman began considering leaving Princeton, a diagnosis detonated the situation &mdash; Arline had contracted a rare form of tuberculosis, most likely from unpasteurized milk. </p>
<p>At first, Feynman was relieved that the grim alternative options of Hodgkin&rsquo;s disease and incurable cancers like lymphoma had been ruled out. But he was underestimating, or perhaps misunderstanding, the gravity of tuberculosis &mdash; the very disease which had <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2017/02/17/alan-turing-morcom-letters/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">taken the love of Alan Turing&rsquo;s life</a> and which, during its two-century heyday, had claimed more lives around the globe than any other malady and all wars combined. At the time of Arline&rsquo;s diagnosis in 1941, immunology was in its infancy, the antibiotic treatment of bacterial infections practically nonexistent, and the first successful medical application of penicillin a year away. Tuberculosis was a death sentence, even if it was a slow death with intervals of remission &mdash; a fact Richard and Arline faced with an ambivalent mix of brave lucidity and hope against hope. </p>
<p>Meanwhile, Richard&rsquo;s parents met the prospect of his marriage with bristling dread. His mother, who believed he was marrying Arline out of pity rather than love, admonished him that he would be putting his health and his very life in danger, and coldly worried about how the stigma attached to tuberculosis would impact her brilliant young son&rsquo;s reputation. &ldquo;I was surprised to learn such a marriage is not unlawful,&rdquo; she scoffed unfeelingly. &ldquo;It ought to be.&rdquo;</p>
<p>But Richard was buoyed by love &mdash; a love so large and luminous that he found himself singing aloud one day as he was arranging Arline&rsquo;s transfer to a sanatorium. Determined to go through with the wedding, he wrote to his beloved:</p>
<blockquote><p>I guess maybe it is like rolling off of a log &mdash; my heart is filled again &amp; I&rsquo;m choked with emotions &mdash; and love is so good &amp; powerful &mdash; it&rsquo;s worth preserving &mdash; I know nothing can separate us &mdash; we&rsquo;ve stood the tests of time and our love is as glorious now as the day it was born &mdash; dearest riches have never made people great but love does it every day &mdash; we&rsquo;re not little people &mdash; we&rsquo;re giants &hellip; I know we both have a future ahead of us &mdash; with a world of happiness &mdash; now &amp; forever.</p></blockquote>
<p>On June 29, 1942, they promised each other eternity. </p>
<figure><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Genius-Life-Science-Richard-Feynman/dp/0679747044/?tag=braipick-20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/richard_arline4.jpg?resize=535%2C883&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/richard_arline4.jpg?w=535&amp;ssl=1 535w, https://i1.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/richard_arline4.jpg?resize=240%2C396&amp;ssl=1 240w, https://i1.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/richard_arline4.jpg?resize=320%2C528&amp;ssl=1 320w" sizes="(max-width: 535px) 100vw, 535px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a><figcaption>Richard and Arline on their wedding day</figcaption></figure>
<p>Gleick writes:</p>
<blockquote><p>He borrowed a station wagon from a Princeton friend, outfitted it with mattresses for the journey, and picked up Arline in Cedarhurst. She walked down her father&rsquo;s hand-poured concrete driveway wearing a white dress. They crossed New York Harbor on the Staten Island ferry &mdash; their honeymoon ship. They married in a city office on Staten Island, in the presence of neither family nor friends, their only witnesses two strangers called in from the next room. Fearful of contagion, Richard did not kiss her on the lips. After the ceremony he helped her slowly down the stairs, and onward they drove to Arline&rsquo;s new home, a charity hospital in Browns Mills, New Jersey.</p></blockquote>
<p>Meanwhile, WWII was reaching its crescendo of destruction, dragging America into the belly of death with the attack on Pearl Harbor. Now one of the nation&rsquo;s most promising physicists, Feynman was recruited to work on what would become <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2011/10/14/richard-feynman-graphic-novel-biography-ottoviani/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">the Manhattan Project</a> and soon joined the secret laboratory in Los Alamos. </p>
<figure><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Genius-Life-Science-Richard-Feynman/dp/0679747044/?tag=braipick-20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/feynman_losalamos.jpg?resize=680%2C787&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/feynman_losalamos.jpg?w=700&amp;ssl=1 700w, https://i1.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/feynman_losalamos.jpg?resize=240%2C278&amp;ssl=1 240w, https://i1.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/feynman_losalamos.jpg?resize=320%2C370&amp;ssl=1 320w, https://i1.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/feynman_losalamos.jpg?resize=600%2C694&amp;ssl=1 600w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a><figcaption>Feynman&rsquo;s Los Alamos badge</figcaption></figure>
<p>Arline entered the nearby Albuquerque sanatorium, from where she wrote him letters in code &mdash; for the sheer fun of it, because she knew how he cherished puzzles, but the correspondence alarmed the military censors at the laboratory&rsquo;s Intelligence Office. Tasked with abating any breaches to the secrecy of the operation, they cautioned Feynman that coded messages were against the rules and demanded that his wife include a key in each letter to help them decipher it. This only amplified Arline&rsquo;s sense of fun &mdash; she began cutting holes into her letters, covering passages with ink, and even mail-ordered a jigsaw puzzle kit with which to cut up the pages and completely confound the agents. </p>
<p>But the levity masked the underlying darkness which Richard and Arline tried so desperately to evade &mdash; Arline was dying. As her body failed, he steadied himself to her spirit:</p>
<blockquote><p>You are a strong and beautiful woman. You are not always as strong as other times but it rises &amp; falls like the flow of a mountain stream. I feel I am a reservoir for your strength &mdash; without you I would be empty and weak&hellip; I find it much harder these days to write these things to you.</p></blockquote>
<p>In every single letter, he told her that he loved her. <em>&ldquo;I have a serious affliction: loving you forever,&rdquo;</em> he wrote. </p>
<figure><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Genius-Life-Science-Richard-Feynman/dp/0679747044/?tag=braipick-20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/feynman_arline3.jpg?resize=600%2C526&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/feynman_arline3.jpg?w=600&amp;ssl=1 600w, https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/feynman_arline3.jpg?resize=240%2C210&amp;ssl=1 240w, https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/feynman_arline3.jpg?resize=320%2C281&amp;ssl=1 320w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a><figcaption>Richard and Arline at the Albuquerque sanatorium</figcaption></figure>
<p>In early 1945, two and a half years into their marriage, Richard and Arline made love for the first time. He had been too afraid of harming her frail health somehow, she too afraid of infecting him with the deadly bacterium consuming her. But Arline insisted that this pent up desire could no longer be contained and assured Richard that this would only bring them closer &mdash; to each other, and to the life they had so lovingly dreamt up for themselves:</p>
<blockquote><p>I&rsquo;ll always be your sweetheart &amp; first love &mdash; besides a devoted wife &mdash; we&rsquo;ll be proud parents too&hellip; I am proud of you always Richard &ndash;[you are] a good husband, and lover, &amp; well, coach, I&rsquo;ll show you what I mean Sunday.</p></blockquote>
<p>But heightened as their hopes were by this new dimension of shared experience, Arline&rsquo;s health continued to plummet. Her weight dropped to eighty-four pounds. Exasperated by the helplessness of medicine, which Feynman had come to see not as a manifestation but as a mutilation of the scientific method, he invested all hope in an experimental drug made of mold growths. &ldquo;Keep hanging on,&rdquo; he exhorted Arline. &ldquo;Nothing is certain. We lead a charmed life.&rdquo; She began spitting blood. </p>
<p>At twenty-seven, on the precipice of a brilliant scientific career, he was terminally in love. </p>
<p>On June 16, 1945, while working at the computing room at Los Alamos, Feynman received a call from the sanatorium that Arline was dying. He borrowed a colleague&rsquo;s car and sped to the hospital, where he found her immobile, her eyes barely tracing his movement. Early in his scientific career, he had been animated by the nature of time. Now, hours stretched and contracted as he sat at her deathbed, until one last small breath tolled the end at 9:21PM.</p>
<p>The wake of loss has a way of tranquilizing grief with the pressing demands of practical arrangements &mdash; a tranquilizer we take willingly, almost gratefully. The following morning, Feynman arranged for his beloved&rsquo;s cremation, methodically collected her personal belongings, and on the final page of the small spiral notebook in which she recorded her symptoms he wrote with scientific remove: &ldquo;June 16 &mdash; Death.&rdquo;</p>
<p>And so we arrive at Gleick&rsquo;s improbable discovery in that box of letters &mdash; improbable because of the extreme rationality with which Feynman hedged against even the slightest intimation of metaphysical conjectures untestable by science and unprovable by reason. During his courtship of Arline, he had been vexed by her enthusiasm for Descartes, whose &ldquo;proof&rdquo; of God&rsquo;s perfection he found intellectually lazy and unbefitting of Descartes&rsquo;s reputation as <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2016/03/31/descartes-rules-for-the-direction-of-the-mind/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">a champion of reason</a>. He had impishly countered Arline&rsquo;s insistence that there are two sides to everything by cutting a piece of paper and half-twisting it into a M&ouml;bius strip, the ends pasted together to render a surface with just one side. </p>
<p>Everything that appeared mystical, Feynman believed, was simply an insufficiently explained mystery with a physical answer not yet found. Even Arline&rsquo;s dying hour had offered testing ground for conviction. Puzzlingly, the clock in the room had stopped at exactly 9:21PM &mdash; the time of death. Aware of how this bizarre occurrence could foment the mystical imagination in unscientific minds, Feynman reasoned for an explanation. Remembering that he had repaired the clock multiple times over the course of Arline&rsquo;s stay at the sanatorium, he realized that the instrument&rsquo;s unwieldy mechanism must have choked when the nurse picked it up in the low evening light to see and record the time. </p>
<p>How astonishing and how touchingly human, then, that Feynman penned the letter Gleick found in the box forty-two years later &mdash; a letter he wrote to Arline in October of 1946, 488 days after her death:</p>
<blockquote><p>D&rsquo;Arline,</p>
<p>I adore you, sweetheart.</p>
<p>I know how much you like to hear that &mdash; but I don&rsquo;t only write it because you like it &mdash; I write it because it makes me warm all over inside to write it to you.</p>
<p>It is such a terribly long time since I last wrote to you &mdash; almost two years but I know you&rsquo;ll excuse me because you understand how I am, stubborn and realistic; and I thought there was no sense to writing.</p>
<p>But now I know my darling wife that it is right to do what I have delayed in doing, and that I have done so much in the past. I want to tell you I love you. I want to love you. I always will love you.</p>
<p>I find it hard to understand in my mind what it means to love you after you are dead &mdash; but I still want to comfort and take care of you &mdash; and I want you to love me and care for me. I want to have problems to discuss with you &mdash; I want to do little projects with you. I never thought until just now that we can do that. What should we do. We started to learn to make clothes together &mdash; or learn Chinese &mdash; or getting a movie projector. Can&rsquo;t I do something now? No. I am alone without you and you were the &ldquo;idea-woman&rdquo; and general instigator of all our wild adventures.</p>
<p>When you were sick you worried because you could not give me something that you wanted to and thought I needed. You needn&rsquo;t have worried. Just as I told you then there was no real need because I loved you in so many ways so much. And now it is clearly even more true &mdash; you can give me nothing now yet I love you so that you stand in my way of loving anyone else &mdash; but I want you to stand there. You, dead, are so much better than anyone else alive.</p>
<p>I know you will assure me that I am foolish and that you want me to have full happiness and don&rsquo;t want to be in my way. I&rsquo;ll bet you are surprised that I don&rsquo;t even have a girlfriend (except you, sweetheart) after two years. But you can&rsquo;t help it, darling, nor can I &mdash; I don&rsquo;t understand it, for I have met many girls and very nice ones and I don&rsquo;t want to remain alone &mdash; but in two or three meetings they all seem ashes. You only are left to me. You are real.</p>
<p>My darling wife, I do adore you.</p>
<p>I love my wife. My wife is dead.</p>
<p>Rich.</p></blockquote>
<p>And then, with the sole defibrillator for heartache we have &mdash; humor &mdash; Feynman adds:</p>
<blockquote><p>PS Please excuse my not mailing this &mdash; but I don&rsquo;t know your new address.</p></blockquote>
<p>Complement this particular portion of the altogether magnificent <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Genius-Life-Science-Richard-Feynman/dp/0679747044/?tag=braipick-20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong><em>Genius: The Life and Science of Richard Feynman</em></strong></a> with Rachel Carson&rsquo;s <a href="http://localhost/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">stunning deathbed farewell to her beloved</a> and Seneca on <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2017/05/02/seneca-consolation-to-helvia/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">resilience in the face of loss</a>, then revisit Feynman on <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2015/05/11/richard-feynman-science-religion/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">science and religion</a> and <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2013/08/08/richard-feynman-on-the-meaning-of-life/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">the meaning of life</a>.</p>
<h3>donating = loving</h3><p>Bringing you (ad-free) Brain Pickings takes me hundreds of hours each month. If you find any joy and stimulation here, please consider becoming a Supporting Member with a recurring monthly <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/donate/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">donation</a> of your choosing, between a cup of tea and a good dinner.</p>



<h3>newsletter</h3>
<p>Brain Pickings has a free weekly newsletter. It comes out on Sundays and offers the week&rsquo;s most unmissable reads. Here&rsquo;s <a href="http://us2.campaign-archive1.com/?u=13eb080d8a315477042e0d5b1&amp;id=de29ba37e7&amp;e=b2dbad0745" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">what to expect</a>. Like? <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/newsletter/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Sign up.</a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/brainpickings/rss/~4/m_1lCjisI2g" height="1" width="1" alt="">]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-17T16:36:53+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Maria Popova</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.brainpickings.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.brainpickings.org"/>
		<updated>2017-10-17T16:36:53+00:00</updated>
		<title>Brain Pickings</title></source>

	<category term="culture"/>

	<category term="science"/>

	<category term="james gleick"/>

	<category term="letters"/>

	<category term="love"/>

	<category term="richard feynman"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-17:/440271</id>
	<link href="http://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/science/whale-behaviour-linked-to-brain-size/article19877612.ece?utm_source=RSS_Feed&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=RSS_Syndication" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Whale behaviour linked to brain size</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sperm whale has the largest brain on Earth</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sperm whale has the largest brain on Earth</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-17T16:35:38+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Reuters</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.thehindu.com/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.thehindu.com/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-17T16:35:38+00:00</updated>
		<title>The Hindu - Sci-Tech</title></source>

	<category term="science"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-17:/440245</id>
	<link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2017/10/171016122153.htm" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Learning during development is regulated by an unexpected brain region</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Half a century of research on how the brain learns to integrate visual inputs from the two eyes has ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Half a century of research on how the brain learns to integrate visual inputs from the two eyes has provided important insights in critical period regulation, leading to the conclusion that it occurs within the cortex. Scientists have now made the surprising discovery that a brain region that passes on input from the eyes to the cortex also plays a crucial role in opening the critical period of binocular vision.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-16T16:21:53+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-16T16:21:53+00:00</updated>
		<title>Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-03-31:/379497</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/learn/intro-to-linux/2017/3/how-install-packages-source-linux" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">How to Install Packages from Source on Linux</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Most modern Linux distributions enjoy standard repositories that include most of the software you&rsquo;ll...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Most modern Linux distributions enjoy standard repositories that include most of the software you&rsquo;ll need to successfully run your Linux server or desktop. Should a package come up missing, more than likely you&rsquo;ll find a repository you can add, so that the installation can be managed with the built-in package manager. This should be considered a best practice. Why? Because it&rsquo;s important for the integrity of the platform to ensure the package manager is aware of installed software. When that is the case, packages can easily be updated (to fix vulnerabilities and the like).</p></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-03-31T14:00:10+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>jlwallen</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-03-31T14:00:10+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-03-31:/379500</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/news/brief-history-random-numbers" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">A Brief History of Random Numbers</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;As an instrument for selecting at random, I have found nothing superior to dice,&rdquo; wrote statisticia...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>&ldquo;As an instrument for selecting at random, I have found nothing superior to dice,&rdquo; wrote statistician Francis Galton&nbsp;<a href="http://galton.org/essays/1890-1899/galton-1890-dice.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">in an 1890 issue of&nbsp;<em>Nature</em></a>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-03-31T11:00:56+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>freeCodeCamp</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-03-31T11:00:56+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-03-29:/378743</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/news/new-home-google-open-source" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">A New Home for Google Open Source</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Free and open source software has been part of our technical and organizational foundation since Goo...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Free and open source software has been part of our technical and organizational foundation since Google&rsquo;s early beginnings. From servers running the Linux kernel to an internal culture of being able to patch any other team's code, open source is part of everything we do.</p></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-03-29T11:04:51+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Google Open Source</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-03-29T11:04:51+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-03-29:/378586</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/blog/linux-block-io-tracing" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Linux Block I/O Tracing</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Title:&nbsp;Linux Block I/O Tracing28 MarLearn more</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div>Title:&nbsp;</div><div><div property="dc:title">Linux Block I/O Tracing</div></div></div><div><div><div>28 Mar</div></div></div><div><div><div><div><a href="http://localhost/blog/linux-block-io-tracing" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Learn more</a></div></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-03-28T15:06:26+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>mfilion</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-03-28T15:06:26+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-03-24:/377204</id>
	<link href="http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-Kernel-ELKDAT" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">ELKDAT Tool Released To Ease Linux Kernel Development &amp; Testing</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>ELKDAT is a new Linux kernel project to provide an easy kernel development and testing tool...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>ELKDAT is a new Linux kernel project to provide an easy kernel development and testing tool...</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-03-24T10:16:24+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.phoronix.com/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.phoronix.com/"/>
		<updated>2017-03-24T10:16:24+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phoronix</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-03-17:/375175</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/news/monitoring-google-compute-engine-metrics" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Monitoring Google Compute Engine Metrics</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post is part 1 in a 3-part series about monitoring Google Compute Engine (GCE).&nbsp;Part 2&nbsp;covers t...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><em>This post is part 1 in a 3-part series about monitoring Google Compute Engine (GCE).&nbsp;<a href="https://www.datadoghq.com/blog/how-to-collect-gce-metrics" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Part 2</a>&nbsp;covers the nuts and bolts of collecting GCE metrics, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.datadoghq.com/blog/monitor-google-compute-engine-with-datadog" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">part 3</a>describes how you can get started collecting metrics from GCE with Datadog. This article describes in detail the resource and performance metrics that can be obtained from GCE.</em></p>
<p><strong>What is Google Compute Engine?</strong></p></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-03-17T11:30:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Datadog</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-03-17T11:30:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-03-17:/375018</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/news/top-10-challenges-devops-implementation" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Top 10 Challenges to DevOps Implementation</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As more companies adopt DevOps to improve their workflow and productivity, a number of challenges re...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>As more companies adopt DevOps to improve their workflow and productivity, a number of challenges related to infrastructure and legacy systems have arisen, according to a new survey from cloud sandbox software provider Quali.</p></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-03-16T10:30:56+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>TechCrunch</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-03-16T10:30:56+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-03-17:/375020</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/news/introduction-grub2-configuration-your-linux-machine-0" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">An Introduction to GRUB2 Configuration for your Linux Machine</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When researching my article from last month,&nbsp;An introduction to the Linux&nbsp;boot and startup process, ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>When researching my article from last month,&nbsp;<em><a href="https://opensource.com/article/17/2/linux-boot-and-startup" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">An introduction to the Linux</a><a href="https://opensource.com/article/17/2/linux-boot-and-startup" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">&nbsp;boot and startup process</a></em>, I became interested in learning more about GRUB2. This article provides a quick introduction to configuring GRUB2, which I will mostly refer to as GRUB for simplicity.</p>
<p><strong>GRUB</strong></p></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-03-16T08:30:56+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>OpenSource.com</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-03-16T08:30:56+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-03-16:/374908</id>
	<link href="http://thevarguy.com/ubuntu/open-source-software-and-security-what-you-need-know" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Open Source Software and Security: What You Need to Know</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Is open source software inherently less secure than closed-source code? Which special security preca...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Is open source software inherently less secure than closed-source code? Which special security precautions should you take with open source? Keep reading for a primer on open source software security...</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-03-16T21:01:20+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://thevarguy.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://thevarguy.com"/>
		<updated>2017-03-16T21:01:20+00:00</updated>
		<title>The VAR Guy -- Linux</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-17:/440112</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-10-cell-technology.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Researchers developed single cell level sorting technology using sound waves</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sound wave enables the sensation of hearing, and is an important way of communicating in the animal ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sound wave enables the sensation of hearing, and is an important way of communicating in the animal world. In physics, sound is considered as a mechanical vibration that can propagate in gases, liquids and solids. A research team from the Singapore University of Technology and Design (SUTD), led by Assistant Professor Dr Ye Ai, is studying the interactions between ultrasound (beyond the audible limit of human hearing) and micron-sized objects (e.g. biological cells) suspended in aqueous solutions. Dr Ai's research team recently developed a highly accurate single cell level sorting technology using a highly focused sound wave beam (50 &mu;m wide roughly &frac14; of a single human hair's diameter). This new cell manipulation technology enables highly accurate isolation of rare cell populations in complex biological samples. More concisely, it provides the potential of finding a single cell in a million.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-17T13:43:56+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-17T13:43:56+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="analytical chemistry"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/1-sutdresearch.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-17:/440130</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-10-revealing-quantum-statistics-pair-distant.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Revealing quantum statistics with a pair of distant atoms</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An international team of researchers has proposed a new way to make atoms or ions indistinguishable ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An international team of researchers has proposed a new way to make atoms or ions indistinguishable by swapping their positions. These particles are then expected to exhibit exotic properties. The study involved physicists from the University of Bonn, the Austrian Academy of Sciences, and the University of California. The work has now been published in Physical Review Letters.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-17T12:59:03+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-17T12:59:03+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="quantum physics"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/revealingqua.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-17:/440082</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-10-quantum-physics-paves-chemical-products.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Quantum physics paves the way for new chemical products</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Research by an OU molecular physicist has discovered that electrons can control chemical reactions i...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Research by an OU molecular physicist has discovered that electrons can control chemical reactions in experiments leading to purer, cheaper chemical products.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-17T12:37:44+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-17T12:37:44+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="condensed matter"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/1-quantumphysi.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-16:/439678</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-10/eic-hos101617.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Hubble observes source of gravitational waves for the first time</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(ESA/Hubble Information Centre) The NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope has observed for the first time ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>ESA/Hubble Information Centre</i>) The NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope has observed for the first time the source of a gravitational wave, created by the merger of two neutron stars. This merger created a kilonova -- an object predicted by theory decades ago -- that ejects heavy elements such as gold and platinum into space. This event also provides the strongest evidence yet that short duration gamma-ray bursts are caused by mergers of neutron stars.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-16T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-10-16T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Chemistry, Physics and Materials Sciences</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-16:/439671</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-10/nrl-ito101617.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">International team observes first radio counterpart to gravitational waves</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Naval Research Laboratory) NRL Radio Astrophysics and Sensing Section astronomers join an internati...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>Naval Research Laboratory</i>) NRL Radio Astrophysics and Sensing Section astronomers join an international collaboration of researchers with the Caltech-led GROWTH project, resulting in the first ever observation of the radio counterpart to a gravitational wave event.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-16T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-10-16T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Chemistry, Physics and Materials Sciences</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-16:/439677</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-10/e-eto101617.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">ESO telescopes observe first light from gravitational wave source</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(ESO) ESO's fleet of telescopes have detected the first visible counterpart to a gravitational wave ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>ESO</i>) ESO's fleet of telescopes have detected the first visible counterpart to a gravitational wave source. These historic observations suggest that this unique object is the result of the merger of two neutron stars. The cataclysmic aftermaths of this kind of merger -- long-predicted events called kilonovae -- disperse heavy elements such as gold and platinum throughout the Universe. This discovery also provides the strongest evidence yet that short-duration gamma-ray bursts are caused by mergers of neutron stars.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-16T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-10-16T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Chemistry, Physics and Materials Sciences</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-16:/439676</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-10/uoc-lad101617.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">LIGO announces detection of gravitational waves from colliding neutron stars</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(University of Chicago) The US-based Laser Interferometer Gravitational-Wave Observatory and the Vir...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>University of Chicago</i>) The US-based Laser Interferometer Gravitational-Wave Observatory and the Virgo detector in Italy announced on Oct. 16 that all three of their detectors had picked up the ripples, or gravitational waves, from two neutron stars that collided 130 million years ago. Among other discoveries, the detection allowed scientists to use gravitational waves to directly calculate the rate at which the universe is expanding.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-16T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-10-16T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Chemistry, Physics and Materials Sciences</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-17:/440111</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-10-icarus.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Icarus lifts off</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After the launch of a Soyuz 2 rocket scheduled for October 12 was postponed by two days, the carrier...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After the launch of a Soyuz 2 rocket scheduled for October 12 was postponed by two days, the carrier rocket yesterday docked with the ISS. On board: the Icarus board computer, the future brain of the German-Russian animal observation system.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-17T13:50:03+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-17T13:50:03+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="space exploration"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/icarusliftso.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-17:/440083</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-10-bees-home.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">How bees find their way home</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>How can a bee fly straight home in the middle of the night after a complicated route through thick v...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>How can a bee fly straight home in the middle of the night after a complicated route through thick vegetation in search of food? For the first time, researchers have been able to show what happens in the brain of the bee.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-17T12:37:09+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-17T12:37:09+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="plants &amp; animals"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2014/bee.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-17:/440079</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-10-habitat-loss-threat-australia-species.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Habitat loss is the top threat to Australia's species</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Earlier this month, Australia's outgoing Threatened Species Commissioner Gregory Andrews told ABC ra...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Earlier this month, Australia's outgoing Threatened Species Commissioner Gregory Andrews told ABC radio that land clearing is not the biggest threat to Australia's wildlife. His claim caused a stir among Australia's biodiversity scientists and conservation professionals, who have plenty of evidence to the contrary.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-17T12:40:04+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-17T12:40:04+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="ecology"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/habitatlossi.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-17:/439995</id>
	<link href="http://www.esa.int/Our_Activities/Space_Science/Mars_Express/Webcam_on_Mars_Express_surveys_high-altitude_clouds" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Webcam on Mars Express surveys high-altitude clouds</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An unprecedented catalogue of more than 21 000 images taken by a webcam on ESA&rsquo;s Mars E...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.esa.int/var/esa/storage/images/esa_multimedia/images/2017/10/cloud_over_mars/17192645-1-eng-GB/Cloud_over_Mars_small.jpg" width="170" height="96" align="left" hspace="8"><br>
		<p>
An unprecedented catalogue of more than 21 000 images taken by a webcam on ESA&rsquo;s Mars Express is proving its worth as a science instrument, providing a global survey of unusual high-altitude cloud features on the Red Planet.
</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-17T09:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.esa.int/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.esa.int/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-17T09:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>ESA Top News</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-17:/440024</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-10-quantum-mechanical-analysis-metabolism.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Researchers take a step toward quantum mechanical analysis of plant metabolism</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hurricanes, traffic jams, demographic development &ndash; to predict the effect of such events, computer s...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hurricanes, traffic jams, demographic development &ndash; to predict the effect of such events, computer simulations are required. Many processes in nature, however, are so complicated that conventional computers fail. Quantum simulators may solve this problem. One of the basic phenomena in nature is the interaction between light and matter in photosynthesis. Physicists of Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT) have now made a big step towards quantum mechanics understanding of plant metabolism. This is reported in the Nature Communications journal.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-17T10:22:19+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-17T10:22:19+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="quantum physics"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/48-researcherst.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-16:/439625</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-10/uom-wad101217.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Whales and dolphins have rich 'human-like' cultures and societies</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(University of Manchester) Whales and dolphins (cetaceans) live in tightly-knit social groups, have ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>University of Manchester</i>) Whales and dolphins (cetaceans) live in tightly-knit social groups, have complex relationships, talk to each other and even have regional dialects -- much like human societies.  A major new study, published today in Nature Ecology &amp; Evolution, has linked the complexity of Cetacean culture and behavior to the size of their brains.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-16T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-10-16T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Agriculture</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-16:/439833</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-10/drnl-sln101617.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">SimPath licenses novel ORNL system for enhanced synthetic biology</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(DOE/Oak Ridge National Laboratory) SimPath has licensed a novel cloning system developed by the Dep...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>DOE/Oak Ridge National Laboratory</i>) SimPath has licensed a novel cloning system developed by the Department of Energy's Oak Ridge National Laboratory that generates and assembles the biological building blocks necessary to synthetically bioengineer new medicines and fuels.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-16T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-10-16T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Chemistry, Physics and Materials Sciences</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-15:/439260</id>
	<link href="https://dzone.com/guides/artificial-intelligence-machine-learning-and-predi?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Artificial Intelligence: Machine Learning and Predictive Analytics</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The age of Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning technologies seems to be right around the co...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The age of Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning technologies seems to be right around the corner. Companies like Facebook &amp; Google are breaking ground on astounding innovations in AI while others, like Tesla, warn of the possibility for harm. The purpose of this Guide is to steer you and your team through endless possibility, and to help build ethically responsible technologies that improve and enhance our lives.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-13T21:01:09+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Julian Morris</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://dzone.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://dzone.com"/>
		<updated>2017-10-13T21:01:09+00:00</updated>
		<title>DZone.com Feed</title></source>

	<category term="machine learning"/>

	<category term="artificial intelligence"/>

	<category term="nlp"/>

	<category term="tensorflow"/>

	<category term="neural network"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=6907135&amp;w=600"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-03-15:/374436</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/blog/learn/chapter/open-source-management/2017/3/6-operational-challenges-using-open-source-software" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">6 Operational Challenges to Using Open Source Software</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Title:&nbsp;6 Operational Challenges to Using Open Source Software15 MarLearn more</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div>Title:&nbsp;</div><div><div property="dc:title">6 Operational Challenges to Using Open Source Software</div></div></div><div><div><div>15 Mar</div></div></div><div><div><div><div><a href="http://localhost/blog/learn/chapter/open-source-management/2017/3/6-operational-challenges-using-open-source-software" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Learn more</a></div></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-03-15T14:30:13+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>bweinberg</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-03-15T14:30:13+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-03-14:/374005</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/news/three-challenges-web-according-its-inventor-0" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Three Challenges for the Web, According to its Inventor</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today marks 28 years since I&nbsp;submitted my original proposal&nbsp;for the world wide web. I imagined the w...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Today marks 28 years since I&nbsp;<a href="http://time.com/21039/tim-berners-lee-web-proposal-at-25/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">submitted my original proposal</a>&nbsp;for the world wide web. I imagined the web as an open platform that would allow everyone, everywhere to share information, access opportunities and collaborate across geographic and cultural boundaries. In many ways, the web has lived up to this vision, though it has been a recurring battle to keep it open.</p></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-03-14T10:30:56+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>WWW Foundation</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-03-14T10:30:56+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-03-08:/372328</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/blog/learn/chapter/open-source-management/2017/3/why-using-open-source-software-helps-companies-stay-flexible" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Why Using Open Source Software Helps Companies Stay Flexible and Innovate</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Title:&nbsp;Why Using Open Source Software Helps Companies Stay Flexible and Innovate8 MarLearn more</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div>Title:&nbsp;</div><div><div property="dc:title">Why Using Open Source Software Helps Companies Stay Flexible and Innovate</div></div></div><div><div><div>8 Mar</div></div></div><div><div><div><div><a href="http://localhost/blog/learn/chapter/open-source-management/2017/3/why-using-open-source-software-helps-companies-stay-flexible" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Learn more</a></div></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-03-08T15:30:17+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>golson</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-03-08T15:30:17+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-03-07:/372087</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/blog/stageless-deployment-pipelines-how-containers-change-way-we-build-and-test-software" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Stageless Deployment Pipelines: How Containers Change the Way We Build and Test Software</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Title:&nbsp;Stageless Deployment Pipelines: How Containers Change the Way We Build and Test Software...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div>Title:&nbsp;</div><div><div property="dc:title">Stageless Deployment Pipelines: How Containers Change the Way We Build and Test Software</div></div></div><div><div><div>7 Mar</div></div></div><div><div><div><div><a href="http://localhost/blog/stageless-deployment-pipelines-how-containers-change-way-we-build-and-test-software" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Learn more</a></div></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-03-07T04:13:01+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>DanGarfield</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-03-07T04:13:01+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-02-23:/368454</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/learn/intro-to-linux/2017/2/vim-sysadmins" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">An Introduction to Vim for Sysadmins</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Title:&nbsp;An Introduction to Vim for Sysadmins 23 FebLearn more</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div>Title:&nbsp;</div><div><div property="dc:title">An Introduction to Vim for Sysadmins </div></div></div><div><div><div>23 Feb</div></div></div><div><div><div><div><a href="http://localhost/learn/intro-to-linux/2017/2/vim-sysadmins" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Learn more</a></div></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-02-23T14:30:53+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>cschroder</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-02-23T14:30:53+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-02-22:/368044</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/blog/learn/compliance/2017/2/basic-rules-streamline-open-source-compliance-software-development" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Basic Rules to Streamline Open Source Compliance For Software Development</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Title:&nbsp;Basic Rules to Streamline Open Source Compliance For Software Development22 FebLearn mor...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div>Title:&nbsp;</div><div><div property="dc:title">Basic Rules to Streamline Open Source Compliance For Software Development</div></div></div><div><div><div>22 Feb</div></div></div><div><div><div><div><a href="http://localhost/blog/learn/compliance/2017/2/basic-rules-streamline-open-source-compliance-software-development" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Learn more</a></div></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-02-22T14:00:30+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>ibrahim</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-02-22T14:00:30+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-02-20:/367394</id>
	<link href="http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NetBSD-Reproducible-Builds" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">NetBSD Accomplishes Reproducible Builds</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A lot of Linux distributions have been focusing on reproducible builds support in the past few years...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A lot of Linux distributions have been focusing on reproducible builds support in the past few years -- ensuring individuals can rebuild a bit-for-bit replica of the original source code. NetBSD has now accomplished their operating system can be built in a reproducible build fashion...</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-02-20T21:11:08+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.phoronix.com/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.phoronix.com/"/>
		<updated>2017-02-20T21:11:08+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phoronix</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-02-17:/366864</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/blog/event/open-source-leadership-summit/2017/2/how-linux-foundation-advancing-next-gen-internet-infrastructure" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">How The Linux Foundation is Advancing Next-Gen Internet Infrastructure</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Title:&nbsp;How The Linux Foundation is Advancing Next-Gen Internet Infrastructure17 FebLearn more</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div>Title:&nbsp;</div><div><div property="dc:title">How The Linux Foundation is Advancing Next-Gen Internet Infrastructure</div></div></div><div><div><div>17 Feb</div></div></div><div><div><div><div><a href="http://localhost/blog/event/open-source-leadership-summit/2017/2/how-linux-foundation-advancing-next-gen-internet-infrastructure" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Learn more</a></div></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-02-17T19:24:10+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>mhinkle</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-02-17T19:24:10+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-02-17:/366743</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/news/event/open-source-leadership-summit/2017/2/video-linus-torvalds-how-build-successful-open-source-project" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Video: Linus Torvalds on How to Build a Successful Open Source Project</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Linux creator Linus Torvalds took the stage at Open Source Leadership Summit this week to share some...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Linux creator Linus Torvalds took the stage at <a href="http://bit.ly/2fZEV58" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Open Source Leadership Summit</a> this week to share some of his secrets to success in building one of the world&rsquo;s largest and most successful open source projects. </p></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-02-17T15:23:05+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>LibbyClark</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-02-17T15:23:05+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-02-17:/366744</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/learn/intro-to-linux-/2017/2/introduction-regular-expressions-new-linux-users" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">An Introduction to Regular Expressions for New Linux Users</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Title:&nbsp;An Introduction to Regular Expressions for New Linux Users17 FebLearn more</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div>Title:&nbsp;</div><div><div property="dc:title">An Introduction to Regular Expressions for New Linux Users</div></div></div><div><div><div>17 Feb</div></div></div><div><div><div><div><a href="http://localhost/learn/intro-to-linux-/2017/2/introduction-regular-expressions-new-linux-users" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Learn more</a></div></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-02-17T15:00:51+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>jlwallen</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-02-17T15:00:51+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-02-14:/365626</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/blog/learn/chapter/open-source-management/2017/2/what-open-source-software" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">What Is Open Source Software?</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Title:&nbsp;What Is Open Source Software? 14 FebLearn more</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div>Title:&nbsp;</div><div><div property="dc:title">What Is Open Source Software? </div></div></div><div><div><div>14 Feb</div></div></div><div><div><div><div><a href="http://localhost/blog/learn/chapter/open-source-management/2017/2/what-open-source-software" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Learn more</a></div></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-02-14T17:30:42+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>bweinberg</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-02-14T17:30:42+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-02-08:/364073</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/blog/compliance-ebook/2017/2/7-elements-open-source-management-program-teams-and-tools" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">The 7 Elements of an Open Source Management Program: Teams and Tools</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Title:&nbsp;The 7 Elements of an Open Source Management Program: Teams and Tools8 FebLearn more</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div>Title:&nbsp;</div><div><div property="dc:title">The 7 Elements of an Open Source Management Program: Teams and Tools</div></div></div><div><div><div>8 Feb</div></div></div><div><div><div><div><a href="http://localhost/blog/compliance-ebook/2017/2/7-elements-open-source-management-program-teams-and-tools" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Learn more</a></div></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-02-08T15:44:39+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>ibrahim</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-02-08T15:44:39+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-02-07:/363633</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/news/internet-things-10-types-enterprise-deployments" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">The Internet of Things: 10 Types of Enterprise Deployments</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As the Internet of Things (IoT) market continues its explosive growth and development, more and more...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>As the Internet of Things (IoT) market continues its explosive growth and development, more and more businesses are looking at the ways they can generate business value from connected devices and the data they generate. By 2020, research firm Gartner&nbsp;<a href="http://www.gartner.com/newsroom/id/3185623" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">predicts</a>&nbsp;that more than half of major new business processes and systems will incorporate IoT elements.</p></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-02-07T09:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>ZDNet</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-02-07T09:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-02-01:/361908</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/news/amazons-deep-learning-engine-now-apache-project" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Amazon’s Deep Learning Engine Is Now an Apache Project</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amazon Web Services has seemingly found open source religion over the past several months, including...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Amazon Web Services has seemingly found open source religion over the past several months, including in the field of artificial intelligence.</p></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-02-01T10:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Architecht</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-02-01T10:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-01-27:/360686</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/news/ibm-adds-tensorflow-support-powerai-deep-learning-0" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">IBM Adds TensorFlow Support for PowerAI Deep Learning</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today IBM announced that its&nbsp;PowerAI&nbsp;distribution for popular open source Machine Learning and Deep ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Today IBM announced that its&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ibm.com/us-en/marketplace/deep-learning-platform" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PowerAI</a>&nbsp;distribution for popular open source Machine Learning and Deep Learning frameworks on the POWER8 architecture now supports the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.tensorflow.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">TensorFlow</a>&nbsp;0.12 framework that was originally created by Google. TensorFlow support through IBM PowerAI provides enterprises with another option for fast, flexible, and production-ready tools and support for developing advanced machine learning products and systems.</p></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-01-27T09:30:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>insideHPC</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-01-27T09:30:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-01-23:/359210</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/news/ipv6-transition-quick-guide" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">IPv6 Transition: A Quick Guide</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Despite the much-anticipated depletion of public IPv4 addresses, adoption of&nbsp;network address transla...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Despite the much-anticipated depletion of public IPv4 addresses, adoption of&nbsp;<a href="http://www.networkcomputing.com/networking/nat-configuration-primer/546082124" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">network address translation (NAT)</a>&nbsp;has led most enterprises to continue using IPv4 both internally and at the internet edge.</p></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-01-23T10:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Network Computing</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-01-23T10:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-01-17:/357577</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/news/google-infrastructure-security-design-overview" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Google Infrastructure Security Design Overview</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This document gives an overview of how security is designed into Google&rsquo;s technical infrastructure. ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>This document gives an overview of how security is designed into Google&rsquo;s technical infrastructure. This global scale infrastructure is designed to provide security through the entire information processing lifecycle at Google. This infrastructure provides secure deployment of services, secure storage of data with end user privacy safeguards, secure communications between services, secure and private communication with customers over the internet, and safe operation by administrators.</p></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-01-17T09:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Google Cloud Platform</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-01-17T09:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-01-13:/356595</id>
	<link href="http://www.tecmint.com/linux-io-input-output-redirection-operators/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Learn The Basics of How Linux I/O (Input/Output) Redirection Works</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the most important and interesting topics under Linux administration is I/O redirection. This...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the most important and interesting topics under Linux administration is I/O redirection. This feature of the command line enables you to redirect the input and/or output of commands from and/or to files,...</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-01-13T07:01:33+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Aaron Kili</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.tecmint.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.tecmint.com"/>
		<updated>2017-01-13T07:01:33+00:00</updated>
		<title>Tecmint: Linux Howtos, Tutorials &amp; Guides » Linux Commands</title></source>

	<category term="linux commands"/>

	<category term="linux tricks"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-01-10:/355582</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/blog/event/LinuxCon-Europe/2016/10-lessons-10-years-amazon" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">10 Lessons from 10 Years of Amazon</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Title:&nbsp;10 Lessons from 10 Years of Amazon10 JanLearn more</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div>Title:&nbsp;</div><div><div property="dc:title">10 Lessons from 10 Years of Amazon</div></div></div><div><div><div>10 Jan</div></div></div><div><div><div><div><a href="http://localhost/blog/event/LinuxCon-Europe/2016/10-lessons-10-years-amazon" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Learn more</a></div></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-01-10T15:00:37+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>geekygirldawn</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-01-10T15:00:37+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-09-18:/429892</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/blog/os-jobs-report/2017/9/demand-open-source-skills-rise" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Demand for Open Source Skills on the Rise</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Title:&nbsp;Demand for Open Source Skills on the Rise18 SepLearn more</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div>Title:&nbsp;</div><div><div property="dc:title">Demand for Open Source Skills on the Rise</div></div></div><div><div><div>18 Sep</div></div></div><div><div><div><div><a href="http://localhost/blog/os-jobs-report/2017/9/demand-open-source-skills-rise" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Learn more</a></div></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-09-18T12:30:32+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>eshein</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-09-18T12:30:32+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-09-20:/430724</id>
	<link href="https://opensource.com/article/17/9/introduction-machine-learning" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">An introduction to machine learning today</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Machine learning and artificial intelligence (ML/AI) mean different things to different people, but ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://opensource.com/sites/default/files/lead-images/code_computer_development_programming.png" width="520" height="292" alt="An introduction to machine learning today" title="An introduction to machine learning today"><p>Machine learning and artificial intelligence (ML/AI) mean different things to different people, but the newest approaches have one thing in common: They are based on the idea that a program's output should be created mostly automatically from a high-dimensional and possibly huge dataset, with minimal or no intervention or guidance from a human. Open source tools are used in a variety of machine learning and artificial intelligence projects. In this article, I'll provide an overview of the state of machine learning today.</p>
<br>
<a href="https://opensource.com/article/17/9/introduction-machine-learning" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">read more</a>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-09-20T07:02:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Ulrich Drepper</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://opensource.com/frontpage</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://opensource.com/frontpage"/>
		<updated>2017-09-20T07:02:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>Opensource.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-09-20:/430786</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/news/ten-essentials-good-api-documentation" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">The Ten Essentials for Good API Documentation</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>API documentation is the number one reference for anyone implementing your API, and it can profoundl...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span>API documentation is the number one reference for anyone implementing your API, and it can profoundly influence the developer experience. Because it describes what services an application programming interface offers and how to use those services, your documentation will inevitably create an impression about your product&mdash;for better or for worse.</span></p></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-09-20T10:07:40+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>A List Apart</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-09-20T10:07:40+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-09-21:/431349</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/learn/intro-to-linux/2017/9/advanced-lm-sensors-tips-and-tricks-linux-0" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Advanced lm-sensors Tips and Tricks on Linux</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Title:&nbsp;Advanced lm-sensors Tips and Tricks on Linux21 SepLearn more</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div>Title:&nbsp;</div><div><div property="dc:title">Advanced lm-sensors Tips and Tricks on Linux</div></div></div><div><div><div>21 Sep</div></div></div><div><div><div><div><a href="http://localhost/learn/intro-to-linux/2017/9/advanced-lm-sensors-tips-and-tricks-linux-0" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Learn more</a></div></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-09-21T12:50:45+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>cschroder</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-09-21T12:50:45+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-09-25:/432242</id>
	<link href="http://www.linuxsecurity.com/content/view/175948?rdf" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">1.4 Million New Phishing Sites Launched Each Month</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>LinuxSecurity.com: The number of phishing attacks reach a record rate in 2017, but the majority of t...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<b>LinuxSecurity.com</b>: The number of phishing attacks reach a record rate in 2017, but the majority of the phishing sites remain active for just four- to eight hours.]]></content>
	<updated>2017-09-25T10:17:54+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.linuxsecurity.com/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.linuxsecurity.com/"/>
		<updated>2017-09-25T10:17:54+00:00</updated>
		<title>LinuxSecurity.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-09:/436677</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/news/10-layers-linux-container-security" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">10 Layers of Linux Container Security</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Containers provide an easy way to package applications and deliver them seamlessly from development ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p><span>Containers provide an easy way to package applications and deliver them seamlessly from development to test to production. This helps ensure consistency across a variety of environments, including physical servers, virtual machines (VMs), or private or public clouds. These benefits are leading organizations to rapidly adopt containers in order to easily develop and manage the applications that add business value.</span></p></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-09T11:30:36+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>OpenSource.com</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-10-09T11:30:36+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-09:/436676</id>
	<link href="https://www.linux.com/news/what-data-says-about-how-linux-kernel-developers-collaborate" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">What the Data Says About How Linux Kernel Developers Collaborate</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Many people consider themselves a Linux kernel developer first, an employee second. Even when they e...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><div><div property="content:encoded"><p>Many people consider themselves a Linux kernel developer first, an employee second. Even when they enjoy their current job and like their employer, most of them tend to look at the employment relationship as something temporary, whereas their identity as a kernel developer is viewed as more permanent and more important. Although companies do sometimes influence the areas where their employees contribute, individuals have quite a bit of freedom in how they do the work.</p></div></div></div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-09T12:59:40+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>OpenSource.com</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linux.com/feeds/rss"/>
		<updated>2017-10-09T12:59:40+00:00</updated>
		<title>Linux.com</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-10:/437015</id>
	<link href="https://www.redhat.com/en/about/press-releases/2017-red-hat-government-symposium-highlight-role-open-source-meeting-challenges-government-it" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">2017 Red Hat Government Symposium to Highlight the Role of Open Source in Meeting the Challenges of Government IT</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Red Hat Government Symposium leads the discussion on how open source can help government agencies. E...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Red Hat Government Symposium leads the discussion on how open source can help government agencies. Event offers a forum for agency and industry leaders to come together to discuss innovation and how to create more secure, efficient solutions to the government's biggest challenges.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-10T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.redhat.com/en/rss/press-releases</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.redhat.com/en/rss/press-releases"/>
		<updated>2017-10-10T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>Red Hat Press Releases</title></source>


</entry>


</feed>
<!-- vim:ft=xml
	  -->
