<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="atom-to-html.xsl"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Starred articles</title>
<generator uri="http://tt-rss.org/">Tiny Tiny RSS/17.4 (3b8d9bc)</generator>
<updated>2018-05-02T09:16:00+00:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost/tt-rss/public.php?op=rss&amp;id=-1&amp;key=vyn7su59c7b50850ac3</id>
<link href="http://localhost/tt-rss/public.php?op=rss&amp;id=-1&amp;key=vyn7su59c7b50850ac3" rel="self"/>

<link href="http://localhost/tt-rss" rel="alternate"/>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-24:/573597</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2018-08/bawh-osc082418.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">One step closer to bioengineered replacements for vessels and ducts</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Brigham and Women's Hospital) Researchers bioprint complex tubular tissues to replace dysfunctional...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>Brigham and Women's Hospital</i>) Researchers bioprint complex tubular tissues to replace dysfunctional vessels and ducts in the body.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-24T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2018-08-24T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Chemistry, Physics and Materials Sciences</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-24:/573347</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2018-08/vfi-nii082318.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">New immunotherapy inhibits tumor growth and protects against metastases</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(VIB (the Flanders Institute for Biotechnology)) Scientists at the VIB-UGent Center for Medical Biot...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>VIB (the Flanders Institute for Biotechnology)</i>) Scientists at the VIB-UGent Center for Medical Biotechnology have taken important steps forward in the development of a cancer-targeting immunotherapy. The research team developed a treatment in mice that destroys part of the tumor and stimulates the immune system to attack persistent surviving cancer cells. In addition, the researchers demonstrated that the treatment provides protection against the development of tumor formation in other areas of the body. Their findings have been published in the renowned academic journal Nature Communications.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-24T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2018-08-24T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Technology, Engineering and Computer Science</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-23:/573101</id>
	<link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2018/08/180823110013.htm" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Why are tropical forests so diverse? New study examines role of 'natural enemies'</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new study affirms a long-held hypothesis that the presence of specialized 'natural enemies' promot...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new study affirms a long-held hypothesis that the presence of specialized 'natural enemies' promotes tropical biodiversity. Except when it doesn't.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-23T15:00:13+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/"/>
		<updated>2018-08-23T15:00:13+00:00</updated>
		<title>Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-27:/574770</id>
	<link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2018/08/180827180741.htm" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Environmentally friendly farming practices used by nearly one third of world's farms</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nearly one-third of the world's farms have adopted more environmentally friendly practices while con...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nearly one-third of the world's farms have adopted more environmentally friendly practices while continuing to be productive, according to a global assessment by 17 scientists in five countries. Researchers analyzed various practices, including organic farming, that use land, water, biodiversity, labor, knowledge and technology to both grow crops and reduce environmental impacts like pesticide pollution, soil erosion, and greenhouse gas emissions.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-27T22:07:41+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/"/>
		<updated>2018-08-27T22:07:41+00:00</updated>
		<title>Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-24:/573242</id>
	<link href="https://linoxide.com/linux-how-to/linux-commands-brief-outline-examples/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">A Brief Outline of 106 Linux Commands with Examples</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Similar to the Command Prompt in Windows, Linux has the Terminal in order to help you configure and ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Similar to the Command Prompt in Windows, Linux has the Terminal in order to help you configure and interact with your system. For someone to work in the Terminal they need to familiarize themselves with Linux commands. Once familiarized it [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://linoxide.com/linux-how-to/linux-commands-brief-outline-examples/" target="_blank">A Brief Outline of 106 Linux Commands with Examples</a> appeared first on <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://linoxide.com" target="_blank">LinOxide</a>.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-24T01:54:25+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Nishali Wijesinghe</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://linoxide.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://linoxide.com"/>
		<updated>2018-08-24T01:54:25+00:00</updated>
		<title>LinOxide » LINUX COMMANDS</title></source>

	<category term="linux commands"/>

	<category term="linux howto"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-20:/571178</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2018-08-imaging-quantum-events.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Researchers succeed in imaging quantum events</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Quantum technology is a growing field of physics and engineering which utilizes properties of quantu...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Quantum technology is a growing field of physics and engineering which utilizes properties of quantum mechanics as a basis for advanced practical applications such as quantum computing, sensors, information, communication and medicine. This promises to lead to a new era of technology unlike anything we've known. Computers will be much more powerful, medical treatment will be non-invasive and far safer than today, and even teleportation can be envisioned. A phenomenon that stands at the core of this development is the Quantum phase transition.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-20T15:00:21+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2018-08-20T15:00:21+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="d1featured"/>

	<category term="quantum physics"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2018/5b7a92bf2815f.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-20:/571261</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2018-08/uob-msc081718.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Multi-purpose silicon chip created for quantum information processing</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(University of Bristol) An international team of researchers led by the University of Bristol have d...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>University of Bristol</i>) An international team of researchers led by the University of Bristol have demonstrated that light can be used to implement a multi-functional quantum processor.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-20T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2018-08-20T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Chemistry, Physics and Materials Sciences</title></source>

	<category term="d1featured"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-20:/571310</id>
	<link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2018/08/180820114121.htm" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Light from ancient quasars helps confirm quantum entanglement</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>New research boosts the case for quantum entanglement. Scientists have used distant quasars, one of ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>New research boosts the case for quantum entanglement. Scientists have used distant quasars, one of which emitted its light 7.8 billion years ago and the other 12.2 billion years ago, to determine the measurements to be made on pairs of entangled photons. They found correlations among more than 30,000 pairs of photons -- far exceeding the limit for a classically based mechanism.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-20T15:41:21+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/"/>
		<updated>2018-08-20T15:41:21+00:00</updated>
		<title>Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily</title></source>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/2018/08/180820114121-large.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-21:/571570</id>
	<link href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2018/08/20/stephen-hawking-a-brief-history-of-time-theory/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Stephen Hawking on What Makes a Good Theory and the Quest for a Theory of Everything</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;There are grounds for cautious optimism that we may now be near the end of the search for the...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>&ldquo;There are grounds for cautious optimism that we may now be near the end of the search for the ultimate laws of nature.&rdquo;</h3>

<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Brief-History-Time-Black-Holes/dp/0857501003/?tag=braipick-20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img width="320" height="504" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/abriefhistoryoftime_hawking.jpg?fit=320%2C504&amp;ssl=1" alt="Stephen Hawking on What Makes a Good Theory and the Quest for a Theory of Everything" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/abriefhistoryoftime_hawking.jpg?w=1531&amp;ssl=1 1531w, https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/abriefhistoryoftime_hawking.jpg?resize=240%2C378&amp;ssl=1 240w, https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/abriefhistoryoftime_hawking.jpg?resize=320%2C504&amp;ssl=1 320w, https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/abriefhistoryoftime_hawking.jpg?resize=768%2C1208&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/abriefhistoryoftime_hawking.jpg?resize=600%2C944&amp;ssl=1 600w, https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/abriefhistoryoftime_hawking.jpg?w=1360&amp;ssl=1 1360w" sizes="(max-width: 320px) 100vw, 320px"></a></p><p><em>&ldquo;We are bathing in mystery and confusion on many subjects,&rdquo;</em> Carl Sagan <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2018/04/05/carl-sagan-jonathan-cott-rolling-stone-interview/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">reflected in an interview</a> in August of 1980, <em>&ldquo;and I think that will always be our destiny. The universe will always be much richer than our ability to understand it.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p>Exactly eight years later, a mind far more scientifically formidable, if not as poetic, ignited in the popular imagination the idea that Sagan&rsquo;s worldview might be wrong &mdash; that the universe might, after all, be fully knowable and fully describable in a single elegant theory. </p>
<p>When <strong>Stephen Hawking</strong> (January 8, 1942&ndash;March 14, 2018) sent his book proposal for what would become <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Brief-History-Time-Black-Holes/dp/0857501003/?tag=braipick-20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong><em>A Brief History of Time: From the Big Bang to Black Holes</em></strong></a> (<a href="http://www.worldcat.org/title/brief-history-of-time/oclc/1005987912&amp;referer=brief_results" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>public library</em></a>) to Cambridge University Press &mdash; his first book of popular science &mdash; his editors cautioned him that it contained too much science to be sellable. Every equation, they admonished, would cut book sales in half. Hawking revised the manuscript until it contained a single equation &mdash; Einstein&rsquo;s <em>E = mc<sup>2</sup></em>. He transmuted all the remaining equations into a scintillating scientific narrative and completed the book just before he rallied Cambridge into a celebration of the 300th anniversary of Newton&rsquo;s <em>Principia</em> &mdash; perhaps the most paradigm-shifting book in the history of science, introducing the theory of gravitation to the world.</p>
<figure><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Brief-History-Time-Black-Holes/dp/0857501003/?tag=braipick-20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/stephenhawking.jpg?resize=680%2C453&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/stephenhawking.jpg?w=800&amp;ssl=1 800w, https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/stephenhawking.jpg?resize=240%2C160&amp;ssl=1 240w, https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/stephenhawking.jpg?resize=320%2C213&amp;ssl=1 320w, https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/stephenhawking.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/stephenhawking.jpg?resize=600%2C400&amp;ssl=1 600w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a><figcaption>Stephen Hawking (Photograph: Gemma Levine)</figcaption></figure>
<p><em>A Brief History of Time</em> was published on April Fool&rsquo;s Day 1988. In the introduction, Carl Sagan extolled Hawking as a &ldquo;worthy successor&rdquo; to Newton and lauded the book as replete with &ldquo;lucid revelations on the frontiers of physics, astronomy, cosmology and courage.&rdquo; Its accelerated ascent up the bestseller list stunned even Hawking himself. Within months, millions of copies had sold and the book was being translated into multiple languages &mdash; success so rapid that it entered the <em>Guinness Book of World Records</em>. (Hawking was amused that his American-made speech synthesizer struggled with the word, pronouncing it <em>Guy-ness</em>.) A &ldquo;phenomenal international bestseller&rdquo; for decades to come, in the words inscribed on the cover of the most current edition at the time of Hawking&rsquo;s death, <em>A Brief History of Time</em> went on to shape the way generations comprehend the universe. </p>
<p>One of the most abiding aspects of the book is Hawking&rsquo;s succinct description of what makes a good theory. In a sense, it parallels pioneering psychologist Jerome Bruner&rsquo;s framework of <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2016/01/20/jerome-bruner-actual-minds-possible-worlds-storytelling/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">what makes a good story</a>. With an eye to Karl Popper&rsquo;s famous assertion that <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2017/01/26/karl-popper-in-search-of-a-better-world-truth-certainty/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">&ldquo;knowledge consists in the search for truth&hellip; not the search for certainty,&rdquo;</a> Hawking writes:</p>
<blockquote><p>Any physical theory is always provisional, in the sense that it is only a hypothesis: you can never prove it. No matter how many times the results of experiments agree with some theory, you can never be sure that the next time the result will not contradict the theory. On the other hand, you can disprove a theory by finding even a single observation that disagrees with the predictions of the theory. As philosopher of science Karl Popper has emphasized, a good theory is characterized by the fact that it makes a number of predictions that could in principle be disproved or falsified by observation. Each time new experiments are observed to agree with the predictions the theory survives, and our confidence in it is increased; but if ever a new observation is found to disagree, we have to abandon or modify the theory.</p></blockquote>
<figure><a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2012/12/21/100-diagrams-that-changed-the-world/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/100diagramsthatchangedtheworld2.jpg?w=680&amp;ssl=1" data-recalc-dims="1"></a><figcaption>A 1568 illuminated illustration of the Ptolemaic geocentric system, from <a href="http://localhost/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>100 Diagrams That Changed the World</em></a></figcaption></figure>
<p>In her excellent biography, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Stephen-Hawking-Unfettered-Kitty-Ferguson/dp/1250139368/?tag=braipick-20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong><em>Stephen Hawking: An Unfettered Mind</em></strong></a> (<a href="http://www.worldcat.org/title/stephen-hawking-an-unfettered-mind/oclc/989106294&amp;referer=brief_results" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>public library</em></a>), Kitty Ferguson builds upon Hawking&rsquo;s formulation of a good theory and offers her own, more expansive and poetic definition:</p>
<blockquote><p>A theory is not Truth with a capital <em>T</em>, not a rule, not fact, not the final word. You might think of a theory as a toy boat. To find out whether it floats, you set it on the water. You test it. When it flounders, you pull it out of the water and make some changes, or you start again and build a different boat, benefiting from what you&rsquo;ve learned from the failure. </p>
<p>Some theories are good boats. They float a long time. We may know there are a few leaks, but for all practical purposes they serve us well. Some serve us so well, and are so solidly supported by experiment and testing, that we begin to regard them as truth. Scientists, keeping in mind how complex and surprising our universe is, are extremely wary about calling them that. Although some theories do have a lot of experimental success to back them up and others are hardly more than a glimmer in a theorist&rsquo;s eyes &mdash; brilliantly designed boats that have never been tried on the water &mdash; it is risky to assume that any of them is an absolute, fundamental scientific &ldquo;truth.&rdquo; </p>
<p>It is important, however, not to dither around forever, continuing to call into question well-established theories without having a good reason for doing so. For science to move ahead, it is necessary to decide whether some theories are dependable enough, and match observation sufficiently well, to allow us to use them as building blocks and proceed from there. Of course, some new thought or discovery might come along and threaten to sink the boat.</p></blockquote>
<figure><a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2016/04/25/black-hole-blues-janna-levin-joseph-weber/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/LIGO_blackholes.jpg?resize=680%2C510&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="680" height="510" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/LIGO_blackholes.jpg?w=1200&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/LIGO_blackholes.jpg?resize=240%2C180&amp;ssl=1 240w, https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/LIGO_blackholes.jpg?resize=320%2C240&amp;ssl=1 320w, https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/LIGO_blackholes.jpg?resize=768%2C576&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/www.brainpickings.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/LIGO_blackholes.jpg?resize=600%2C450&amp;ssl=1 600w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a><figcaption>A simulation of two black holes colliding to produce a gravitational wave &mdash; the landmark event detected by LIGO in 2016, arguably the most significant astrophysical discovery since Galileo&rsquo;s day and the triumph of <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2016/04/25/black-hole-blues-janna-levin-joseph-weber/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">an Everestine century-long climb toward truth</a>, building heavily on Hawking&rsquo;s work.</figcaption></figure>
<p>Hawking&rsquo;s own life was animated by one particular theoretical pursuit &mdash; the search for a theory, colloquially known as a <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2013/09/25/stephen-hawking-made-simple-animation/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">&ldquo;theory of everything,&rdquo;</a> that unifies Einstein&rsquo;s general relativity, the gravity-based science of the very large, and quantum mechanics, the science of the very small, based on three non-gravitational forces: the weak, strong, and electromagnetic forces. In the penultimate chapter of <em>A Brief History of Time</em>, Hawking considers this unholy grail of physics against the backdrop of the history of science:</p>
<blockquote><p>The prospects for finding such a theory seem to be much better now because we know so much more about the universe. But we must beware of overconfidence &mdash; we have had false dawns before! At the beginning of this century, for example, it was thought that everything could be explained in terms of the properties of continuous matter, such as elasticity and heat conduction. The discovery of atomic structure and the uncertainty principle put an emphatic end to that. Then again, in 1928, physicist and Nobel Prize winner Max Born told a group of visitors to G&ouml;ttingen University, &ldquo;Physics, as we know it, will be over in six months.&rdquo; His confidence was based on the recent discovery by Dirac of the equation that governed the electron. It was thought that a similar equation would govern the proton, which was the only other particle known at the time, and that would be the end of theoretical physics. However, the discovery of the neutron and of nuclear forces knocked that one on the head too. Having said this, I still believe there are grounds for cautious optimism that we may now be near the end of the search for the ultimate laws of nature.</p></blockquote>
<p>Complement the timelessly fascinating <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Brief-History-Time-Black-Holes/dp/0857501003/?tag=braipick-20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong><em>Brief History of Time</em></strong></a> with poet Marie Howe&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2018/05/22/singularity-marie-howe-stephen-hawking/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">stunning tribute to Hawking</a>, Hawking himself on <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2018/03/14/stephen-hawking-origins-interview/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">the meaning of the universe</a>, his &ldquo;theory of everything&rdquo; <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2013/09/25/stephen-hawking-made-simple-animation/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">animated in 150 seconds</a>, the story of <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2018/07/20/isobel-hawking-stephen-hawking/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">how his mother shaped his genius</a>, and the <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2014/01/08/stephen-hawking-childrens-book/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">children&rsquo;s book about time travel</a> he co-wrote with his daughter, then revisit some of today&rsquo;s leading thinkers on <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2013/01/22/this-explains-everything-brockman-edge-question/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">the most elegant theory of how the world works</a>. </p>
<h3>donating = loving</h3><p>Bringing you (ad-free) Brain Pickings takes me hundreds of hours each month. If you find any joy and stimulation here, please consider becoming a Supporting Member with a recurring monthly <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/donate/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">donation</a> of your choosing, between a cup of tea and a good dinner.</p>



<h3>newsletter</h3>
<p>Brain Pickings has a free weekly newsletter. It comes out on Sundays and offers the week&rsquo;s most unmissable reads. Here&rsquo;s <a href="http://us2.campaign-archive1.com/?u=13eb080d8a315477042e0d5b1&amp;id=de29ba37e7&amp;e=b2dbad0745" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">what to expect</a>. Like? <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/newsletter/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Sign up.</a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/brainpickings/rss/~4/k41T6VgKJWc" height="1" width="1" alt="">]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-20T06:00:58+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Maria Popova</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.brainpickings.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.brainpickings.org"/>
		<updated>2018-08-20T06:00:58+00:00</updated>
		<title>Brain Pickings</title></source>

	<category term="culture"/>

	<category term="science"/>

	<category term="books"/>

	<category term="stephen hawking"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-20:/571205</id>
	<link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2018/08/180820104215.htm" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">New in­form­a­tion on brain areas linked to tact­ile sense and meta­cog­nit­ive abil­ity</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new doctoral thesis gives information on the neural basis of the sense of touch. According to the ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new doctoral thesis gives information on the neural basis of the sense of touch. According to the results, magnetic stimulation of prefrontal cortex affected the subjects' performance in tactile tasks, and their ability to evaluate their performance in these tasks.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-20T14:42:15+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/"/>
		<updated>2018-08-20T14:42:15+00:00</updated>
		<title>Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-20:/571317</id>
	<link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2018/08/180820113027.htm" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Link between magnetic field strength and temperature</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Researchers recently discovered that the strength of the magnetic field required to elicit a particu...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Researchers recently discovered that the strength of the magnetic field required to elicit a particular quantum mechanical process corresponds to the temperature of the material. Based on this finding, scientists can determine a sample's temperature to a resolution of one cubic micron by measuring the field strength at which this effect occurs. Temperature sensing is integral in most industrial, electronic and chemical processes, so greater spatial resolution could benefit commercial and scientific pursuits.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-20T15:30:27+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/"/>
		<updated>2018-08-20T15:30:27+00:00</updated>
		<title>Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily</title></source>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/2018/08/180820113027-large.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-21:/571752</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2018-08-sub-nm-memory-device-nanofabrication.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Researchers develop sub-7-nm memory device without nanofabrication</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Scientists have developed some of the tiniest magnets to date, just 3-7 nanometers (nm) in size. Due...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Scientists have developed some of the tiniest magnets to date, just 3-7 nanometers (nm) in size. Due to their small dimensions and high thermal stability, as well as the simple self-assembly process used to make them, the nanomagnets represent an important step toward designing next-generation memory devices with ultra-high densities and low power consumption.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-21T14:40:01+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2018-08-21T14:40:01+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="general physics"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2018/141-researchersd.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-21:/571826</id>
	<link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2018/08/180821112018.htm" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Future information technologies: Nanoscale heat transport under the microscope</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Researchers have investigated heat transport in a model system comprising nanometer-thin metallic an...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Researchers have investigated heat transport in a model system comprising nanometer-thin metallic and magnetic layers. Similar systems are candidates for future high-efficiency data storage devices that can be locally heated and rewritten by laser pulses (Heat-Assisted Magnetic Recording). Measurements taken with extremely short X-ray pulses have shown that the heat is distributed a hundred times slower than expected.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-21T15:20:18+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/"/>
		<updated>2018-08-21T15:20:18+00:00</updated>
		<title>Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily</title></source>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/2018/08/180821112018-large.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-20:/571147</id>
	<link href="https://dzone.com/articles/free-software-vs-open-source-vs-freeware-whats-the?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Free Software vs Open Source vs Freeware: What's the Difference?</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the software development industry, technical terms are often dropped here and there. While some p...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p pid="2">In the software development industry, technical terms are often dropped here and there. While some people unknowingly use them interchangeably, some confuse their meanings altogether.</p>
<p pid="4">Free software, open source, freeware, and shareware are some of the most commonly confused software terms in the industry. </p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-20T13:01:01+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Dr. Michael Garbade</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://dzone.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://dzone.com"/>
		<updated>2018-08-20T13:01:01+00:00</updated>
		<title>DZone.com Feed</title></source>

	<category term="open source"/>

	<category term="free software"/>

	<category term="freeware"/>

	<category term="open source licensing"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=9999011&amp;w=600"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-20:/571401</id>
	<link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2018/08/180820113113.htm" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">A timescale for the origin and evolution of all of life on Earth</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new study has used a combination of genomic and fossil data to explain the history of life on Eart...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new study has used a combination of genomic and fossil data to explain the history of life on Earth, from its origin to the present day.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-20T15:31:13+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/"/>
		<updated>2018-08-20T15:31:13+00:00</updated>
		<title>Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-21:/571808</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2018-08-antarctic-rift-implications-volcanic-evolution.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">New Antarctic rift data has implications for volcanic evolution</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>New data revealing two tectonic plates fused to form a single Antarctic Plate 15 million years later...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>New data revealing two tectonic plates fused to form a single Antarctic Plate 15 million years later than originally predicted and this extra motion has major implications for understanding of the tectono-volcanic activity surrounding the Pacific Ocean, from the Alpine mountains in New Zealand to the California geological setting, according to research from Ben-Gurion University of the Negev (BGU).</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-21T15:53:50+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2018-08-21T15:53:50+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="earth sciences"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2018/newantarctic.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-21:/571922</id>
	<link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2018/08/180820155109.htm" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Ape parasite genomes reveal origin, evolution of leading cause of malaria outside Africa</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The genome sequences of ape parasites related to Plasmodium vivax, the main source of mosquito-borne...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The genome sequences of ape parasites related to Plasmodium vivax, the main source of mosquito-borne malaria outside Africa, provide insights on the origin and early evolution of the human parasite. This finding could have implications for better comprehending and eradicating malaria infection worldwide.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-20T19:51:09+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/"/>
		<updated>2018-08-20T19:51:09+00:00</updated>
		<title>Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily</title></source>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/2018/08/180820155109-large.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-21:/571888</id>
	<link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2018/08/180821094301.htm" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">CasPER -- a new method for diversification of enzymes</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Scientists have invented a new method that allows for flexible engineering of essential and nonessen...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Scientists have invented a new method that allows for flexible engineering of essential and nonessential enzymes without additional engineering.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-21T13:43:01+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/"/>
		<updated>2018-08-21T13:43:01+00:00</updated>
		<title>Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-22:/572079</id>
	<link href="https://www.google.com/url?rct=j&amp;sa=t&amp;url=https://www.prweb.com/releases/cio_monica_eaton_cardone_examines_economic_benefits_of_women_of_color_in_tech_and_business/prweb15706167.htm&amp;ct=ga&amp;cd=CAIyHGNkMTUzMjQ2MjMxOTY0NWQ6Y28udWs6ZW46R0I&amp;usg=AFQjCNFUOyiReoT8C9M9CHG4lln9Jb9h8g" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">CIO Monica Eaton-Cardone Examines Economic Benefits of Women of Color in Tech and Business</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Women of color remain underrepresented in technology and leadership, to the ... Other recent studies...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Women of color remain underrepresented in <b>technology</b> and leadership, to the ... Other recent <b>studies</b> further underscore the value of <b>diversity</b> in the&nbsp;...</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-21T17:26:15+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.google.co.uk/alerts/feeds/03626471526943961455/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.google.co.uk/alerts/feeds/03626471526943961455/"/>
		<updated>2018-08-21T17:26:15+00:00</updated>
		<title>Google Alert - diversity in science and technology</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-20:/571202</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2018-08-synthetic-dna-based-enzymes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Synthetic DNA-based enzymes</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Enzymes perform very specific functions and require little energy &ndash; which is why biocatalysts are al...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Enzymes perform very specific functions and require little energy &ndash; which is why biocatalysts are also of interest to the chemical industry. In a review article published in the journal Nature Reviews Chemistry, Professor Thomas Happe and Associate Professor Anja Hemschemeier from the Photobiotechnology work group at Ruhr-Universit&auml;t Bochum have provided a summary on what is known about the mechanisms of enzymes in nature. Moreover, the authors outline a future vision: artificial biocatalysts that are not protein-based, as they usually are in nature, but which are rather made from DNA. The article was published on 17 August 2018.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-20T14:34:13+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2018-08-20T14:34:13+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="biochemistry"/>

	<category term="d1featured"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2018/syntheticdna.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-20:/571321</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2018-08/iaa-btr082018.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Bioengineered tooth replacement opens doors to new therapies</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(International &amp; American Associations for Dental Research) Tooth loss is a significant health issue...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>International &amp; American Associations for Dental Research</i>) Tooth loss is a significant health issue currently affecting millions of people worldwide. Two articles published in the September 2018 issue of the Journal of Dental Research share recent advances in bioengineering teeth.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-20T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2018-08-20T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Technology, Engineering and Computer Science</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-20:/570964</id>
	<link href="http://news.mit.edu/2018/gps-inside-your-body-0820" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">A &amp;quot;GPS for inside your body&amp;quot;</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Investigating inside the human body often requires cutting open a patient or swallowing long tubes w...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Investigating inside the human body often requires cutting open a patient or swallowing long tubes with built-in cameras. But what if physicians&nbsp;could get a better glimpse in a&nbsp;less expensive, invasive, and time-consuming manner?</p>





<p>A team from MIT&rsquo;s <a href="http://csail.mit.edu" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Laboratory</a> (CSAIL) led by Professor Dina Katabi is working on doing exactly that with an &ldquo;in-body GPS" system dubbed&nbsp;ReMix. The new method can pinpoint the location of ingestible implants inside the body using low-power wireless signals. These implants could be used as&nbsp;tiny tracking devices on shifting tumors to help monitor&nbsp;their slight movements.</p>

<p>In animal tests, the team demonstrated that they can track the implants with centimeter-level accuracy. The team says that, one day, similar implants could be used to deliver drugs to specific regions in the body.</p>

<p>ReMix was developed in collaboration with researchers from Massachusetts General Hospital (MGH). The team describes the system in a paper that's being presented at this week's Association for Computing Machinery's Special Interest Group on Data Communications (SIGCOMM) conference in Budapest, Hungary.</p>

<div></div>

<p><strong>Tracking inside the body</strong></p>

<p>To test ReMix, Katabi&rsquo;s group first implanted a small marker in animal tissues. To track its movement, the researchers used a wireless device that reflects radio signals off the patient.&nbsp;This was based on a wireless technology that the researchers previously demonstrated to detect <a href="http://news.mit.edu/2016/detecting-emotions-with-wireless-signals-0920" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">heart rate</a>, <a href="http://news.mit.edu/2014/could-wireless-replace-wearables" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">breathing</a>, and <a href="http://news.mit.edu/2017/dina-katabi-csail-team-develop-wireless-system-to-detect-walking-speeds-0501" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">movement</a>. A special algorithm then uses that signal to pinpoint the exact location of the marker.</p>

<p>Interestingly, the marker inside the body does not need to transmit any wireless signal. It simply reflects the signal transmitted by the wireless device outside the body. Therefore, it doesn't need a battery or any other external source of energy.</p>

<p>A key challenge in using wireless signals in this way is the many competing reflections that bounce off a person's body. In fact, the signals that reflect off a person&rsquo;s skin are actually 100 million times more powerful than the signals of the metal marker itself.</p>

<p>To overcome this, the team designed an approach that essentially separates the interfering skin signals from the ones they're trying to measure. They did this using a small semiconductor device, called a &ldquo;diode,&rdquo; that mixes signals together so the team can then filter out the skin-related signals. For example, if the skin reflects at frequencies of F1 and F2, the diode creates new combinations of those frequencies, such as F1-F2 and F1+F2. When all of the signals reflect back to the system, the system only picks up the combined frequencies, filtering out the original frequencies that came from the patient&rsquo;s skin.</p>

<p>One potential application for ReMix is in proton therapy, a type of cancer treatment that involves bombarding tumors with beams of magnet-controlled protons. The approach allows doctors to prescribe higher doses of radiation, but requires a very high degree of precision, which means that it&rsquo;s usually limited to only certain cancers.</p>

<p>Its success hinges on something that's actually quite unreliable: a tumor staying exactly where it is during the radiation process. If a tumor moves, then healthy areas could be exposed to the radiation. But with a small marker like ReMix&rsquo;s, doctors could better determine the location of a tumor in real-time and either pause the treatment or steer the beam into the right position. (To be clear, ReMix is not yet accurate enough to be used in clinical settings. Katabi says a margin of error closer to a couple of millimeters would be necessary for actual implementation.)</p>

<p>"The ability to continuously sense inside the human body has largely been a distant dream," says Romit Roy Choudhury, a professor of electrical engineering and computer science at the University of Illinois, who was not involved in the research. "One of the roadblocks has been wireless communication to a device and its continuous localization. ReMix makes a leap in this direction by showing that the wireless component of implantable devices may no longer be the bottleneck."</p>

<p><strong>Looking ahead</strong></p>

<p>There are still many ongoing challenges for improving ReMix. The team next hopes to combine the wireless data with medical data, such as that from magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) scans, to further improve the system&rsquo;s accuracy. In addition, the team will continue to reassess the algorithm and the various tradeoffs needed to account for the complexity of different bodies.</p>

<p>"We want a model that's technically feasible, while still complex enough to accurately represent the human body," says MIT PhD student Deepak Vasisht, lead author on the new paper. "If we want to use this technology on actual cancer patients one day, it will have to come from better modeling a person's physical structure."</p>

<p>The researchers say that such systems could help enable more widespread adoption of proton therapy centers. Today, there are only about 100 centers globally.</p>

<p>"One reason that [proton therapy] is so expensive is because of the cost of installing the hardware," Vasisht says. "If these systems can encourage more applications of the technology, there will be more demand, which will mean more therapy centers, and lower prices for patients."</p>

<p>Katabi and Vasisht co-wrote the paper with MIT PhD student Guo Zhang, University of Waterloo professor Omid Abari, MGH physicist Hsaio-Ming Lu, and MGH technical director Jacob Flanz.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-20T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Adam Conner-Simons | Rachel Gordon | CSAIL</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://news.mit.edu/mitresearch-rss.xml</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://news.mit.edu/mitresearch-rss.xml"/>
		<updated>2018-08-20T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>MIT Research News</title></source>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image" 
		length="1"
		href="http://news.mit.edu/sites/mit.edu.newsoffice/files/styles/article_cover_image_original/public/images/2018/dina-katabi-acm-prize-computing-A1_0.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-02-23:/494243</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2018-02-global-effort-ocean-plastics.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Global effort could cut ocean plastics by 77% by 2025</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Global funding to revolutionise waste management in the world's worst polluting countries could clea...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Global funding to revolutionise waste management in the world's worst polluting countries could clean up ocean plastic by 77% by 2025.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-02-23T12:22:44+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2018-02-23T12:22:44+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="environment"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2018/globaleffort.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-02-22:/493984</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2018-02/aaft-mth022118.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">More than half the world's ocean are commercially fished</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(American Association for the Advancement of Science) More than half of the world's oceans are expos...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>American Association for the Advancement of Science</i>) More than half of the world's oceans are exposed to industrial fishing activities, a new study, conducted at unprecedented scale, reveals. Peak fishing activity, the study goes on to report, is more affected by cultural and political events such as holidays and closures than by changes in economic factors, or environmental ones.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-02-22T05:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2018-02-22T05:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Earth Science</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-02-07:/487925</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2018-02/wsu-wrb020718.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">WSU researchers build alien ocean to test NASA outer space submarine</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Washington State University) Building a submarine gets tricky when the temperature drops to -300 Fa...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>Washington State University</i>) Building a submarine gets tricky when the temperature drops to -300 Fahrenheit and the ocean is made of methane and ethane. Washington State University researchers are working with NASA to determine how a submarine might work on Titan, the largest of Saturn's many moons and the second largest in the solar system. The space agency plans to launch a real submarine into Titan seas in the next 20 years.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-02-07T05:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2018-02-07T05:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Space and Planetary Science</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-02-06:/486978</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2018-02-microplastics-small-problem-filter-feeding-ocean.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Microplastics: No small problem for filter-feeding ocean giants</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Plastic pollution has recently gained increasing attention for its effects on marine mammals, fish a...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Plastic pollution has recently gained increasing attention for its effects on marine mammals, fish and birds. However, it is still not fully understood to what extent small pieces of plastic, known as microplastics, impact marine life and ecosystems.&nbsp;</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-02-06T10:31:21+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2018-02-06T10:31:21+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="environment"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2018/microplastic.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-01-31:/484385</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2018-01-vote-corals-atlantic-ocean.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Regulators vote to protect more corals in Atlantic Ocean</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Federal fishing regulators on Tuesday approved a compromise they said would expand the amount of cor...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Federal fishing regulators on Tuesday approved a compromise they said would expand the amount of coral habitat preserved in the Atlantic Ocean while also protecting fishing interests.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-01-31T07:31:01+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2018-01-31T07:31:01+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="ecology"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2013/coral.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-01-25:/482361</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2018-01/uom-poh012418.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Primordial oceans had oxygen 250 million years before the atmosphere</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(University of Minnesota) Research by a University of Minnesota Duluth (UMD) graduate student Mojtab...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>University of Minnesota</i>) Research by a University of Minnesota Duluth (UMD) graduate student Mojtaba Fakhraee and Associate Professor Sergei Katsev has pushed a major milestone in the evolution of the Earth's environment back by about 250 million years.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-01-24T05:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2018-01-24T05:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Atmospheric Science</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-01-18:/479256</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2018-01/ioap-2wt011718.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">2017 was the warmest year on record for the global ocean</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Institute of Atmospheric Physics, Chinese Academy of Sciences) 2017 was the warmest year on record ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>Institute of Atmospheric Physics, Chinese Academy of Sciences</i>) 2017 was the warmest year on record for the global ocean according to an updated ocean analysis from Institute of Atmospheric Physics/Chinese Academy of Science.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-01-18T05:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2018-01-18T05:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Atmospheric Science</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-01-12:/477364</id>
	<link href="https://futurism.com/climate-change-acidifying-lakes-rivers-same-way-oceans/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Climate Change Is Acidifying Our Lakes and Rivers the Same Way It Does With Oceans</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Acidifying Water
Earth&rsquo;s oceans absorb about 40% of all the carbon dioxide (CO2) that humans e...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Acidifying Water</h2>
<p>Earth&rsquo;s oceans <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/climate-consensus-97-per-cent/2017/feb/16/scientists-study-ocean-absorption-of-human-carbon-pollution" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">absorb about 40%</a> of all the carbon dioxide (CO2) that humans emit into the atmosphere. That CO2 then acidifies the water and is known to harm marine wildlife, especially shellfish, in a well-documented phenomenon known as ocean acidification. Yet according to a new study <a href="http://www.cell.com/current-biology/fulltext/S0960-%209822(17)31655-X" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">published in </a><i><a href="http://www.cell.com/current-biology/fulltext/S0960-%209822(17)31655-X" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Current Biology</a>, </i>ocean waters are not the only bodies of water that are affected by CO2 emissions.</p>
<p>Researchers showed that, over the course of 35 years, four reservoirs in Germany had both a significant increase in CO2 and a related decrease in pH, with waters dropping by about 0.3. (pH runs on a scale of 1 to 14, with 1 being the most acidic and 14 being the most basic.) They detected these changes from data from the local Ruhr region agency, which monitors drinking water, over the years 1981 to 2015.</p>
<p>Through these records, the team was able to determine that CO2 levels were rising by noting changes in temperature, water density, pH, ion species distribution, and inorganic content.</p>
<figure><img src="https://futurism.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/lake-1200x800.jpg" alt="Freshwater bodies like this pristine mountain lake are affected by CO2 emissions, causing acidification and negatively affecting animals." width="1200" height="800"><figcaption>Image Credit: Makalu / Pixabay</figcaption></figure>
<p>Until now, the study of freshwater acidification has been difficult at best. This is because showing how the impact of carbon dioxide on ecosystems demands complicated modeling, and results are typically less clear than when studying ocean systems.</p>
<h2>Wildlife Danger</h2>
<p>It is likely, according to this study, that freshwater systems absorb CO2 in different ways than oceans do. While the details of these processes are not the same between fresh and saltwater bodies,&nbsp;they share an ability to<a href="https://futurism.com/marine-food-webs-brink-collapse-because-climate-change/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> negatively impact aquatic life</a>.</p>
<p>To explore this further, the team documented the effects of this acidification in freshwater crustaceans&nbsp;&mdash;two species of Daphnia, which are known as water fleas. In ocean studies, acidification affects animals&rsquo; abilities to form shells, but these freshwater species had before not been studied. This team found that these crustaceans, when exposed to higher levels of CO2, were less able to sense predators and defend themselves.</p>
<p></p>
<p>This body of research still needs further exploration, but it is clear that climate change is contributing to acidification in freshwater bodies of water as well as the oceans. There is one spot of hope: it has been suggested by some studies that this process<a href="https://www.newscientist.com/article/2087532-adding-rocks-to-oceans-could-de-acidify-water-and-save-coral/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> could be mitigated in the ocean</a>. As such, it is not out of reach to suggest that, as efforts to curb climate change continue, information like that found within this study could be used to do the same in freshwater.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com/climate-change-acidifying-lakes-rivers-same-way-oceans/" target="_blank">Climate Change Is Acidifying Our Lakes and Rivers the Same Way It Does With Oceans</a> appeared first on <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com" target="_blank">Futurism</a>.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-01-12T22:14:08+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Chelsea Gohd</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://futurism.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://futurism.com"/>
		<updated>2018-01-12T22:14:08+00:00</updated>
		<title>Futurism</title></source>

	<category term="earth &amp; energy"/>

	<category term="acidification"/>

	<category term="climate change"/>

	<category term="ocean acidification"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-01-08:/475249</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2018-01-plastic-free-oceans.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">On the way to plastic-free oceans</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Four days since leaving port, Dr. Katsiaryna Pabortsava reaches her destination. She's in the middle...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Four days since leaving port, Dr. Katsiaryna Pabortsava reaches her destination. She's in the middle of the North Atlantic, thousands of miles from land, and she's looking for microplastics.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-01-08T13:50:01+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2018-01-08T13:50:01+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="environment"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2018/onthewaytopl.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-12-07:/464090</id>
	<link href="https://inhabitat.com/over-200-nations-commit-to-ending-ocean-plastic-waste" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Over 200 nations commit to ending ocean plastic waste</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over 200 countries just signed a United Nations resolution in Nairobi, Kenya to eliminate plastic w...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img fl:hint-main-image="true" src="//inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/12/Plastic-Beach-889x592.jpg" alt="plastic beach, plastic waste, plastic pollution beach, plastic ocean, plastic pollution ocean, plastic pollution dog"></p>
<p>Over 200 countries just signed a <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/united-nations/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">United Nations</a> resolution in Nairobi, <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/kenya/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Kenya</a> to eliminate plastic waste in the world&rsquo;s oceans. The resolution is an important step towards establishing a legally binding treaty that would deal with the plastic pollution problem afflicting the world&rsquo;s oceans. According to the United Nations Environment Programme (UNEP), there will be more plastic by weight in the world&rsquo;s oceans than fish by 2050 if current trends continue. </p>
<p><img src="//inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/12/Plastic-From-Seabirds-889x596.jpg" alt="plastic pollution, plastic pollution seabirds, plastic seabird stomachs, plastic pulled from seabird stomaches"></p>
<p>The resolution offers hope for the future: &ldquo;There is very strong language in this resolution,&rdquo; said Vidar Helgesen, Norway&rsquo;s environment minister, in an interview with <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-environment-un-pollution/more-than-200-nations-promise-to-stop-ocean-plastic-waste-idUSKBN1E02F7?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=environmentNews" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reuters</a>. &ldquo;We now have an agreement to explore a legally binding instrument and other measures and that will be done at the international level over the next 18 months.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Although plastic pollution is a global problem, <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/norway" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Norway</a> was the country that initiated the UN resolution. &ldquo;We found micro plastics inside mussels, which is something we like to eat,&rdquo; said Helgesen. &ldquo;In January this year, a fairly rare species of whale was stranded on a beach because of exhaustion and they simply had to kill it. In its tummy they found 30 plastic bags.&rdquo; Even the most remote parts of the globe have not escaped the plastic menace. In the final episode of the acclaimed <a href="http://www.bbcearth.com/blueplanet2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Blue Planet II</a><em>, </em>plastic pollution is documented in isolated areas of <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/antarctica/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Antarctica</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://inhabitat.com/scientists-discover-cheap-method-to-identify-lost-99-of-ocean-microplastics/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Related: Scientists discover cheap method to identify &ldquo;lost&rdquo; 99% of ocean microplastics</a></p>
<p><img src="//inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/12/Plastic-Beach-889x592.jpg" alt="plastic beach, plastic waste, plastic pollution beach, plastic ocean, plastic pollution ocean, plastic pollution dog"></p>
<p><a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/china/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">China</a> is the world&rsquo;s largest producer of plastic waste and biggest emitter of greenhouse gases. However, the world&rsquo;s most populous country has taken the global lead in addressing these environmental crises. &ldquo;If there is one nation changing at the moment more than anyone else, it&rsquo;s China &hellip; the speed and determination of the government to change is enormous,&rdquo; said Erik Solheim, head of UNEP, according to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-environment-un-pollution/more-than-200-nations-promise-to-stop-ocean-plastic-waste-idUSKBN1E02F7?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=environmentNews" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reuters</a>. Meanwhile, the resolution, which was originally intended to have legally binding targets and timetables, was <a href="http://www.iflscience.com/policy/un-resolution-fighting-plastic-pollution-weakened-us-resistance/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">weakened by the United States</a>, after Trump Administration officials rejected the stronger language.</p>
<p>Current American intransigence notwithstanding, Solheim envisions a future in which products and manufacturing systems are redesigned to use as little plastic as possible. &ldquo;Let&rsquo;s abolish products that we do not need &hellip; if you go to tourist places like Bali, a huge amount of the plastic picked from the oceans are actually straws,&rdquo; said Solheim. Although there is much work to be done before a treaty is signed, several nations are already moving ahead to protect the environment. To mark the signing of the UN resolutions, 39 countries, including Chile, Oman, Sri Lanka and South Africa, adopted new commitments to reduce <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/plastic/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">plastic pollution</a>.</p>
<p>Via <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-environment-un-pollution/more-than-200-nations-promise-to-stop-ocean-plastic-waste-idUSKBN1E02F7?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=environmentNews" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reuters</a></p>
<p><em>Images via <a href="https://depositphotos.com/search/ocean-plastic.html?qview=76750639" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Depositphotos</a> and <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/10213764@N02/8037389194/in/photolist-eeFfCF-7Hxy4a-dfeHML-65h9PZ-bVmaTU-7MJugT-eeFfz6-bJy8EX-eeFfP6-eeLZhy-eeLZed-65mrbb-eeLZcw-8RjBXS-eeLZam-eeFfxa-cEAEc9-dN4B69-wkFjV-6NXDJJ-88UZ7P-aySGo1-ayQ2yk-DgbWuv-CP4WBu-DgbV1i-CiFdZ3-CP4X91-CGFTQB-CiNpRD-P2TC1s" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Trevor Leyenhorst/Flickr</a></em></p><div>
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Inhabitat?a=I1YsLYCfv3Y:fGIagRupOGQ:yIl2AUoC8zA" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Inhabitat?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Inhabitat?a=I1YsLYCfv3Y:fGIagRupOGQ:DLYy-l-dIDg" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Inhabitat?d=DLYy-l-dIDg" border="0"></a>
</div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-12-08T00:15:49+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Greg Beach</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://inhabitat.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://inhabitat.com"/>
		<updated>2017-12-08T00:15:49+00:00</updated>
		<title>Inhabitat - Sustainable Design Innovation, Eco Architecture, Green Building » green technology</title></source>

	<category term="policy"/>

	<category term="united nations"/>

	<category term="environment"/>

	<category term="pollution"/>

	<category term="norway"/>

	<category term="china"/>

	<category term="plastic"/>

	<category term="un"/>

	<category term="united states"/>

	<category term="news"/>

	<category term="international agreements"/>

	<category term="diplomacy"/>

	<category term="nature / environment"/>

	<category term="waste disposal"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-12-04:/462363</id>
	<link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2017/12/171204091205.htm" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Submarine volcanoes add to ocean soundscape</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Most volcanoes erupt beneath the ocean, but scientists know little about them compared to what they ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Most volcanoes erupt beneath the ocean, but scientists know little about them compared to what they know about volcanoes that eject their lava on dry land.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-12-04T14:12:05+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/"/>
		<updated>2017-12-04T14:12:05+00:00</updated>
		<title>Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily</title></source>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/2017/12/171204091205-large.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-11-29:/460344</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-11/nrni-hdm112917.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">How does microbial degradation of plastics work in the ocean?</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(NIOZ Royal Netherlands Institute for Sea Research) How does microbial degradation of plastics work ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>NIOZ Royal Netherlands Institute for Sea Research</i>) How does microbial degradation of plastics work in the ocean? Very little is known about this important process, while vast quantities of plastic litter enters the oceans and threaten marine life. The key factors controlling microbial degradation are largely unknown. NIOZ marine scientist Helge Niemann was awarded a grant of 2 million euro by the European Research Council (ERC) to find out how the process of microbial degradation works in the ocean.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-11-29T05:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-11-29T05:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Chemistry, Physics and Materials Sciences</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-26:/445142</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-10-ocean-acidification-strong-case-limiting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Ocean acidification research makes a strong case for limiting climate change</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Experiments and analyses carried out by more than 250 scientists from 20 German institutions clearly...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Experiments and analyses carried out by more than 250 scientists from 20 German institutions clearly indicate that ocean acidification and warming, along with other environmental stressors, impair life in the ocean. A brochure summarises major outcomes of the project for policymakers and the public. Members of the project Biological Impacts of Ocean Acidification (BIOACID) will also be present at the United Nations climate change conference COP23 in Bonn.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-26T11:18:02+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-26T11:18:02+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="environment"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/1-oceanacidifi.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-12:/438301</id>
	<link href="https://inhabitat.com/worlds-first-ocean-pollution-eating-seabin-launches-in-the-uk" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">World's first ocean pollution-eating Seabin launches in the UK</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>UK waterways are about to get a lot cleaner with the launch of the world&rsquo;s first production Seabin ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img fl:hint-main-image="true" src="https://inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/10/UK-gets-its-first-Seabin-in-Portsmouth-Harbour-3-889x500.jpg" alt="pollution, Australia, pastic, Seabin, overfishing, environment, innovation, green technology, green products, clean tech, "></p>
<p>UK waterways are about to get a lot cleaner with the launch of the world&rsquo;s first production Seabin in Portsmouth harbor. The device, which was developed by a pair of <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/Australia" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Australian</a> surfers, works by sucking in various kinds of <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/pollution" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">pollution</a> (including oil) and spitting out clean water. The Seabin can collect approximately 1.5 kg of waste each day and has a capacity of 12 kg &mdash; and in a given year, a single bin can collect 20,000 plastic bottles or 83,000 <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/plastic" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">plastic</a> bags. </p>
<p><img src="https://inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/10/UK-gets-its-first-Seabin-in-Portsmouth-Harbour-3-889x500.jpg" alt="pollution, Australia, pastic, Seabin, overfishing, environment, innovation, green technology, green products, clean tech, "></p>
<p>The Seabin was <a href="https://inhabitat.com/floating-seabin-sucks-up-ocean-waste-including-oil-and-detergents/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">first unveiled in December</a> 2015. To fund the <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/innovation" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">invention</a>, founders Andrew Turton and Pete Ceglinski created an <a href="https://www.indiegogo.com/projects/cleaning-the-oceans-one-marina-at-a-time#/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IndieGoGo campaign.</a> With little time to spare, the campaign exceeded its goal. </p>
<p>Equipped with $250,000, Turton and Ceglinski are now prepared to follow through with their plan, which entails cleaning up marinas with the <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/organic" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">natural</a> fiber garbage bin and an automated, above-the-water pump. The device was designed with marine safety in mind &ndash; only debris and chemical pollution on the surface of the water is collected; fish and other aquatic creatures are left alone.</p>
<p><img src="https://inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/10/UK-gets-its-first-Seabin-in-Portsmouth-Harbour-1-889x667.jpg" alt="pollution, Australia, pastic, Seabin, overfishing, environment, innovation, green technology, green products, clean tech, "></p>
<p><a href="https://www.thetimes.co.uk/edition/news/floating-seabin-invented-by-pete-ceglinski-and-andrew-turtonis-put-to-work-sucking-rubbish-from-sea-rh3ssrlqj" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">The Times</a> reports that the Seabin was installed near the base of the Land Rover Ben Ainslie Racing (BAR) team in the Portsmouth harbor. The group is passionate about <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/environment" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">environmental efforts</a> &ndash; not only have members pledged to give up meat every Monday, they only consume sustainable seafood. Now, they&rsquo;ve agreed to oversee the Seabin, which will improve the quality of water while protecting the cage of over 1,000 <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/overfishing" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">oysters</a> near the pontoon.</p>
<p><a href="https://inhabitat.com/new-study-reveals-plastic-pollution-in-the-antarctic-is-5x-worse-than-expected/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Related: New study reveals plastic pollution in the Antarctic is 5x worse than expected</a></p>
<p><img src="https://inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/10/UK-gets-its-first-Seabin-in-Portsmouth-Harbour-2-889x600.jpg" alt="pollution, Australia, pastic, Seabin, overfishing, environment, innovation, green technology, green products, clean tech, "></p>
<p>The Seabin team are also conducting trials at Spain&rsquo;s Port Adriano and the Port of Helsinki (Finland). In early November, the innovative device will go on sale for &pound;3,000 ($3,957).</p>
<p><a href="http://seabinproject.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">+ Seabin Project</a></p>
<p>Via <a href="https://www.thetimes.co.uk/edition/news/floating-seabin-invented-by-pete-ceglinski-and-andrew-turtonis-put-to-work-sucking-rubbish-from-sea-rh3ssrlqj?CMP=Sprkr-_-Editorial-_-thetimes-_-News-_-Imageandlink-_-Statement-_-Unspecified-_-TWITTER&amp;linkId=43352444" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">The Times</a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017/10/11/seabin-portsmouth-harbour/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Engadget</a></p>
<p><em>Images via <a href="http://seabinproject.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Seabin</a></em></p>
<p><img src="https://inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/10/UK-gets-its-first-Seabin-in-Portsmouth-Harbour-4-889x572.jpg" alt="pollution, Australia, pastic, Seabin, overfishing, environment, innovation, green technology, green products, clean tech, "></p><div>
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Inhabitat?a=G5-Bq2xy3Zw:xlhZ7XX__S4:yIl2AUoC8zA" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Inhabitat?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Inhabitat?a=G5-Bq2xy3Zw:xlhZ7XX__S4:DLYy-l-dIDg" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Inhabitat?d=DLYy-l-dIDg" border="0"></a>
</div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-11T22:09:46+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Amanda Froelich</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://inhabitat.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://inhabitat.com"/>
		<updated>2017-10-11T22:09:46+00:00</updated>
		<title>Inhabitat - Sustainable Design Innovation, Eco Architecture, Green Building » green technology</title></source>

	<category term="organic"/>

	<category term="environment"/>

	<category term="pollution"/>

	<category term="green technology"/>

	<category term="australia"/>

	<category term="clean tech"/>

	<category term="innovation"/>

	<category term="green products"/>

	<category term="sailing"/>

	<category term="plastic"/>

	<category term="water issues"/>

	<category term="news"/>

	<category term="overfishing"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-08-24:/422487</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-08/nsfc-nwt082417.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">NASA's Webb Telescope will study our solar system's 'ocean worlds'</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(NASA/Goddard Space Flight Center) NASA's James Webb Space Telescope will use its infrared capabilit...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>NASA/Goddard Space Flight Center</i>) NASA's James Webb Space Telescope will use its infrared capabilities to study the "ocean worlds" of Jupiter's moon Europa and Saturn's moon Enceladus, adding to observations previously made by NASA's Galileo and Cassini orbiters. The Webb telescope's observations could also help guide future missions to the icy moons.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-08-24T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-08-24T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Space and Planetary Science</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-07-31:/414687</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-07/yu-loa073117.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Loss of Arctic sea ice impacting Atlantic Ocean water circulation system</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Yale University) Arctic sea ice is not merely a passive responder to the climate changes occurring ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>Yale University</i>) Arctic sea ice is not merely a passive responder to the climate changes occurring around the world, according to new research. Scientists at Yale University and the University of Southampton say the ongoing Arctic ice loss can play an active role in altering one of the planet's largest water circulation systems: the Atlantic Meridional Overturning Circulation (AMOC).</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-07-31T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-07-31T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Atmospheric Science</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-07-11:/408611</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-07/f-dte070317.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Does the European public understand the impacts of climate change on the ocean?</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Frontiers) A new in-depth study of the European public's awareness of the impacts of climate change...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>Frontiers</i>) A new in-depth study of the European public's awareness of the impacts of climate change on the ocean shows that although many are relatively well informed, an alarming number remain either uninformed or misinformed. Many believe that Arctic sea-ice is already completely lost during the summer and that sea temperatures have already risen by more than 2&deg;C. Climate science needs to be effectively communicated to the public so that citizens demand climate action.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-07-11T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-07-11T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Atmospheric Science</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-06-06:/398512</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-06/awih-hta060617.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">How the Arctic Ocean became saline</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Alfred Wegener Institute, Helmholtz Centre for Polar and Marine Research) The Arctic Ocean was once...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>Alfred Wegener Institute, Helmholtz Centre for Polar and Marine Research</i>) The Arctic Ocean was once a gigantic freshwater lake. Only after the land bridge between Greenland and Scotland had submerged far enough did vast quantities of salt water pour in from the Atlantic.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-06-06T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-06-06T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Earth Science</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-17:/570305</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2018-08-telescope-mysteries-radio-dark-energy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">New telescope chases the mysteries of radio flashes and dark energy</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>South Africa is becoming one of the world's most important radio astronomy hubs, thanks in large par...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>South Africa is becoming one of the world's most important radio astronomy hubs, thanks in large part to its role as co-host of the Square Kilometre Array (SKA). Now a new telescope is being unveiled that will be built at the SKA South Africa site in the Karoo. The Hydrogen Intensity and Real-time Analysis eXperiment (HIRAX) project is an international collaboration being led by scientists from the University of KwaZulu-Natal. The Conversation Africa chatted to project leader Professor Kavilan Moodley about HIRAX's scientific goals.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-17T14:25:27+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2018-08-17T14:25:27+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="astronomy"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2018/3-newtelescope.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-17:/570217</id>
	<link href="https://dzone.com/articles/when-machine-learning-meets-the-business-world?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">When Machine Learning Meets the Business World</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Businesses have always been at the forefront as early adopters of new technologies. Advancements in ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p pid="3">Businesses have always been at the forefront as early adopters of new technologies. Advancements in computing like Machine Learning have already made a notable impact on the business world. With business operations and processes spread across varying levels, the inclusion of a Machine Learning framework can prove worthwhile in increasing efficiency, productivity, and speed.</p> 
<p pid="4">Machine Learning has found widespread acceptance among enterprises. <a href="https://s3.amazonaws.com/files.technologyreview.com/whitepapers/MITTR_GoogleforWork_Survey.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MIT Technology Review and Google Cloud</a> recently published a report based on their studies in Machine Learning and its adoption. The reports state that about 60 percent of the respondents have already implemented Machine Learning into their business.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-17T09:06:03+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Vinod Saratchandran</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://dzone.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://dzone.com"/>
		<updated>2018-08-17T09:06:03+00:00</updated>
		<title>DZone.com Feed</title></source>

	<category term="artificial intelligence"/>

	<category term="business"/>

	<category term="d1featured"/>

	<category term="deep learning"/>

	<category term="enterprise"/>

	<category term="machine learning"/>

	<category term="machine learning algorithm"/>

	<category term="reinforcement learning"/>

	<category term="software application development"/>

	<category term="supervised machine learning"/>

	<category term="unsupervised machine learning"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10007548&amp;w=600"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-16:/570032</id>
	<link href="https://futurism.com/videos/openai-robotic-hand/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">OpenAI’s Robotic Hand Learned to Make Precise, Human-like Movements</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In order to consistently perform with high-precision the robotic hand needs to be able to react to a...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="169" src="https://wp-assets.futurism.com/2018/08/test-300x169.png" alt=""></div><p>In order to consistently perform with high-precision the robotic hand needs to be able to react to a variety of objects.</p>
<p></p><p>The post <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com/videos/openai-robotic-hand/" target="_blank">OpenAI&rsquo;s Robotic Hand Learned to Make Precise, Human-like Movements</a> appeared first on <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com" target="_blank">Futurism</a>.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-16T21:43:55+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Jacob Banas</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://futurism.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://futurism.com"/>
		<updated>2018-08-16T21:43:55+00:00</updated>
		<title>Futurism</title></source>

	<category term="d1featured"/>

	<category term="dactyl"/>

	<category term="machine learning"/>

	<category term="openai"/>

	<category term="precise robot"/>

	<category term="robot hand"/>

	<category term="robots &amp; machines"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-17:/570272</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2018-08-einstein-equivalence-principle-quantum-world.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">How Einstein's equivalence principle extends to the quantum world</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>How Einstein's equivalence principle extends to the quantum world has been puzzling physicists for d...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>How Einstein's equivalence principle extends to the quantum world has been puzzling physicists for decades, but a team including a University of Queensland researcher has found the key to this question.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-17T12:46:15+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2018-08-17T12:46:15+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="d1featured"/>

	<category term="quantum physics"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2018/1-einstein.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-17:/570398</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2018-08-science-alma-highest-frequency-capabilities.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">First science with ALMA's highest-frequency capabilities</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The ALMA telescope in Chile has transformed how we see the universe, showing us otherwise invisible ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The ALMA telescope in Chile has transformed how we see the universe, showing us otherwise invisible parts of the cosmos. This array of incredibly precise antennas studies a comparatively high-frequency sliver of radio light: waves that range from a few tenths of a millimeter to several millimeters in length. Recently, scientists pushed ALMA to its limits, harnessing the array's highest-frequency (shortest wavelength) capabilities, which peer into a part of the electromagnetic spectrum that straddles the line between infrared light and radio waves.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-17T16:41:10+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2018-08-17T16:41:10+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="astronomy"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2018/firstscience.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-17:/570269</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2018-08-image-sun-magnetic-field.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Image: Sun's magnetic field modeled</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>NASA's Solar Dynamics Observatory (SDO) scientists used their computer models to generate a view of ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>NASA's Solar Dynamics Observatory (SDO) scientists used their computer models to generate a view of the Sun's magnetic field on August 10, 2018.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-17T12:52:57+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2018-08-17T12:52:57+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="d1featured"/>

	<category term="space exploration"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2018/imagesunsmag.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-16:/569725</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2018-08/tiot-hdp081618.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">How do plants rest photosynthetic activity at night?</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Tokyo Institute of Technology) Scientists at Tokyo Institute of Technology have identified two prot...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>Tokyo Institute of Technology</i>) Scientists at Tokyo Institute of Technology have identified two proteins that allow plants to respond to changes in surrounding light conditions and thereby make photosynthesis more efficient.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-16T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2018-08-16T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Agriculture</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-16:/569866</id>
	<link href="https://dzone.com/articles/how-sensor-technology-is-revolutionizing-healthcar?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">How Sensor Technology Is Revolutionizing Healthcare</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the rising popularity of Fitbits, smartwatches, and IoT, sensor technology is starting to have ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p pid="5">With the rising popularity of Fitbits, smartwatches, and IoT, sensor technology is starting to have a real impact on healthcare.</p> 
<p pid="6">The market for medical wearables is estimated to hit $12.1 billion by 2021, according to a recent <a href="https://www.marketsandmarkets.com/Market-Reports/wearable-medical-device-market-81753973.html?gclid=CjwKCAiAmb7RBRATEiwA7kS8VNa5y7oFWGL6JgvR5HeH4-8NGxnVtm5W3mTby2ZNd0rGdwcPUxaDohoCLI8QAvD_BwE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">study by Markets and Markets</a>. These wearables go far beyond fitness tracking. New devices can monitor for heart attacks, signs of stroke, and measure and control insulin levels for diabetics.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-16T16:01:02+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Rassel James</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://dzone.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://dzone.com"/>
		<updated>2018-08-16T16:01:02+00:00</updated>
		<title>DZone.com Feed</title></source>

	<category term="iot"/>

	<category term="healthcare"/>

	<category term="wearables"/>

	<category term="connected devices"/>

	<category term="sensor technology"/>

	<category term="ekg"/>

	<category term="gluconext"/>

	<category term="kardia"/>

	<category term="theora care"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=9976169&amp;w=600"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-08-17:/570161</id>
	<link href="https://www.tecmint.com/linux-curl-command-examples/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">15 Tips On How to Use ‘Curl’ Command in Linux</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in the mid-1990&rsquo;s when the Internet was still in its infancy, a Swedish programmer named Daniel...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in the mid-1990&rsquo;s when the Internet was still in its infancy, a Swedish programmer named Daniel Stenberg started a project that eventually grew into what we know as curl today. Initially, he aimed...</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-08-16T06:27:59+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Gabriel Cánepa</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.tecmint.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.tecmint.com"/>
		<updated>2018-08-16T06:27:59+00:00</updated>
		<title>Tecmint: Linux Howtos, Tutorials &amp; Guides » Linux Commands</title></source>

	<category term="linux commands"/>

	<category term="curl command examples"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-07-27:/560322</id>
	<link href="http://www.esa.int/ESA_Multimedia/Videos/2018/07/What_is_an_eclipse" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">What is an eclipse?</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Get ready for tonight's lunar eclipse and find out why the Moon will take on a re...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.esa.int/var/esa/storage/images/esa_multimedia/images/2018/07/blood_moon/17623610-1-eng-GB/Blood_Moon_large.jpg" width="600"><br>
		Get ready for tonight's lunar eclipse and find out why the Moon will take on a reddish colour]]></content>
	<updated>2018-07-27T08:54:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.esa.int/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.esa.int/"/>
		<updated>2018-07-27T08:54:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>ESA Top News</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-07-25:/559273</id>
	<link href="http://www.esa.int/spaceinvideos/Videos/2018/07/Galileo_23_26_Liftoff_replay" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Galileo liftoff replay</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Watch the replay of Europe&rsquo;s next four Galileo satellites lifting off at 11:25 GM...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.esa.int/var/esa/storage/images/esa_multimedia/images/2018/07/galileo_liftoff/17618285-3-eng-GB/Galileo_liftoff_large.jpg" width="600"><br>
		Watch the replay of Europe&rsquo;s next four Galileo satellites lifting off at 11:25 GMT (13:25 CEST, 08:25 local time) on Wednesday 25 July]]></content>
	<updated>2018-07-25T10:50:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.esa.int/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.esa.int/"/>
		<updated>2018-07-25T10:50:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>ESA Top News</title></source>

	<category term="d1featured"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-07-11:/552990</id>
	<link href="http://www.esa.int/Our_Activities/Observing_the_Earth/Copernicus/Sentinel-5P/Copernicus_Sentinel-5P_releases_first_data" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Copernicus Sentinel-5P releases first data</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Following months of tests and careful evaluation, the first data on air pollutants from...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.esa.int/var/esa/storage/images/esa_multimedia/images/2018/07/air_pollution_movement/17591108-1-eng-GB/Air_pollution_movement_small.gif" width="1200" height="675" align="left" hspace="8"><br>
		<p>
Following months of tests and careful evaluation, the first data on air pollutants from the Copernicus Sentinel-5P satellite have been released. These first maps show a range of trace gases that affect air quality such as carbon monoxide, nitrogen dioxide and ozone.
</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-07-11T14:50:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.esa.int/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.esa.int/"/>
		<updated>2018-07-11T14:50:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>ESA Top News</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-06-28:/547485</id>
	<link href="http://www.esa.int/Our_Activities/Space_Science/New_launch_date_for_James_Webb_Space_Telescope" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">New launch date for James Webb Space Telescope</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After completion of an independent review, a new launch date for the James Webb Space T...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.esa.int/var/esa/storage/images/esa_multimedia/images/2018/03/artist_s_impression_of_the_james_webb_space_telescope/17429369-1-eng-GB/Artist_s_impression_of_the_James_Webb_Space_Telescope_small.jpg" width="170" height="96" align="left" hspace="8"><br>
		<p>
After completion of an independent review, a new launch date for the James Webb Space Telescope has been announced: 30 March 2021.
</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-06-28T08:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.esa.int/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.esa.int/"/>
		<updated>2018-06-28T08:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>ESA Top News</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-06-25:/545979</id>
	<link href="http://www.esa.int/Our_Activities/Space_Engineering_Technology/Hera/Earth_s_first_mission_to_a_binary_asteroid_for_planetary_defence" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Earth’s first mission to a binary asteroid, for planetary defence</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Planning for humankind&rsquo;s first mission to a binary asteroid system has entered its next...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.esa.int/var/esa/storage/images/esa_multimedia/images/2018/06/hera_measures_didymoon_s_size_shape_and_mass/17563521-1-eng-GB/Hera_measures_Didymoon_s_size_shape_and_mass_small.gif" width="640" height="360" align="left" hspace="8"><br>
		<p>
Planning for humankind&rsquo;s first mission to a binary asteroid system has entered its next engineering phase. ESA&rsquo;s proposed Hera mission would also be Europe&rsquo;s contribution to an ambitious planetary defence experiment.
</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-06-25T08:35:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.esa.int/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.esa.int/"/>
		<updated>2018-06-25T08:35:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>ESA Top News</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-06-06:/537313</id>
	<link href="http://www.esa.int/Our_Activities/Human_Spaceflight/International_Space_Station/Liftoff_Alexander_Gerst_returns_to_space_on_Horizons_mission" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Liftoff – Alexander Gerst returns to space</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today at 11:12 GMT (13:12 CEST) ESA astronaut Alexander Gerst was launched into space a...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.esa.int/var/esa/storage/images/esa_multimedia/images/2018/06/horizons_liftoff3/17538728-2-eng-GB/Horizons_liftoff_small.jpg" width="170" height="96" align="left" hspace="8"><br>
		<p>
Today at 11:12 GMT (13:12 CEST) ESA astronaut Alexander Gerst was launched into space alongside NASA astronaut Serena Au&ntilde;&oacute;n-Chancellor and Roscosmos commander Sergei Prokopyev in the Soyuz MS-09 spacecraft from Baikonur cosmodrome in Kazakhstan.
</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-06-06T10:12:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.esa.int/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.esa.int/"/>
		<updated>2018-06-06T10:12:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>ESA Top News</title></source>

	<category term="d1featured"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-05-25:/532399</id>
	<link href="http://www.esa.int/Our_Activities/Space_Engineering_Technology/Student_Hyperloop_motor_tested_at_ESA" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Student Hyperloop motor tested at ESA</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dutch students due to compete in Elon Musk&rsquo;s high-speed &lsquo;Hyperloop&rsquo; challenge this July...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.esa.int/var/esa/storage/images/esa_multimedia/images/2018/05/hyperloop_motor_testing/17521990-1-eng-GB/Hyperloop_motor_testing_small.jpg" width="170" height="96" align="left" hspace="8"><br>
		<p>
Dutch students due to compete in Elon Musk&rsquo;s high-speed &lsquo;Hyperloop&rsquo; challenge this July subjected their motor module to near-vacuum conditions within ESA&rsquo;s technical heart.
</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-05-25T11:51:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.esa.int/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.esa.int/"/>
		<updated>2018-05-25T11:51:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>ESA Top News</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-05-09:/525380</id>
	<link href="http://www.esa.int/Our_Activities/Observing_the_Earth/Copernicus/Sentinel-3/Copernicus_Sentinel-3B_delivers_first_images" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Copernicus Sentinel-3B delivers first images</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Less than two weeks after it was launched, the Copernicus Sentinel-3B satellite has del...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.esa.int/var/esa/storage/images/esa_multimedia/images/2018/05/antarctic_sunset_from_sentinel-3b/17503373-3-eng-GB/Antarctic_sunset_from_Sentinel-3B_small.jpg" width="170" height="96" align="left" hspace="8"><br>
		<p>
Less than two weeks after it was launched, the Copernicus Sentinel-3B satellite has delivered its first images of Earth. Exceeding expectations, this first set of images include the sunset over Antarctica, sea ice in the Arctic and a view of northern Europe.
</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-05-09T08:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.esa.int/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.esa.int/"/>
		<updated>2018-05-09T08:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>ESA Top News</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-05-07:/524354</id>
	<link href="http://www.esa.int/Our_Activities/Space_Science/ESA_selects_three_new_mission_concepts_for_study" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">ESA selects three new mission concepts for study</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A high-energy survey of the early Universe, an infrared observatory to study the format...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.esa.int/var/esa/storage/images/esa_multimedia/images/2018/05/m5_mission_themes/17498510-1-eng-GB/M5_mission_themes_small.jpg" width="170" height="96" align="left" hspace="8"><br>
		<p>
A high-energy survey of the early Universe, an infrared observatory to study the formation of stars, planets and galaxies, and a Venus orbiter are to be considered for ESA&rsquo;s fifth medium class mission in its Cosmic Vision science programme, with a planned launch date in 2032.
</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-05-07T09:15:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.esa.int/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.esa.int/"/>
		<updated>2018-05-07T09:15:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>ESA Top News</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-05-03:/523010</id>
	<link href="http://www.esa.int/Our_Activities/Telecommunications_Integrated_Applications/Space_photons_bring_a_new_dimension_to_cryptography" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Space photons bring a new dimension to cryptography</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>ESA and its partners will investigate how satellites can distribute photon &lsquo;keys&rsquo; to he...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.esa.int/var/esa/storage/images/esa_multimedia/images/2014/04/esa_s_optical_ground_station/14488494-1-eng-GB/ESA_s_Optical_Ground_Station_small.jpg" width="170" height="96" align="left" hspace="8"><br>
		<p>
ESA and its partners will investigate how satellites can distribute photon &lsquo;keys&rsquo; to help secure encryption.
</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-05-03T05:25:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.esa.int/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.esa.int/"/>
		<updated>2018-05-03T05:25:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>ESA Top News</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2018-05-02:/522402</id>
	<link href="http://www.esa.int/Our_Activities/Observing_the_Earth/CryoSat/CryoSat_reveals_retreat_of_Patagonian_glaciers" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">CryoSat reveals retreat of Patagonian glaciers</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While ESA&rsquo;s CryoSat continues to provide clear insight into how much sea ice is being l...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.esa.int/var/esa/storage/images/esa_multimedia/videos/2018/05/glaciers_in_decline/17493882-1-eng-GB/Glaciers_in_decline_small.jpg" width="170" height="96" align="left" hspace="8"><br>
		<p>
While ESA&rsquo;s CryoSat continues to provide clear insight into how much sea ice is being lost and how the Antarctic and Greenlandic ice sheets are changing, the mission has again surpassed its original scope by revealing exactly how mountain glaciers are also succumbing to change.
</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2018-05-02T09:16:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.esa.int/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.esa.int/"/>
		<updated>2018-05-02T09:16:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>ESA Top News</title></source>


</entry>


</feed>
<!-- vim:ft=xml
	  -->
