<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="atom-to-html.xsl"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Starred articles</title>
<generator uri="http://tt-rss.org/">Tiny Tiny RSS/17.4 (3b8d9bc)</generator>
<updated>2017-10-24T16:46:00+00:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost/tt-rss/public.php?op=rss&amp;id=-1&amp;key=vyn7su59c7b50850ac3</id>
<link href="http://localhost/tt-rss/public.php?op=rss&amp;id=-1&amp;key=vyn7su59c7b50850ac3" rel="self"/>

<link href="http://localhost/tt-rss" rel="alternate"/>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-11-02:/448149</id>
	<link href="http://www.esa.int/ESA_Multimedia/Videos/2017/10/Sentinel-5P_prepared_for_liftoff" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Sentinel-5P timelapse</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A look back on the preparations for the 13 October liftoff of Sentinel-5P</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.esa.int/var/esa/storage/images/esa_multimedia/images/2017/10/sentinel-5p_before_encapsulation/17230117-1-eng-GB/Sentinel-5P_before_encapsulation_large.jpg" width="600"><br>
		A look back on the preparations for the 13 October liftoff of Sentinel-5P]]></content>
	<updated>2017-11-02T09:30:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.esa.int/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.esa.int/"/>
		<updated>2017-11-02T09:30:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>ESA Top News</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-11-13:/453083</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-11-photosynthesis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Learning from photosynthesis: Synthetic circuits can harvest light energy</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The green sulfur bacterium makes its home in the chilly waters of the Black Sea. To eke out its lone...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The green sulfur bacterium makes its home in the chilly waters of the Black Sea. To eke out its lonely existence, this life form scavenges energy from the feeble sunlight available to it at a depth of over 250 feet.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-11-13T16:22:30+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-11-13T16:22:30+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="materials science"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/learningfrom.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-11-10:/452062</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-11-closer-crops-yield.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">One step closer to crops with twice the yield</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Scientists from Wageningen University &amp; Research have found natural genetic variation for photosynth...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Scientists from Wageningen University &amp; Research have found natural genetic variation for photosynthesis in plants and are unravelling it to the DNA level. As a result it should be possible to breed crops that use photosynthesis more effectively in the future, increasing their yield and enabling them to capture more CO2 from the air in the soil. This represents a major step on the long road to solving global food challenges and realising the Paris climate agreement.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-11-10T14:48:12+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-11-10T14:48:12+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="biotechnology"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/1-1-onestepclose.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-11-10:/451999</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-11-earliest-life-evolved-earth.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">New study sheds light on how earliest forms of life evolved on Earth</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new study led by ANU has shed light on how the earliest forms of life evolved on Earth about four ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new study led by ANU has shed light on how the earliest forms of life evolved on Earth about four billion years ago.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-11-10T13:43:02+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-11-10T13:43:02+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="evolution"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/1-newstudyshed.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-11-09:/451669</id>
	<link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2017/11/171109135703.htm" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Dawn spacecraft explores dwarf planet Ceres' interior evolution</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Surface features on Ceres -- the largest world between Mars and Jupiter -- and its interior evolutio...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Surface features on Ceres -- the largest world between Mars and Jupiter -- and its interior evolution have a closer relationship than one might think. A recent study analyzed Ceres' surface features to reveal clues about the dwarf planet's interior evolution.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-11-09T18:57:03+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/"/>
		<updated>2017-11-09T18:57:03+00:00</updated>
		<title>Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily</title></source>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/2017/11/171109135703-large.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-11-03:/449039</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-11/niom-bac110317.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Brain's alertness circuitry conserved through evolution</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(NIH/National Institute of Mental Health) Using a molecular method likely to become widely adopted b...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>NIH/National Institute of Mental Health</i>) Using a molecular method likely to become widely adopted by the field, researchers have discovered brain circuitry essential for alertness, or vigilance -- and for brain states more generally. Strikingly, the same cell types and circuits are engaged during alertness in zebra fish and mice, species whose evolutionary forebears parted ways hundreds of millions of years ago. This suggests that the human brain is likely similarly wired for this state critical to survival.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-11-03T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-11-03T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Chemistry, Physics and Materials Sciences</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-11-02:/448548</id>
	<link href="https://futurism.com/we-just-completed-a-record-breaking-test-of-a-revolutionary-ion-engine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">We Just Completed a Record-Breaking Test of a Revolutionary Ion Engine</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>X3 Hall-effect
When it comes to the future of space exploration, a number of new technologies are be...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>X3 Hall-effect</h2>
<p>When it comes to the future of space exploration, a number of new technologies are being investigated. Foremost among these are new forms of propulsion that will be able to balance fuel-efficiency with power. Not only would engines that are capable of achieving a great deal of thrust using less fuel be cost-effective, they will be able to ferry astronauts to destinations like Mars and beyond in less time.</p>
<p>This is where engines like the X3 Hall-effect thruster comes into play. This thruster, which is being developed by NASA&rsquo;s Glenn Research Center in conjunction with the US Air Force and the University of Michigan, is a scaled-up model of the kinds of thrusters used by the&nbsp;<a href="https://dawn.jpl.nasa.gov/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>Dawn</em>&nbsp;spacecraft</a>. During a&nbsp;<a href="http://ns.umich.edu/new/releases/25192-thruster-for-mars-mission-breaks-records" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">recent test</a>, this thruster shattered the previous record for a Hall-effect thruster, achieving higher power and superior thrust.</p>
<p>Hall-effect thrusters have garnered favor with mission planners in recent years because of their extreme efficiency. They function by turning small amounts of propellant (usually inert gases like xenon) into charged plasma with electrical fields, which is then accelerated very quickly using a magnetic field. Compared to chemical rockets, they can achieve top speeds using a tiny fraction of their fuel.</p>
<p>However, a major challenge so far has been building a Hall-effect thruster that is capable of achieving high levels of thrust as well. While fuel efficient, conventional ion engines typically produce only a fraction of the thrust produced by rockets that rely on solid-chemical propellants. Hence why NASA has been developing the scaled-up model X3 thruster in conjunction with its partners.</p>
<p>The development of the thruster has been overseen by Alec Gallimore, a professor of aerospace engineering and the Robert J. Vlasic Dean of Engineering at the University of Michigan. As he indicated in a recent Michigan News&nbsp;<a href="http://ns.umich.edu/new/releases/25192-thruster-for-mars-mission-breaks-records" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">press statement</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>&ldquo;Mars missions are just on the horizon, and we already know that Hall thrusters work well in space. They can be optimized either for carrying equipment with minimal energy and propellant over the course of a year or so, or for speed&mdash;carrying the crew to Mars much more quickly.&rdquo;</em></p></blockquote>
<h2>New Records</h2>
<p>In recent tests, the X3 shattered the previous thrust record set by a Hall thruster, achieving 5.4 newtons of force compared with the old record of 3.3 newtons. The X3 also more than doubled the operating current (250 amperes vs. 112 amperes) and ran at a slightly higher power than the previous record-holder (102 kilowatts vs. 98 kilowatts). This was encouraging news, since it means that the engine can offer faster acceleration, which means shorter travel times.</p>
<p>The test was carried about by Scott Hall and Hani Kamhawi at the NASA Glenn Research Center in Cleveland. Whereas Hall is a doctoral student in aerospace engineering at U-M, Kamhawi is NASA Glenn research scientist who has been heavily involved in the development of the X3. In addition, Kamhawi is also Hall&rsquo;s NASA mentor, as part of the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nasa.gov/directorates/spacetech/strg/archives_nstrf.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">NASA Space Technology Research Fellowship</a>&nbsp;(NSTRF).</p>
<figure><img src="https://futurism.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Dawn-Ion-engine-NASA-JPL-600x338.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="338"><figcaption>Artist&rsquo;s concept of Dawn mission using its blue ion engine to reach Ceres in the distance. Credit: NASA/JPL</figcaption></figure>
<p>This test was the culmination of more than five years of research which sought to improve upon current Hall-effect designs. To conduct the test, the team relied on NASA Glenn&rsquo;s vacuum chamber, which is currently the only chamber in the US that can handle the X3 thruster. This is due to the sheer amount of exhaust the thruster produces, which can result in ionized xenon drifting back into the plasma plume, thus skewing the test results.</p>
<p>NASA Glenn&rsquo;s setup is the only one with a vacuum pump powerful enough to create the conditions necessary to keep the exhaust clean. Hall and Kamhawi also had to build a custom thrust stand to support the X3&rsquo;s 227 kg (500 pound) frame and withstand the force it generates, since existing stands were not up to the task. After securing a test window, the team spent four weeks prepping the stand, the thruster, and setting up all the necessary connections.</p>
<figure><img src="https://futurism.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/thruster-for-mars-mission-breaks-records-thruster-orig-20171023-1024x683-600x400.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="400"><figcaption>Scott Hall makes some final adjustments on the thruster before the test begins. Credit: NASA</figcaption></figure>
<p>All the while, NASA researchers, engineers and technicians were on hand to provide support. After 20 hours of pumping to achieve a space-like vacuum inside the chamber, Hall and Kamhawi conducted a series of tests where the engine would be fired for 12-hours straight. Over the course of 25 days, the team brought the X3 up to its record-breaking power, current and thrust levels.</p>
<h2>Future Testing</h2>
<p>Looking ahead, the team plans to conduct more tests in Gallimore&rsquo;s lab at U-M using an upgraded vacuum chamber. These upgrades will are schedules to be completed by January of 2018, and will enable the team to conduct future tests in-house. This upgrade was made possible thanks to a $1 million USD grant, contributed in part by the Air Force Office of Scientific Research, with additional support provided by the Jet Propulsion Laboratory and U-M.</p>
<figure><img src="https://futurism.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/thruster-for-mars-mission-breaks-records-firing-orig-20171023-e1509127871136-1024x607-600x356.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="356"><figcaption>A side shot of the X3 firing at 50 kilowatts. Credit: NASA</figcaption></figure>
<p>The X3&rsquo;s power supplies are also being developed by&nbsp;<a href="http://www.rocket.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Aerojet Rocketdyne</a>, the Sacramento-based rocket and missile propulsion manufacturer that is also the lead on the propulsion system grant from NASA. By Spring of 2018, the engine is expected to be integrated with these power systems; at which point, a series of 100-hour tests that will once again be conducted at the Glenn Research Center.</p>
<p>The X3 is one of three prototypes that NASA is investigating for future crewed missions to Mars, all of which are intended to reduce travel times and reduce the amount of fuel needed. Beyond making such missions more cost-effective, the reduced transit times are also intended to reduce the amount of radiation astronauts will be exposed to as they travel between Earth and Mars.</p>
<p>The project is funded through NASA&rsquo;s&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nasa.gov/nextstep" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Next Space Technologies for Exploration Partnership</a>&nbsp;(Next-STEP), which supports not just propulsion systems but also habitat systems and in-space manufacturing.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com/we-just-completed-a-record-breaking-test-of-a-revolutionary-ion-engine/" target="_blank">We Just Completed a Record-Breaking Test of a Revolutionary Ion Engine</a> appeared first on <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com" target="_blank">Futurism</a>.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-11-02T21:09:37+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Universe Today</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://futurism.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://futurism.com"/>
		<updated>2017-11-02T21:09:37+00:00</updated>
		<title>Futurism</title></source>

	<category term="robots &amp; machines"/>

	<category term="hall-effect thrusters"/>

	<category term="nasa"/>

	<category term="rockets"/>

	<category term="sci-fi visions"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-11-02:/448526</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-11/uot-aca103017.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Are cities affecting evolution?</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(University of Toronto) In the first study to take a comprehensive look at the way urbanization is a...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>University of Toronto</i>) In the first study to take a comprehensive look at the way urbanization is affecting evolution, Professors Marc Johnson and Jason Munshi-Smith say they've found a 'wake-up call for the public, governments and other scientists.'</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-11-02T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-11-02T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Atmospheric Science</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-11-01:/447930</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-11/uop-lpa103017.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Luck plays a role in how language evolves, Penn team finds</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(University of Pennsylvania) Read a few lines of Chaucer or Shakespeare and you'll get a sense of ho...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>University of Pennsylvania</i>) Read a few lines of Chaucer or Shakespeare and you'll get a sense of how the English language has changed during the past millennium. Examining collections of annotated texts dating from the 12th to the 21st centuries, researchers found that certain linguistic changes were guided by pressures analogous to natural selection -- social, cognitive and other factors -- while others seem to have occurred purely by happenstance.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-11-01T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-11-01T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Earth Science</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-11-01:/447757</id>
	<link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2017/11/171101092019.htm" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Revolutionizing nuclear waste reprocessing and saving money</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Seeking a better way to capture radioactive iodides in spent nuclear reactor fuel, scientists have d...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Seeking a better way to capture radioactive iodides in spent nuclear reactor fuel, scientists have developed an extremely efficient 'molecular trap' that can be recycled and reused.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-11-01T13:20:19+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/"/>
		<updated>2017-11-01T13:20:19+00:00</updated>
		<title>Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily</title></source>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/2017/11/171101092019-large.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-11-15:/454336</id>
	<link href="https://futurism.com/first-time-scientists-used-gene-editing-inside-living-patient/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">For the First Time, Scientists Used Gene Editing Inside a Living Patient</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cut and Paste
For the first time, doctors have edited the genome of a living human patient. A 44-yea...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Cut and Paste</h2>
<p>For the first time, doctors have <a href="http://www.the-scientist.com/?articles.view/articleNo/50957/title/Man-Receives-First-In-Vivo-Gene-Editing-Therapy/&amp;utm_content=63169272&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=facebook/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">edited the genome</a> of a living human patient. A 44-year-old man received the treatment at a hospital in Oakland, California on November 13.</p>
<p>The patient suffers from Hunter syndrome, a rare genetic condition which leaves the sufferer without an enzyme that&rsquo;s used to break down complex polysaccharides, a carbohydrate. Left untreated, it can <a href="https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/hunter-syndrome/symptoms-causes/syc-20350706" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">cause permanent damage</a> to mental development, organ function and physical abilities. In this case, doctors have attempted to correct the condition by using zinc finger nucleuses (ZFNs). These enzymes cut a gene that&rsquo;s present in liver cells, inserting a functional copy of the gene that produces the desired enzyme.</p>
<p></p>
<p>The treatment was <a href="https://futurism.com/genome-editing-used-first-attempt-treat-hemophilia/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">developed by Sangamo Therapeutics</a>, a biotechnology firm based in California. &ldquo;This is the first time someone could have a new gene put into their liver,&rdquo; said the company&rsquo;s president and CEO, Sandy Macrae, in an interview with <i>The Scientist</i>. He described performing the trial as &ldquo;a privilege and a responsibility.&rdquo;</p>
<p>ZFNs are a more unwieldy method of <a href="https://futurism.com/hiv-can-mutate-evade-attempts-modify-crispr-gene-editing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">performing gene editing</a> than CRISPR Cas-9, but they do offer more precision. The implementation utilized by Sangamo reportedly offers the ability to cut at any base that might be required.</p>
<h2>Gene Genie</h2>
<p>A successful trial like this demonstrates how far we&rsquo;ve come in terms of being able to <a href="https://futurism.com/images/how-crispr-works-the-future-of-genetic-engineering/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">make edits to the human genome</a>. Between CRISPR and ZFNs, we have developed powerful tools that allow us to make precise modifications &ndash; and that will allow us to treat a wide variety of different conditions.</p>
<p>This procedure is part of a larger trial being carried out by Sangamo, which will also consist of experimental treatments for people suffering from hemophilia B and Hurler syndrome, as well as Hunter syndrome. All three diseases are caused by absent or non-functional genes, which can now be inserted thanks to these cutting-edge techniques.</p>
<p>The use of ZFNs to treat Hunter syndrome offers up a huge improvement over the way the disease is addressed at present. The current method typically involves weekly infusions of <a href="https://explorist.futurism.com/biologic-drugs-transforming-medicine/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">enzyme replacement therapy</a>. While this has proven to be effective, since the patient isn&rsquo;t actually producing the enzymes, it&rsquo;s an ongoing treatment that consumes a lot of time and money. <figure><a href="https://futurism.com/images/how-crispr-works-the-future-of-genetic-engineering/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><img src="https://futurism.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/Crispr-Cas-9.jpg" alt="How CRISPR Works: The Future of Genetic Engineering and Designer Humans"></a><figcaption><strong><a href="https://futurism.com/images/how-crispr-works-the-future-of-genetic-engineering/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Click to View Full Infographic</a></strong></figcaption></figure>
</p><p>Conversely, ZFNs make lasting changes to the human body that remove the problem entirely. It&rsquo;s easy to see how this technique could have a huge impact on the patient&rsquo;s quality of life &ndash; it&rsquo;s a matter of nipping the issue in the bud, rather than addressing it continually.&nbsp;The next step will be to figure out how this technique might be used to treat other conditions.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com/first-time-scientists-used-gene-editing-inside-living-patient/" target="_blank">For the First Time, Scientists Used Gene Editing Inside a Living Patient</a> appeared first on <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com" target="_blank">Futurism</a>.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-11-15T18:22:19+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Brad Jones</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://futurism.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://futurism.com"/>
		<updated>2017-11-15T18:22:19+00:00</updated>
		<title>Futurism</title></source>

	<category term="health &amp; medicine"/>

	<category term="hunter syndrome"/>

	<category term="sangamo therapeutics"/>

	<category term="zfns"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-11-14:/453601</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-11/fau-brh111317.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Bioengineered robotic hand with its own nervous system will sense touch</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Florida Atlantic University) Researchers are developing a first-of-its-kind bioengineered robotic h...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>Florida Atlantic University</i>) Researchers are developing a first-of-its-kind bioengineered robotic hand that will actually feel and adapt to its environment. This 'living' robot will have its own peripheral nervous system directly linking robotic sensors and actuators.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-11-14T05:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-11-14T05:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Technology, Engineering and Computer Science</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-11-13:/453059</id>
	<link href="http://news.mit.edu/2017/crispr-carrying-nanoparticles-edit-genome-1113" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">CRISPR-carrying nanoparticles edit the genome</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a new study, MIT researchers have developed nanoparticles that can deliver the CRISPR genome-edit...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a new study, MIT researchers have developed nanoparticles that can deliver the CRISPR genome-editing system and specifically modify genes in mice. The team used nanoparticles to carry the CRISPR components, eliminating the need to use viruses for delivery.</p>



<p>Using the new delivery technique, the researchers were able to cut out certain genes in about 80 percent of liver cells, the best success rate ever achieved with CRISPR in adult animals.</p>



<p>&ldquo;What&rsquo;s really exciting here is that we&rsquo;ve shown you can make a nanoparticle that can be used to permanently and specifically edit the DNA in the liver of an adult animal,&rdquo; says Daniel Anderson, an associate professor in MIT&rsquo;s Department of Chemical Engineering and a member of MIT&rsquo;s Koch Institute for Integrative Cancer Research and Institute for Medical Engineering and Science (IMES).</p>



<p>One of the genes targeted in this study, known as Pcsk9, regulates cholesterol levels. Mutations in the human version of the gene are associated with a rare disorder called dominant familial hypercholesterolemia, and the FDA recently approved two antibody drugs that inhibit Pcsk9. However these antibodies need to be taken regularly, and for the rest of the patient&rsquo;s life, to provide therapy. The new nanoparticles permanently edit the gene following a single treatment, and the technique also offers promise for treating other liver disorders, according to the MIT team.</p>



<p>Anderson is the senior author of the study, which appears in the Nov. 13 issue of <em>Nature Biotechnology</em>. The paper&rsquo;s lead author is Koch Institute research scientist Hao Yin. Other authors include David H. Koch Institute Professor Robert Langer of MIT, professors Victor Koteliansky and Timofei Zatsepin of the Skolkovo Institute of Science and Technology, and Professor Wen Xue of the University of Massachusetts Medical School.</p>



<p><strong>Targeting disease</strong></p>



<p>Many scientists are trying to develop safe and efficient ways to deliver the components needed for CRISPR, which consists of a DNA-cutting enzyme called Cas9 and a short RNA that guides the enzyme to a specific area of the genome, directing Cas9 where to make its cut.</p>



<p>In most cases, researchers rely on viruses to carry the gene for Cas9, as well as the RNA guide strand. In 2014, Anderson, Yin, and their colleagues developed a nonviral delivery system in the first-ever demonstration of curing a disease (the liver disorder tyrosinemia) with CRISPR in an adult animal. However, this type of delivery requires a high-pressure injection, a method that can also cause some damage to the liver.</p>



<p>Later, the researchers showed they could deliver the components without the high-pressure injection by packaging messenger RNA (mRNA) encoding Cas9 into a nanoparticle instead of a virus. Using this approach, in which the guide RNA was still delivered by a virus, the researchers were able to edit the target gene in about 6 percent of hepatocytes, which is enough to treat tyrosinemia.</p>



<p>While that delivery technique holds promise, in some situations it would be better to have a completely nonviral delivery system, Anderson says. One consideration is that once a particular virus is used, the patient will develop antibodies to it, so it couldn&rsquo;t be used again. Also, some patients have pre-existing antibodies to the viruses being tested as CRISPR delivery vehicles.</p>



<p>In the new <em>Nature Biotechnology</em> paper, the researchers came up with a system that delivers both Cas9 and the RNA guide using nanoparticles, with no need for viruses. To deliver the guide RNAs, they first had to chemically modify the RNA to protect it from enzymes in the body that would normally break it down before it could reach its destination.</p>



<p>The researchers analyzed the structure of the complex formed by Cas9 and the RNA guide, or sgRNA, to figure out which sections of the guide RNA strand could be chemically modified without interfering with the binding of the two molecules. Based on this analysis, they created and tested many possible combinations of modifications.</p>



<p>&ldquo;We used the structure of the Cas9 and sgRNA complex as a guide and did tests to figure out we can modify as much as 70 percent of the guide RNA,&rdquo; Yin says. &ldquo;We could heavily modify it and not affect the binding of sgRNA and Cas9, and this enhanced modification really enhances activity.&rdquo;</p>



<p><strong>Reprogramming the liver</strong></p>



<p>The researchers packaged these modified RNA guides (which they call enhanced sgRNA) into lipid nanoparticles, which they had previously used to deliver other types of RNA to the liver, and injected them into mice along with nanoparticles containing mRNA that encodes Cas9.</p>



<p>They experimented with knocking out a few different genes expressed by hepatocytes, but focused most of their attention on the cholesterol-regulating Pcsk9 gene. The researchers were able to eliminate this gene in more than 80 percent of liver cells, and the Pcsk9 protein was undetectable in these mice. They also found a 35 percent drop in the total cholesterol levels of the treated mice.</p>



<p>The researchers are now working on identifying other liver diseases that might benefit from this approach, and advancing these approaches toward use in patients.</p>



<p>&ldquo;I think having a fully synthetic nanoparticle that can specifically turn genes off could be a powerful tool not just for Pcsk9 but for other diseases as well,&rdquo; Anderson says. &ldquo;The liver is a really important organ and also is a source of disease for many people. If you can reprogram the DNA of your liver while you&rsquo;re still using it, we think there are many diseases that could be addressed.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;We are very excited to see this new application of nanotechnology open new avenues for gene editing,&rdquo; Langer adds.</p>



<p>The research was funded by the National Institutes of Health (NIH), the Russian Scientific Fund, the Skoltech Center, and the Koch Institute Support (core) Grant from the National Cancer Institute.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-11-13T15:59:59+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Anne Trafton | MIT News Office</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://news.mit.edu/mitresearch-rss.xml</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://news.mit.edu/mitresearch-rss.xml"/>
		<updated>2017-11-13T15:59:59+00:00</updated>
		<title>MIT Research News</title></source>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image" 
		length="1"
		href="http://news.mit.edu/sites/mit.edu.newsoffice/files/styles/article_cover_image_original/public/images/2017/MIT-Nonviral-CRISPR.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-11-09:/451640</id>
	<link href="https://futurism.com/epa-approved-release-mosquito-killing-insects-grown-lab/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">The EPA Just Approved the Release of Mosquito-Killing Insects Grown in the Lab</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mosquito-Killing Mosquitoes
For more than 4,000 years, humans have battled mosquito-borne diseases, ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Mosquito-Killing Mosquitoes</h2>
<p>For more than <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/malaria/about/history/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">4,000 years</a>, humans have battled mosquito-borne diseases, and now, the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) has approved a line of lab-grown mosquitoes designed to reduce the number of these illness-causing insects.</p>
<p>If you get an itchy bite over the summer, it&rsquo;s most probably from a member of the species Aedes albopictus, otherwise known as the Asian tiger mosquito. On November 3, the EPA approved the release of male Asian tiger mosquitoes infected with a bacterium that prevents them from successfully reproducing.</p>
<p>Kentucky-based biotech company <a href="http://mosquitomate.com/?v=3.0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MosquitoMate</a> infected the lab-grown male mosquitoes with <a href="https://www.epa.gov/pesticides/epa-grants-extension-experimental-use-permit-wolbachia-mosquito" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wolbachia pipientis</a>, a naturally occurring bacteria found in many insects. This bacteria cannot be transmitted to mammals, and eggs fertilized by infected males will not hatch. In the wild, Wolbachia protects individual <a href="https://qz.com/676813/in-a-world-first-scientists-have-found-a-way-to-use-bacteria-to-fight-the-zika-virus/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">mosquitoes from viruses</a>, but male mosquitoes do not bite humans regardless.</p>
<p></p>
<p>MosquitoMate has EPA permission to sell the lab-grown mosquitoes to municipal bodies and individuals in 20 states. <a href="https://qz.com/1123456/the-epa-has-approved-the-release-of-weaponized-mosquitoes-in-20-us-states/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Quartz reports that</a> the approved states are those with weather similar to that of Kentucky, New York, and California, where MosquitoMate tested the bugs&rsquo; effectiveness. The mosquitoes have also been officially registered as a biopesticide.</p>
<h2>Fighting Disease</h2>
<p>On their website, <a href="http://mosquitomate.com/how-it-works/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MosquitoMate claims</a> that the release of their modified males reduces biting mosquito populations by 80 percent, and currently, they market their line of lab-grown mosquitoes as a method of pest control, helping towns and their citizens see fewer itchy bites in the warm months.</p>
<p>However, mosquitoes of the Aedes genus carry diseases like Zika, dengue, yellow fever, and Chikungunya. The most common vector of those diseases is the species Aedes aegypti, which is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aedes_aegypti#/media/File:Global_Aedes_aegypti_distribution_(e08347).png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">relatively uncommon in the U.S.</a>, but a scourge in tropical climates around the world. Wolbachia does not naturally occur in this particular species.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.nature.com/news/us-government-approves-killer-mosquitoes-to-fight-disease-1.22959?WT.mc_id=TWT_NatureNews&amp;sf148235237=1" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Nature reports that</a> MosquitoMate has tested Wolbachia-infected A. aegypti mosquitoes <a href="http://keysmosquito.org/2017/04/18/fkmcd-releases-wolbachia-mosquitoes-on-stock-island/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">in the Florida keys</a> and in Fresno, Calfornia. If the bacteria shows the same effectiveness in this species, the company&rsquo;s mosquitoes could be a tiny, flying weapon in our battle against some of the <a href="https://www.wired.com/2016/06/zika-mosquitos/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">deadliest diseases on the planet</a>.</p>
<figure><a href="https://futurism.com/images/in-the-footsteps-of-zika-the-next-critter-borne-viruses-infographic/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><img src="https://futurism.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/In-the-Footsteps-of-Zika_home_-v1.jpg" alt="In the Footsteps of Zika: The Next Critter-Borne Viruses [INFOGRAPHIC]"></a><figcaption><strong><a href="https://futurism.com/images/in-the-footsteps-of-zika-the-next-critter-borne-viruses-infographic/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Click to View Full Infographic</a></strong></figcaption></figure>
<p>Notably, MosquitoMate&rsquo;s lab-grown mosquitoes are not genetically engineered &mdash; they&rsquo;re infected with the Wolbachia bacterium after birth &mdash; but others are using genetic engineering to try to solve the world&rsquo;s mosquito problem.</p>
<p>Bill Gates has invested millions toward <a href="https://futurism.com/bill-gates-doubles-down-on-eradicating-mosquitoes-with-genetic-engineering/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">eradicating malaria</a> through genetically modified mosquitoes, while researchers from Johns Hopkins University are working on ones that <a href="https://futurism.com/gene-editing-could-end-mosquito-borne-disease/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">resist the dengue fever virus.</a></p>
<p>In Brazil, U.K.-based company Oxitec has been <a href="https://futurism.com/factory-made-mosquitoes-can-reduce-disease-transmitting-populations-by-90/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">testing a group</a> of A. aegypti that have been genetically modified to contain a gene that kills their progeny. When the company attempted <a href="https://futurism.com/fda-approved-genetically-modified-mosquitoes-will-combat-zika-virus/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">to trial their mosquitoes in Florida</a>, however, one community voted to prevent their release, though the rest of their county was in favor.</p>
<figure><img src="https://futurism.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Aedes_aegypti_CDC-Gathany-2.jpg" alt="An Aedes aegypti mosquito. (Image credit: US Center for Disease Control)" width="700" height="380"><figcaption>An <i>Aedes aegypti </i>mosquito. Image credit: U.S. Center for Disease Control</figcaption></figure>
<p>Despite reassurances that genetic engineering is safe, <a href="https://futurism.com/genetic-engineering-a-primer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">fears of this technique clearly remain.</a> Additionally, some are <a href="https://futurism.com/scientists-could-eradicate-malaria-by-altering-mosquitoes-dna-but-should-they/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">worried about the potential ecological consequences</a> of messing with the spread of these biting insects.</p>
<p>However, with mosquitoes causing an estimated <a href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/mosquitoes-kill-more-humans-human-murderers-do-180951272/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">725,000 deaths per year</a>, such experiments can be worth consideration so long as they are conducted smartly.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com/epa-approved-release-mosquito-killing-insects-grown-lab/" target="_blank">The EPA Just Approved the Release of Mosquito-Killing Insects Grown in the Lab</a> appeared first on <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com" target="_blank">Futurism</a>.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-11-09T19:06:07+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Claudia Geib</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://futurism.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://futurism.com"/>
		<updated>2017-11-09T19:06:07+00:00</updated>
		<title>Futurism</title></source>

	<category term="health &amp; medicine"/>

	<category term="epa"/>

	<category term="gmo"/>

	<category term="mosquito"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-11-19:/455931</id>
	<link href="https://futurism.com/insects-flying-declined-75-percent/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">27-Year Study Finds the Amount of Insects Flying in the Air Has Declined 75 Percent</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Bug&nbsp;researchers in Germany are puzzled.
New data suggests&nbsp;the total population of flying insects the...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Bug&nbsp;researchers in Germany are puzzled.</p>
<p>New data suggests&nbsp;the total population of flying insects there has declined a whopping 75% in the past 27 years. And no one knows why.</p>
<p>A study released Wednesday in the journal&nbsp;<a href="http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#sec002" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">PLOS ONE</a>&nbsp;details a longitudinal study by German researchers to measure &ldquo;flying insect biomass&rdquo; &mdash; the weight of all flying bugs&nbsp;&mdash; in 63 protected spots around the country.</p>
<p>The&nbsp;scientists surveyed places like dunes, grasslands, and forests, using&nbsp;trapping tents to collect over 118 pounds of bugs over the 27 year period. They were expecting to find some&nbsp;population decreases, but this extreme decline, they said, is &ldquo;alarming&rdquo;.</p>
<p>The most recent&nbsp;<a href="http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0169156" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Living Planet Index</a>&nbsp;(which measures biodiversity and population&nbsp;trends&nbsp;in fish, amphibians, reptiles, birds and mammals around the world) suggested that wildlife abundance on&nbsp;Earth decreased by as much as 58%&nbsp;between&nbsp;1970&nbsp;and 2012.&nbsp;<a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007%2Fs10841-017-9972-4" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Butterfly</a>, bee, and moth populations have&nbsp;previously been shown to be in decline&nbsp;across Europe.</p>
<p>But this widespread insect death&nbsp;struck the researchers as extreme.&nbsp;At the peak of summer heat, when there are usually more bugs out than in the spring and fall,&nbsp;the&nbsp;drop&nbsp;was even&nbsp;more pronounced, and bug counts were down 82%,&nbsp;&mdash; that&rsquo;s 7% more than the average&nbsp;decline over the 27-year period.</p>
<p>The lack of insects, of course, also&nbsp;problematic for small critters who eat flying bugs and has ripple effects up the food chain. A majority (roughly 80%) of plants rely on insects for pollination, and birds gobble them for sustenance.&nbsp; German birds are feeling the squeeze on their food supply&nbsp;&mdash;&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nabu.de/news/2017/10/23284.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">new research</a>&nbsp;published Thursday shows that Germany&nbsp;lost 15% of its non-endangered bird population in the past 12 years.</p>
<p>The researchers aren&rsquo;t sure what&rsquo;s causing this precipitous fall. Across the diverse&nbsp;swath of German habitats studied, all spots saw similar declines, suggesting the decrease had nothing to do with landscape changes.&nbsp;And the scientists don&rsquo;t think&nbsp;shifts&nbsp;in weather, land use, or climate change are valid explanations either. If anything,&nbsp;rising global temperatures should increase bug populations, the authors argue, because insect biomass is &ldquo;positively related&rdquo; to temperature, according to their models.</p>
<p>Other experts&nbsp;have pointed out, however, that not all bugs thrive on a warming Earth.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national/health-science/a-bugged-life-warm-winter-could-mean-more-insects/2012/03/07/gIQA5b033R_story.html?utm_term=.45b99b20780a" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">The Washington Post</a>&nbsp;reports that an especially warm spring&nbsp;could bring some bugs (like bees) out early,&nbsp;only to&nbsp;starve when there&rsquo;s not enough food.</p>
<p>But the German researchers are zeroing in on one possible explanation&nbsp;for their findings:&nbsp;&ldquo;Pesticide usage, year-round tillage, increased use of fertilizers and frequency of agronomic measures&hellip; may form a plausible cause,&rdquo; they&nbsp;wrote.</p>
<p>More research is needed to know the role the agricultural industry is playing, but the German Farmer&rsquo;s Union is already&nbsp;playing defense. The association&rsquo;s secretary general,&nbsp;Bernhard Kr&uuml;sken, told&nbsp;<a href="http://www.dw.com/en/insect-and-bird-populations-declining-dramatically-in-germany/a-41030897" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Deutsche Welle</a>&nbsp;that &ldquo;considering that the insect count was done exclusively in protected habitats, this shows that it would be premature to quickly point at agriculture.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Regardless of the cause, scientists worldwide have been sounding the alarm&nbsp;about declining insect populations for months.</p>
<p>&ldquo;If you&rsquo;re an insect-eating bird living in that area, four-fifths of your food is gone in the last quarter-century, which is staggering,&rdquo; Dave Goulson, an ecologist at the University of Sussex, told&nbsp;<a href="http://www.sciencemag.org/news/2017/05/where-have-all-insects-gone" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Science Magazine</a>&nbsp;earlier this year. &ldquo;One almost hopes&rdquo; the German trend is&nbsp;unique, he said, and not reverberating around the globe.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com/insects-flying-declined-75-percent/" target="_blank">27-Year Study Finds the Amount of Insects Flying in the Air Has Declined 75 Percent</a> appeared first on <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com" target="_blank">Futurism</a>.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-11-19T13:00:23+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Business Insider</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://futurism.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://futurism.com"/>
		<updated>2017-11-19T13:00:23+00:00</updated>
		<title>Futurism</title></source>

	<category term="sci-fi visions"/>

	<category term="bugs"/>

	<category term="environment"/>

	<category term="extinction"/>

	<category term="insects"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-25:/444931</id>
	<link href="https://futurism.com/we-are-officially-sending-a-habitat-to-orbit-the-moon/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">We Are Officially Sending a Habitat to Orbit the Moon</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Establishing a Lunar Habitat
Now that the United States is officially getting back into space explor...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Establishing a Lunar Habitat</h2>
<p>Now that the United States is officially getting back into space exploration, the Moon now seems to be the focus &mdash; or at least the starting point &mdash; of a lot of plans involving space travel. The Trump administration <a href="https://futurism.com/the-u-s-officially-says-they-are-sending-humans-to-the-moon/?src=featured" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">has redirected NASA&rsquo;s priorities</a> to settling on our lunar neighbor before Mars, and SpaceX CEO Elon Musk has said the<a href="https://futurism.com/elon-musk-is-officially-sending-humans-to-mars-in-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">&nbsp;BFR project</a> will be a key factor in creating a lunar base.</p>
<p>To continue the trend, Bigelow Aerospace and the United Launch Alliance (ULA) announced last week they would be collaborating to design an inflatable habitat. The habitat would be launched into space by the end of 2022, and eventually function as a lunar depot. <a href="http://bigelowaerospace.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bigelow Aerospace</a> is designing two B330 expandable modules, while ULA is providing the Vulcan 562 configuration rocket that will carry the module into low Earth orbit. A single B330 is roughly one-third the volume of the International Space Station.</p>
<p></p>
<p>After the Vulcan rocket brings the B330 into low Earth orbit, it will inflate, and Bigelow will outfit it with additional equipment and put it through a series of tests. Once it&rsquo;s fully up and running, additional launches will be carried out to provide 35 tons of cryogenic propellant to the module. It will then be maneuvered into its final location: low lunar orbit.</p>
<p>&ldquo;We are excited to work with ULA on this lunar depot project,&rdquo; said Bigelow Aerospace president Robert Bigelow in a statement. &ldquo;Our lunar depot plan is a strong complement to other plans intended to eventually put people on Mars. It will provide NASA and America with an exciting and financially practical success opportunity that can be accomplished in the short term. This lunar depot could be deployed easily by 2022 to support the nation&rsquo;s re-energized plans for returning to the Moon.&rdquo;</p>
<h2>Other Countries Heading to the Moon</h2>
<p>The United States isn&rsquo;t the only country that has plans for the moon. Russia and China are set to sign <a href="https://futurism.com/russia-and-china-to-sign-a-multi-year-space-exploration-deal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a multi-year space exploration deal</a> that covers lunar and deep space exploration, and Russia is <a href="https://futurism.com/russia-confirms-participation-in-nasas-deep-space-gateway-project/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">working with NASA on the Deep Space Gateway project</a> to build a lunar space station.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, the China National Space Administration (CNSA) and the European Space Agency (ESA) expressed a desire <a href="https://futurism.com/china-and-europe-may-build-a-moon-village-in-the-2020s/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">to work together on an international lunar base</a>, or a &ldquo;moon village,&rdquo; by 2020.</p>
<p></p>
<p>&ldquo;The Chinese have a very ambitious moon program already in place,&rdquo; said Pal A. Hvistendahl, ESA&rsquo;s head of media relations, at the time. &ldquo;Space has changed since the space race of the &rsquo;60s. We recognize that to explore space for peaceful purposes, we do [need] international cooperation.&rdquo;</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s been quite some time since humanity saw the Moon as a worthwhile place to venture to. Regardless of who manages to do it first, it&rsquo;s an exciting time for space travel.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com/we-are-officially-sending-a-habitat-to-orbit-the-moon/" target="_blank">We Are Officially Sending a Habitat to Orbit the Moon</a> appeared first on <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com" target="_blank">Futurism</a>.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-25T21:51:09+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Kyree Leary</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://futurism.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://futurism.com"/>
		<updated>2017-10-25T21:51:09+00:00</updated>
		<title>Futurism</title></source>

	<category term="off world"/>

	<category term="lunar habitat"/>

	<category term="moon"/>

	<category term="space"/>

	<category term="space exploration"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-11-03:/448989</id>
	<link href="https://inhabitat.com/you-can-now-explore-all-19-of-south-africas-national-parks-on-google-maps" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">You can now explore all 19 of South Africa's National Parks on Google Maps</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever wanted to walk in the footsteps of Nelson Mandela, track cheetahs on foot, or stroll ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img fl:hint-main-image="true" src="https://inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/11/Explore-South-Africas-National-Parks-with-Google-Maps-1-889x406.jpg" alt="Google Maps, South Africa, National Parks, Nature Reserves, Conservation, Exploration, Hiking, Nature, Outdoors, "></p>
<p>Have you ever wanted to <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/@-29.4681918,30.1703826,2a,75y,228.21h,95.64t/data=!3m6!1e1!3m4!1sizWlQwYx7n4Zl8MLaEFvUw!2e0!7i13312!8i6656" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">walk in the footsteps of Nelson Mandela</a>, <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/@-32.102144,25.4173855,3a,23.8y,139.73h,110.13t/data=!3m6!1e1!3m4!1suSAzqx67c2rI4AtkKJdRQg!2e0!7i13312!8i6656" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">track cheetahs on foot</a>, or stroll with elephants &mdash; and other exotic creatures &mdash; in <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/South-Africa" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">South Africa</a>? Well, here&rsquo;s your chance. Thanks to the efforts of over 200 volunteers, now you can use <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/Google-Maps" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Google Maps</a> to explore 19 National Parks, 17 nature reserves, and many other sites of natural, cultural and historical significance in South Africa.</p>
<p></p>
<p>More than 200 nature-loving South Africans volunteered to map out parts of the country they call home. Many of the helpers were rangers and guides with <a href="https://www.sanparks.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">SANParks</a>, <a href="http://www.capenature.co.za/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">CapeNature</a> and <a href="http://www.kznwildlife.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">KZN Ezemvelo Wildlife</a>. Others were just good Samaritans, tech enthusiasts and avid <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/hiking" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">hikers</a> who want to make a difference. Over the span of twelve months, the volunteers trekked over 50,000km to establish 232 points of interest.</p>
<p><img src="https://inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/11/Explore-South-Africas-National-Parks-with-Google-Maps-1-889x406.jpg" alt="Google Maps, South Africa, National Parks, Nature Reserves, Conservation, Exploration, Hiking, Nature, Outdoors, "></p>
<p>Said Magdalena Filak, Program Manager for Google, &ldquo;The hundreds of volunteers who helped along the way proved to be truly passionate about showing the best of South Africa through their participation in the loan program.&rdquo; The <a href="https://www.google.com/streetview/loan/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Google Street View Camera Loan</a> program encourages anyone to borrow the 360-degree camera technology to help the <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/Earth" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">planet</a>. Reportedly, this is the first time Google has partnered with a third-party for the program.</p>
<p><img src="https://inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/11/Explore-South-Africas-National-Parks-with-Google-Maps-3-889x556.jpg" alt="Google Maps, South Africa, National Parks, Nature Reserves, Conservation, Exploration, Hiking, Nature, Outdoors, "></p>
<p><a href="https://www.drivesouthafrica.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Drive South Africa</a> played a big role in coordinating the <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/volunteering" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">volunteers</a>. Andre Van Kets, an outdoor enthusiast and the founder of the <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/Cape-Town" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Cape Town</a>-based company, explained the technology: &ldquo;The Trekker camera is a 22kg custom-made backpack fitted with 15 cameras pointing in all directions. The on-board technology plots the camera&rsquo;s exact location on the trail. While recording, the camera takes a 360-degree photo every two-seconds. It&rsquo;s basically the off-road equivalent of Google&rsquo;s Street View cars.&rdquo; Kets added that he saw &ldquo;potential in this technology to showcase South Africa to travellers around the globe&rdquo; when he applied.</p>
<p><a href="https://inhabitat.com/thousands-of-plastic-bottles-transformed-into-an-inspiring-tower-of-hope-in-south-africa/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Related: Thousands of plastic bottles transformed into an inspiring tower of hope in South Africa</a></p>
<p><img src="https://inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/11/Explore-South-Africas-National-Parks-with-Google-Maps-2-889x598.jpg" alt="Google Maps, South Africa, National Parks, Nature Reserves, Conservation, Exploration, Hiking, Nature, Outdoors, "></p>
<p>In addition to mapping over two hundred points of interest, volunteers mapped eight UNESCO World Heritage Sites. Users can also see <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/@-22.2138856,29.386949,3a,75y,68.02h,86.4t/data=!3m6!1e1!3m4!1sPXnvkba2tetLrlxAdnFjGQ!2e0!7i13312!8i6656" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Mapungubwe Hill</a>, which is home to an ancient African civilization, the <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/@-28.1337718,16.9107854,3a,75y,191.17h,89.73t/data=!3m6!1e1!3m4!1sVxjsP55XcPr4gZ2P226WOw!2e0!7i13312!8i6656" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Richtersveld</a> that is known for its incredible moonscapes, and <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/@-27.6689539,32.3168609,2a,75y,87.58h,72.84t/data=!3m9!1e1!3m7!1sTdz5axKc6LNslQd14tCIRQ!2e0!7i13312!8i6656!9m2!1b1!2i25" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">iSimangaliso Wetland Park</a>, South Africa&rsquo;s oldest UNESCO site which serves as a critical habitat for many <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/biodiversity" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">species</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/11/Explore-South-Africas-National-Parks-with-Google-Maps-5-889x556.jpg" alt="Google Maps, South Africa, National Parks, Nature Reserves, Conservation, Exploration, Hiking, Nature, Outdoors, "></p>
<p>The response has been overwhelmingly positive. Dennis Wood of Ezemvelo KZN Wildlife said, &ldquo;As the proud conservation authority for KwaZulu-Natal, Ezemvelo KZN Wildlife are excited to be partnered with Google&rsquo; new initiative in exposing our <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/national-parks" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">trails</a> on this global platform that we believe will engage our prospective guests to &ldquo;Take time to Discover&rdquo; our province&rsquo;s rich natural beauty and <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/conservation" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">conservation</a> wildlife heritage.&rdquo;</p>
<p><img src="https://inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/11/Explore-South-Africas-National-Parks-with-Google-Maps-6-889x556.jpg" alt="Google Maps, South Africa, National Parks, Nature Reserves, Conservation, Exploration, Hiking, Nature, Outdoors, "></p>
<p><big><a href="https://www.google.com/streetview/loan/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">+ Google Street View Loan Program</a></big></p>
<p><em>Images via <a href="https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipPq7zlSbKRPhmnlXg2i4AhmdC8oRtR6AMrtdXnx_yTOv9wKpwn38ahISxbW5hFa4A?key=RDRfRmVtZjcxTlBkNjc3TzlQUWcxUnZVM1JEWHpn" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Google Maps</a></em></p><div>
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Inhabitat?a=NDpVaH1_hpY:du8HjmNaIII:yIl2AUoC8zA" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Inhabitat?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Inhabitat?a=NDpVaH1_hpY:du8HjmNaIII:DLYy-l-dIDg" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Inhabitat?d=DLYy-l-dIDg" border="0"></a>
</div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-11-03T17:59:29+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Amanda Froelich</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://inhabitat.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://inhabitat.com"/>
		<updated>2017-11-03T17:59:29+00:00</updated>
		<title>Inhabitat - Sustainable Design Innovation, Eco Architecture, Green Building  green technology</title></source>

	<category term="south africa"/>

	<category term="conservation"/>

	<category term="green technology"/>

	<category term="innovation"/>

	<category term="earth"/>

	<category term="google"/>

	<category term="cape town"/>

	<category term="national parks"/>

	<category term="google maps"/>

	<category term="science"/>

	<category term="biodiversity"/>

	<category term="news"/>

	<category term="hiking"/>

	<category term="volunteering"/>

	<category term="things to do"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-11-06:/449608</id>
	<link href="https://www.cyberciti.biz/programming/improve-your-bashsh-shell-script-with-shellcheck-lint-script-analysis-tool/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Improve your bash/sh shell script with ShellCheck lint script analysis tool</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>ShellCheck is a static analysis tool for shell scripts. One can use it to finds bugs in your shell s...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><span>S</span>hellCheck is a static analysis tool for shell scripts. One can use it to finds bugs in your shell scripts. It is written in Haskell. You can find warnings and suggestions for bash/sh shell scripts with this tool. Let us see how to install and use ShellCheck on a Linux or Unix-like system to enhance your shell scripts, avoid errors and productivity.</div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-11-06T09:47:05+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Vivek Gite</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://feeds.cyberciti.biz/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.cyberciti.biz/"/>
		<updated>2017-11-06T09:47:05+00:00</updated>
		<title>nixCraft: Linux Tips, Hacks, Tutorials, And Ideas In Blog Format</title></source>

	<category term="command line hacks"/>

	<category term="howto"/>

	<category term="programming"/>

	<category term="debian linux"/>

	<category term="freebsd"/>

	<category term="linux"/>

	<category term="macos"/>

	<category term="os x"/>

	<category term="sysadmin"/>

	<category term="ubuntu"/>

	<category term="unix"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-31:/447154</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-10-lhc.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">LHC reaches 2017 targets ahead of schedule</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, CERN Control Centre operators announced good news, the Large Hadron Collider (LHC) has succes...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, CERN Control Centre operators announced good news, the Large Hadron Collider (LHC) has successfully met its production target for 2017, delivering more than 45 inverse femtobarns to the experiments.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-31T14:20:02+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-31T14:20:02+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="general physics"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/lhcreaches20.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-28:/445917</id>
	<link href="https://futurism.com/future-quantum-computer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Heres What a World Powered by Quantum Computers Will Look Like</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Beyond Science Fiction
In 1935, Albert Einstein famously collaborated with physicists Boris Podolsky...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Beyond Science Fiction</h2>
<p>In 1935, Albert Einstein famously collaborated with physicists Boris Podolsky and Nathan Rosen <sup></sup>on a paper designed to illuminate the weaknesses in quantum mechanics, a branch of physics focused on the very small. Though the phenomenon of &ldquo;entanglement&rdquo; was so new the term hadn&rsquo;t even been coined yet, Einstein wasted no time voicing his skepticism of it, calling the &ldquo;spooky action at a distance&rdquo; simply impossible.</p>
<p>Nearly a century later, we now have abundant proof that <a href="https://futurism.com/this-discovery-could-transform-our-understanding-of-the-cosmos/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">entanglement is possible</a>. In fact, we&rsquo;re now on the brink of building the quantum computers that will allow us to use the phenomenon to answer some of humanity&rsquo;s greatest questions.</p>
<p></p>
<p>Quantum computers handle and process information in a way far different from that of classical computers.</p>
<p>While a classical computer works with bits as information placeholders, a quantum computer works with quantum bits (qubits). While bits carry information in either a 0 or 1 state, qubits can be 0s and 1s <i>at the same time</i> thanks to quantum superposition.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, entanglement allows particles to be manipulated despite the distance between them &mdash; anything that happens to one particle will instantly be reflected in the other. Information can, therefore, be sent across greater distances far more quickly than with classical computers.</p>
<p></p>
<p>Although the field of quantum computing is still in its nascent stages and extremely complicated, researchers have made significant advances in recent years on the development of <a href="https://futurism.com/googles-quantum-computer-may-be-superior-to-conventional-computers-by-2018/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">working quantum computers</a>. They&rsquo;ve found ways to <a href="https://futurism.com/physicists-demonstrate-record-breaking-long-distance-quantum-entanglement-in-space/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> sustain the life of qubits</a> to increase the length of time information could be <a href="https://futurism.com/scientists-just-successfully-stored-quantum-information-10000-times-longer-than-ever-before/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">contained in a quantum system</a>, and according to experts, <a href="https://futurism.com/taken-the-age-of-commercial-quantum-computers-has-arrived/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">working quantum computers</a> will very likely be available in the next couple of decades.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Nobody is saying &lsquo;never&rsquo; anymore,&rdquo; Scott Totzke, Chief Executive of the Canadian firm Isara Corp., <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/how-googles-quantum-computer-could-change-the-world-1508158847?mod=e2fb" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">told </a><i><a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/how-googles-quantum-computer-could-change-the-world-1508158847?mod=e2fb" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Wall Street Journal</a></i>. &ldquo;We are in the very, very early days, but we are well past the science-fiction point.&rdquo;</p>
<p>So, what can we expect from the future of quantum computing?</p>
<h2>Life With Quantum Computers</h2>
<p>Quantum computers will be capable of performing vastly more <a href="https://futurism.com/the-race-to-prove-quantum-supremacy-may-be-won-in-the-next-year/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">complicated computations</a> than classical computers, and according to <a href="http://superposition.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">William Hurley</a>, chair of the Quantum Computing Standards Workgroup at the <a href="https://www.ieee.org/index.html?WT.mc_id=mn_ieee" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)</a>, the implications of that will be tremendous.</p>
<p>Hurley elaborated on this in an email to Futurism:</p>
<blockquote><p>It&rsquo;s my personal belief that quantum computing will help us make sense of the deluge of data we find ourselves creating to solve some very interesting problems. There are systems generating billions of data sets a day, and those might be the solution to some critical problems affecting society, but we can&rsquo;t possibly begin to [work] through [all the data]. To me, that&rsquo;s extremely exciting.</p></blockquote>
<p>In short, the future of quantum computing will see us solving some of the most complex questions facing the world today and not just in fields like physics or science.</p>
<p>&ldquo;I think there&rsquo;s a huge opportunity for quantum computing to disrupt a number of industries,&rdquo; said Hurley. &ldquo;However, I believe that the financial, pharmaceutical, and security industries will see the most change in the shortest amount of time.&rdquo;</p>
<p></p>
<p>While some experts have warned that this power could be <a href="https://futurism.com/worlds-leading-physicist-says-quantum-computers-are-tools-of-destruction-not-creation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">used for nefarious purposes</a>, Hurley believes the good will outweigh the bad:</p>
<blockquote><p>There will always be reasons to temper our optimism around any new technological advance. Still, I am incredibly excited about the potential positive outcomes of quantum computing. From finding new cures to diseases to helping discover new particles, I think this is the most excited I have been in my entire career. We should be focusing our energy as much on the positive outcomes as we currently are the negative ones.</p></blockquote>
<h2>A New Kind of Internet</h2>
<p>So-called quantum communications is one of the more interesting applications planned for the future of quantum computing.</p>
<p>Researchers in China and elsewhere in the world have begun exploring the potential of <a href="https://futurism.com/china-set-to-launch-the-worlds-first-quantum-communication-network/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">building quantum networks</a> using the same principles behind quantum computing. The creation of these networks would eventually open the door for a <a href="https://futurism.com/the-quantum-internet-is-just-a-decade-away-heres-what-you-need-to-know/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">quantum internet</a>, a more secure communication system in which information is stored and transmitted with <a href="https://futurism.com/nist-study-quantum-computers-will-make-current-cryptography-obsolete/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">advanced cryptography</a>. Such a network, however, couldn&rsquo;t be truly realized until <a href="https://futurism.com/new-condensed-matter-state-paves-the-way-for-scalable-quantum-computers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">quantum computers become scalable</a>, which <a href="https://futurism.com/when-will-quantum-computers-be-consumer-products/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Futurism readers</a> think will happen before 2050.</p>
<figure><a href="https://futurism.com/images/future-moonshots-infographic/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><img src="https://futurism.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Homepage-Thumbnail-3-1.jpg" alt="Future Moonshots [INFOGRAPHIC]"></a><figcaption><strong><a href="https://futurism.com/images/future-moonshots-infographic/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Click to View Full Infographic</a></strong></figcaption></figure>
<p>While researchers have managed to create quantum computers, they are all bulky and only work in specialized environments. Therefore, the future of quantum computing may include the adoption of alternatives to the systems currently being created in cutting-edge laboratories.</p>
<p>The path forward may be through the creation of <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/tech-talk/computing/hardware/qudits-the-real-future-of-quantum-computing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">specialized computer chips</a> capable of functioning like quantum computers but sans the state-of-the-art components those systems require. The quantum computing revolution could also well begin with the average person accessing a quantum computer through a cloud service, such as those <a href="https://futurism.com/ibm-giving-public-access-five-qubit-quantum-computer-free/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IBM</a> and <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-07-17/google-s-quantum-computing-push-opens-new-front-in-cloud-battle" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Google</a> have created.</p>
<p>&ldquo;I think you&rsquo;re going to see general availability of simulators and emulators that are useful in the next 24 months,&rdquo; said Hurley. Still, those systems would just be a placeholder for the real deal, which he sees arriving in the not-so-distant future: &ldquo;I would love to see a universal quantum computer available as earlier as three to five years out, and I believe that could be possible.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com/future-quantum-computer/" target="_blank">Here&rsquo;s What a World Powered by Quantum Computers Will Look Like</a> appeared first on <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com" target="_blank">Futurism</a>.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-27T18:28:31+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Dom Galeon</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://futurism.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://futurism.com"/>
		<updated>2017-10-27T18:28:31+00:00</updated>
		<title>Futurism</title></source>

	<category term="robots &amp; machines"/>

	<category term="computing"/>

	<category term="quantum computing"/>

	<category term="quantum internet"/>

	<category term="quantum mechanics"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-28:/445919</id>
	<link href="https://futurism.com/videos/quantum-computers-explained/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">The Science of Quantum Computers Explained in Under Two Minutes</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the next few years, quantum computers will usher in the next great era in computing technology. T...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the next few years, quantum computers will usher in the next great era in computing technology. Their successful creation will be a paradigm-shifting achievement&hellip;one that will forever alter the future of humanity. Here&rsquo;s what you need to know.</p>
<p></p><p>The post <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com/videos/quantum-computers-explained/" target="_blank">The Science of Quantum Computers Explained in Under Two Minutes</a> appeared first on <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com" target="_blank">Futurism</a>.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-27T18:04:25+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Jolene Creighton</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://futurism.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://futurism.com"/>
		<updated>2017-10-27T18:04:25+00:00</updated>
		<title>Futurism</title></source>

	<category term="hard science"/>

	<category term="encryption"/>

	<category term="quantum computers"/>

	<category term="qubits"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-31:/446885</id>
	<link href="http://physicsworld.com/cws/article/news/2017/oct/30/proton-antiproton-equivalence-confirmed-by-best-ever-measurement-of-magnetic-moment" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Protonantiproton equivalence confirmed by best-ever measurement of magnetic moment</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Flash Physics: need-to-know updates from the world of physics</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Flash Physics: need-to-know updates from the world of physics<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/PhysicsWorld/~4/4J2Gr9sGSA4" height="1" width="1" alt=""></p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-30T12:46:08+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Marric Stephens</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://physicsworld.com/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://physicsworld.com/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-30T12:46:08+00:00</updated>
		<title>physicsworld.com: all content</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-30:/446857</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-10-saturn-belts-stranger-solar.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Saturn's radiation belts: A stranger to the solar wind</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The radiation belts of Earth and Saturn differ more strongly than previously assumed. In these belts...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The radiation belts of Earth and Saturn differ more strongly than previously assumed. In these belts, very energetic particles, such as electrons and protons, move around the planet at high velocities - captured by its magnetic field. In the case of the Earth, the solar wind, a current of charged particles from the Sun varying in strength, controls the intensity of the radiation belt both directly and indirectly. The radiation belts of Saturn, however, develop completely independently of the solar wind and are instead decisively influenced by the gas giant's moons. These results are published today in the journal Nature Astronomy by a group of researchers from the Max Planck Institute for Solar System Research (MPS) in Germany co-leading the most comprehensive study on the subject to date. Key to the new findings are measurements of the MIMI-LEMMS instrument aboard NASA's Cassini space probe, which explored the Saturn system for more than 13 years before its dive into the planet on the 15th of September this year.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-30T21:59:52+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-30T21:59:52+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="space exploration"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/saturnsradia.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-28:/446048</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-10/nsfc-s2i102717.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">September 2017's intense solar activity viewed from space</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(NASA/Goddard Space Flight Center) September 2017 saw a spate of solar activity, with the Sun emitti...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>NASA/Goddard Space Flight Center</i>) September 2017 saw a spate of solar activity, with the Sun emitting 27 M-class and four X-class flares and releasing several powerful coronal mass ejections, or CMEs, between Sept. 6-10. Solar flares are powerful bursts of radiation, while coronal mass ejections are massive clouds of solar material and magnetic fields that erupt from the Sun at incredible speeds.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-27T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-10-27T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Space and Planetary Science</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-27:/445892</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-10/ggph-tsu102717.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">The successful US/German satellite gravity mission GRACE comes to an end after 15 years</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(GFZ GeoForschungsZentrum Potsdam, Helmholtz Centre) On March 17, 2002, the twin satellites of the N...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>GFZ GeoForschungsZentrum Potsdam, Helmholtz Centre</i>) On March 17, 2002, the twin satellites of the NASA/German Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment (GRACE) were launched in order to make precise measurements of the Earth&acute;s gravity field. GRACE has lasted three times as long as originally planned for more than 15 years. Now it has ended science operations.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-27T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-10-27T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Space and Planetary Science</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-27:/445715</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-10-physicists-quantum-gravity-current-technology.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Physicists propose test of quantum gravity using current technology</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Physicists have proposed a way to test quantum gravity that, in principle, could be performed by a l...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Physicists have proposed a way to test quantum gravity that, in principle, could be performed by a laser-based, table-top experiment using currently available technology. Although a theory of quantum gravity would overcome one of the biggest challenges in modern physics by unifying general relativity and quantum mechanics, currently physicists have no way of testing any proposed theories of quantum gravity.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-27T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-27T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="quantum physics"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/quantumgravi.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-31:/447165</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-10-disruptive-bioengineering-cells-interact.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Disruptive bioengineering  changing the way cells interact with each other</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Researchers at the MRC Weatherall Institute of Molecular Medicine have developed a new platform base...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Researchers at the MRC Weatherall Institute of Molecular Medicine have developed a new platform based on the revolutionary CRISPR/Cas9 technology, to alter the way human cells respond to external signals, and provide new opportunities for stopping cancer cells from developing.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-31T13:55:17+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-31T13:55:17+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="biotechnology"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/disruptivebi.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-31:/447123</id>
	<link href="https://inhabitat.com/73-million-trees-to-be-planted-in-largest-reforestation-project-ever-undertaken" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">73 million trees to be planted in largest reforestation project ever</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Conservation International aims to plant 73 million trees in the Brazilian Amazon in the largest re...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img fl:hint-main-image="true" src="//inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/10/Amazon-Rainforest-889x592.jpg" alt="Amazon, rainforest, tropical forest, Amazon rainforest"></p>
<p>Conservation International aims to plant 73 million trees in the <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/amazon-rainforest/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Brazilian Amazon</a> in the largest reforestation project ever. The trees will be planted in the &ldquo;arc of deforestation&rdquo; that runs through the <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/brazil/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Brazilian</a> states of Amazonas, Acre, Par&aacute;, and Rond&ocirc;nia, as well as throughout the Xingu watershed. In the short-term, the project aims to restore 70,000 acres of tropical forest.&nbsp;&ldquo;If the world is to hit the 1.2&deg;C or 2&deg;C [degrees of warming] target that we all agreed to in Paris, then protecting tropical forests in particular has to be a big part of that,&rdquo; said M. Sanjayan, CEO of Conservation International, in an interview with <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/40481305/the-largest-ever-tropical-reforestation-is-planting-73-million-trees" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Fast Company</a>.</p>
<p><img src="//inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/10/Amazon-River-889x591.jpg" alt="Amazon, rainforest, tropical forest, Amazon rainforest"></p>
<p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s not just the trees that matter, but what kind of <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/trees/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">trees</a>,&rdquo; said Sanjayan. &ldquo;If you&rsquo;re really thinking about getting carbon dioxide out of atmosphere, then tropical forests are the ones that end up mattering the most.&rdquo; Ceasing deforestation would allow for the absorption of 37 percent of the world&rsquo;s annual <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/fossil-fuels/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">carbon emissions</a> yet scientists worry that 20 percent of the Amazon may be deforested in the next two decades, in addition to the 20 percent that was deforested in the past 40 years. To combat this rapid pace of destruction, Conservation International is utilizing new, efficient planting techniques that could be applied worldwide.&nbsp;&ldquo;This is not a stunt,&rdquo; said Sanjayan. &ldquo;It is a carefully controlled experiment to literally figure out how to do tropical restoration at scale, so that people can replicate it and we can drive the costs down dramatically.&rdquo;</p>
<p><a href="https://inhabitat.com/hurricane-maria-ravaged-the-only-tropical-rainforest-in-the-united-states/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Related:&nbsp;Hurricane Maria ravaged the only tropical rainforest in the United States</a></p>
<p><img src="//inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/10/Amazon-Rainforest-889x592.jpg" alt="Amazon, rainforest, tropical forest, Amazon rainforest"></p>
<p>The planting method used in the project is known as <em>muvuca</em>, which is a <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/portugal/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Portuguese</a> word to describe many people in a small place. In&nbsp;<em>muvuca,</em> hundreds of native tree seeds of various species are spread over every inch of deforested land. Natural selection then allows the most suited to survive and thrive. A 2014 study from the Food and Agriculture Organization and Biodiversity International found that&nbsp;more than 90 percent of native tree species planted using the&nbsp;<em>muvuca</em> method germinate and are well suited to survive <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/drought/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">drought conditions</a> for up to six months.&nbsp;&ldquo;With plant-by-plant reforestation techniques, you get a typical density of about 160 plants per hectare,&rdquo; said Rodrigo Medeiros, Conservation International&rsquo;s vice president of the Brazil program and project lead, according to <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/40481305/the-largest-ever-tropical-reforestation-is-planting-73-million-trees" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Fast Company</a>. &ldquo;With muvuca, the initial outcome is 2,500 species per hectare. And after 10 years, you can reach 5,000 trees per hectare. It&rsquo;s much more diverse, much more dense, and less expensive than traditional techniques.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Via <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/40481305/the-largest-ever-tropical-reforestation-is-planting-73-million-trees" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Fast Company</a></p>
<p><em>Images via <a href="https://depositphotos.com/search/amazon-rainforest.html?qview=84187390" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Depositphotos</a> <a href="https://depositphotos.com/search/amazon-rainforest.html?qview=42468941" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">(1)</a></em></p><div>
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Inhabitat?a=S16SbfGVWYQ:etVtWICobTw:yIl2AUoC8zA" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Inhabitat?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Inhabitat?a=S16SbfGVWYQ:etVtWICobTw:DLYy-l-dIDg" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Inhabitat?d=DLYy-l-dIDg" border="0"></a>
</div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-31T13:47:21+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Greg Beach</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://inhabitat.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://inhabitat.com"/>
		<updated>2017-10-31T13:47:21+00:00</updated>
		<title>Inhabitat - Sustainable Design Innovation, Eco Architecture, Green Building  green technology</title></source>

	<category term="environment"/>

	<category term="conservation"/>

	<category term="climate change"/>

	<category term="carbon emissions"/>

	<category term="trees"/>

	<category term="forests"/>

	<category term="deforestation"/>

	<category term="rainforests"/>

	<category term="ecology"/>

	<category term="greenhouse gas emissions"/>

	<category term="science"/>

	<category term="reforestation"/>

	<category term="news"/>

	<category term="amazon rainforest"/>

	<category term="tropical rainforests"/>

	<category term="tropical forests"/>

	<category term="conservation international"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-27:/445741</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-10-image-genetics-space.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Image: Studying the genetics of organisms in space</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At NASA's Kennedy Space Center, organisms in a Petri plate are exposed to blue excitation lighting i...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At NASA's Kennedy Space Center, organisms in a Petri plate are exposed to blue excitation lighting in a Spectrum prototype unit. Scientists and engineers working on the Spectrum project are developing new hardware for the International Space Station, to support experiments demonstrating how different organisms, such as plants, microbes or worms, develop under conditions of microgravity.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-27T11:50:03+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-27T11:50:03+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="space exploration"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/imagestudyin.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-30:/446473</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-10-genome-previous-photosynthesis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Genome research challenges previous understanding of the origin of photosynthesis</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Plant biologists at Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory (Berkeley Lab), in collaboration with coll...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Plant biologists at Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory (Berkeley Lab), in collaboration with colleagues from the California Institute of Technology (Caltech), have reconstructed the evolutionary history of photosynthesis to provide new insight into the yet-unfolding story of its origins.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-30T11:08:20+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-30T11:08:20+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="biotechnology"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/genomeresear.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-30:/446549</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-10/bti-pgs102917.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Pumpkin genomes sequenced, revealing uncommon evolutionary history</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Boyce Thompson Institute) For some, pumpkins conjure carved Halloween decorations, but for many peo...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>Boyce Thompson Institute</i>) For some, pumpkins conjure carved Halloween decorations, but for many people around the world, these gourds provide nutrition. Scientists at Boyce Thompson Institute (BTI) and the National Engineering Research Center for Vegetables in Beijing have sequenced the genomes of two important pumpkin species, Cucurbita maxima and Cucurbita moschata.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-29T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-10-29T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Technology, Engineering and Computer Science</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-29:/446225</id>
	<link href="https://www.livescience.com/60802-explorers-dive-beneath-antarctic-ice.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Explorers Will Dive Beneath Antarctic Ice Shelf Looking for Life</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Scientists will spend six weeks diving beneath the Ross Ice Shelf, exploring how climate change affe...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Scientists will spend six weeks diving beneath the Ross Ice Shelf, exploring how climate change affects marine biodiversity while documenting their work through social media and in 360-degree video.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-29T12:30:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.livescience.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.livescience.com"/>
		<updated>2017-10-29T12:30:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>LiveScience.com</title></source>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/jpeg" 
		length="1"
		href="https://img.purch.com/rc/160x100/aHR0cDovL3d3dy5saXZlc2NpZW5jZS5jb20vaW1hZ2VzL2kvMDAwLzA5Ni80NTAvb3JpZ2luYWwvYWRnLTguanBn"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-27:/445690</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-10-evaporation-dynamics-nano-micro-scale.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Evaporation dynamics at the nano- and micro-scale</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new evaporation dynamics study finds that very small droplets evaporate more slowly than predicted...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new evaporation dynamics study finds that very small droplets evaporate more slowly than predicted by current models. Researchers from the Institute of Physical Chemistry of the Polish Academy of Sciences (IPC PAS) in Warsaw, in cooperation with the Institute of Physics of the PAS (IP PAS),have described the course of evaporation of micrometer and nanometer-sized droplets. The result of the research, presented in the journal Soft Matter, is an equation that accurately predicts the course of evaporation for droplets of different sizes and fluids. The equation has many applications, including constructing more accurate climate models and designing more efficient internal combustion engines or cooling units.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-27T10:26:11+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-27T10:26:11+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="condensed matter"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/smalldroplet.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-26:/445376</id>
	<link href="https://futurism.com/rights-synthetic-lifeforms-civil-rights-controversy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">The Rights of Synthetic Lifeforms is the Next Great Civil Rights Controversy</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Robot Rights
Artificially intelligent (AI) robots and automated systems are already transforming soc...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Robot Rights</h2>
<p>Artificially intelligent (AI) robots and <a href="https://futurism.com/automation-may-lead-to-a-workless-future-for-humans-heres-how-we-can-cope/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">automated systems</a> are already transforming society in a host of ways. Cars are creeping closer to <a href="https://futurism.com/intel-and-waymo-have-teamed-up-to-roll-out-fully-autonomous-vehicles/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Level 5 autonomy</a>, factories are cutting costs by <a href="https://futurism.com/3-tiny-robots-help-cut-chinese-warehouse-labor-costs-by-half-kelsey/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">replacing human workers with robots</a>, and AIs are even outperforming people in a number of traditionally <a href="https://futurism.com/the-automation-upheaval-wont-be-limited-to-blue-collar-jobs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">white-collar professions</a>.</p>
<p>As these systems advance, so will the potential that they are involved in criminal activity, and right now, no regulations are in place that say how the law should treat super-intelligent synthetic entities. Who takes the blame if a robot causes an accident or is implicated in a crime? What happens if a robot is the victim of a crime? Do self-aware robots deserve rights that are comparable to those given to human beings?</p>
<p></p>
<p>Before we can begin discussing robot rights, we need to articulate exactly what (or who?) counts in this equation, said <a href="https://www.media.mit.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MIT Media Lab</a> researcher and robot ethics expert Kate Darling in an email correspondence with Futurism. In other words, clearly defined terminology is a prerequisite for any productive conversation regarding robot rights.</p>
<p>&ldquo;If we want to use legislation to regulate robotic technology, we&rsquo;re going to need to establish better definitions than what we&rsquo;re operating with today,&rdquo; she said. &ldquo;Even the word &lsquo;robot&rsquo; doesn&rsquo;t have a good universal definition right now.&rdquo;</p>
<h2>Eyes on Today</h2>
<p>Now is the time to put these definitions in place because artificially intelligent robots are already in our midst.</p>
<p>Autonomous delivery robots are a common sight in the <a href="https://futurism.com/estonia-could-be-the-first-country-in-the-world-to-introduce-its-own-cryptocurrency/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Estonian</a> capital of Tallinn. As such, the country&rsquo;s government is being proactive with regards to robot regulations and legal recourse for issues regarding ownership and culpability.</p>
<p>&ldquo;It all started out from the <a href="https://futurism.com/autonomous-cars-will-be-on-california-roads-in-2018-without-human-drivers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">self-driving car</a> taskforce,&rdquo; Marten Kaevats, the national digital advisor for the government office of Estonia, told Futurism. &ldquo;We quite soon discovered that these liability, integrity, and accountability issues are not specific to self-driving cars; they&rsquo;re general AI questions.&rdquo;</p>
<p></p>
<p>Kaevats is aware that any discussion of robots and AI can quickly devolve into talk of <a href="https://futurism.com/kurzweil-claims-that-the-singularity-will-happen-by-2045/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the singularity</a> and superintelligence, but that&rsquo;s not the focus right now. &ldquo;We are trying to work on things that are actually already here,&rdquo; he explained.</p>
<p>Still, Estonia is looking to put legislation in place that has the flexibility to respond to advances in technology. Kaevats acknowledges that it&rsquo;s not possible to create regulations that are completely future-proof, but he sees a pressing need for laws that offer certain rights alongside certain liabilities.</p>
<p>As Kaevats pointed out, right now, self-aware artificial intelligences are so far off that there&rsquo;s no reason to rush into giving robots similar rights to humans. In addition to considering the ethical ramifications of putting machines on par with humans, we need to examine how such laws might be open to abuse <em>before </em>regulations are established.</p>
<h2>Production Line Patsy</h2>
<p>Estonia isn&rsquo;t the only place where conversations on robot rights are happening.</p>
<p>The journal <em>Artificial Intelligence and Law</em> recently published an article by <a href="http://www.bath.ac.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">University of Bath</a> reader Joanna J. Bryson and academic lawyers Mihailis E. Diamantis and Thomas D. Grant. In the paper, the authors state that <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10506-017-9214-9#Sec8" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">proposals for synthetic personhood</a> are already being discussed by the European Union and that the legal framework to do so is already in place. The authors stress the importance of giving artificially intelligent beings obligations as well as protections, so as to remove their potential as a &ldquo;liability shield.&rdquo;</p>
<p>But granting them full rights?</p>
<p>When Bryson spoke to Futurism, she warned <em>against</em> the establishment of robot rights, relating the situation to the way the legal personhood of corporations has been abused in the past<em>. </em></p>
<p>&ldquo;Corporations are legal persons, but it&rsquo;s a legal fiction. It would be a similar legal fiction to make AI a legal person,&rdquo; said Bryson. &ldquo;What we need to do is roll back, if anything, the overextension of legal personhood &mdash; not roll it forward into machines. It doesn&rsquo;t generate any benefits; it only encourages people to obfuscate their AI.&rdquo;</p>
<figure><a href="https://futurism.com/images/types-of-ai-from-reactive-to-self-aware-infographic/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><img src="https://futurism.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/HomeThumb.jpg-1.png" alt="Types of AI: From Reactive to Self-Aware [INFOGRAPHIC]"></a><figcaption><strong><a href="https://futurism.com/images/types-of-ai-from-reactive-to-self-aware-infographic/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Click to View Full Infographic</a></strong></figcaption></figure>
<p>Bryson offered up the example of a <a href="https://futurism.com/dubai-jump-starts-autonomous-taxi-service-with-50-tesla-vehicles/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">driverless taxi</a>, which could potentially be made fully independent from its owner or manufacturer, serving as a legally recognized individual, fulfilling its own contracts. This situation could be manipulated to reduce the amount of taxes paid on the vehicle&rsquo;s earnings by whoever receives the profits.</p>
<p>Kaevats said that this won&rsquo;t be a problem in Estonia &mdash; the country&rsquo;s digital <a href="https://futurism.com/research-shows-inequality-is-solved-with-wealth-redistribution-not-tax-cuts/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tax system</a> is proactive enough to track any malicious activity. However, the potential for abuse certainly exists in regions with less technologically advanced tax codes.</p>
<p>Corporations can already use the letter of the law to withhold as much wealth as possible. The use of a synthetic person as a &ldquo;fall guy&rdquo; for illicit activity isn&rsquo;t outside the realm of possibility, and giving a robot rights could serve to emancipate them from conventional ownership. At that point, the entity is the ultimate independent contractor, with companies able to absolve themselves of wrongdoing even if they instructed the machine to behave in the illegal way.</p>
<p>Legislation could certainly be written up that avoids these pitfalls, though, so policy makers just need to be sure that any rights given to synthetic entities don&rsquo;t include loopholes that can be abused.</p>
<h2>Moral Dilemma</h2>
<p>In the far more distant future, we&rsquo;ll need to consider the issue of self-aware robots. How should we tackle synthetic personhood for those entities?</p>
<p>&ldquo;If we discover that there are certain capacities that we want to create in artificial intelligence, and once you create those, you spontaneously get these cognitive features that warrant personhood, we&rsquo;ll have to have this discussion about how similar they are to the human consciousness,&rdquo; James Hughes, executive director of the <a href="https://ieet.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Institute for Ethics and Emerging Technologies</a>, told Futurism.</p>
<q>Traditionally, under the law, you&rsquo;re either a person or you are property.</q>
<p>The creation of this level of technology won&rsquo;t be happening anytime soon, if it happens at all, but its potential raises some thorny issues about our obligation to <a href="https://futurism.com/human-intelligence-limited-why-need-synthetic-intelligence/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">synthetic beings</a> and the evolving nature of personhood.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Traditionally, under the law, you&rsquo;re either a person or you are property &mdash; and the problem with being property is that you have no rights,&rdquo; bioethicist and attorney-at-law Linda McDonald-Glenn told Futurism. &ldquo;In the past, we&rsquo;ve made some pretty awful mistakes.&rdquo;</p>
<p>According to Hughes, this situation calls for a test that determines whether or not a synthetic person is self-aware. In the meantime, Estonia has found a fairly simple way to determine the rights of their robots. Instead of using technology as the defining factor, the nation will grant rights based on registration under the <a href="https://medium.com/e-residency-blog/estonia-starts-public-discussion-legalising-ai-166cb8e34596" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">mythologically inspired Kratt law</a>.</p>
<p>Estonian folklore states that the Kratt is an inanimate object brought to life, just as artificial intelligence can give a machine the cognitive abilities it needs to complete a particular task. The Kratt law will determine what level of sophistication a robot needs to possess in order to be considered its own legal entity.</p>
<p>&ldquo;This is what we want our governments to do,&rdquo; said Bryson, praising European efforts to put well-thought-out legislation in place. &ldquo;This is what governments are for and what law is for.&rdquo;</p>
<p>In many ways, AI technology is still very young, but there&rsquo;s no better time than now to start thinking about the legal and ethical implications of its usage.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com/rights-synthetic-lifeforms-civil-rights-controversy/" target="_blank">The Rights of Synthetic Lifeforms is the Next Great Civil Rights Controversy</a> appeared first on <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com" target="_blank">Futurism</a>.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-26T18:00:58+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Brad Jones</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://futurism.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://futurism.com"/>
		<updated>2017-10-26T18:00:58+00:00</updated>
		<title>Futurism</title></source>

	<category term="artificial intelligence"/>

	<category term="ethics"/>

	<category term="regulation"/>

	<category term="robots"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-27:/445672</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-10/epfd-aal102617.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Advanced artificial limbs mapped in the brain</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Ecole Polytechnique F&eacute;d&eacute;rale de Lausanne) EPFL scientists from the Center for Neuroprosthetics have...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>Ecole Polytechnique F&eacute;d&eacute;rale de Lausanne</i>) EPFL scientists from the Center for Neuroprosthetics have used functional MRI to show how the brain re-maps motor and sensory pathways following targeted motor and sensory reinnervation (TMSR), a neuroprosthetic approach where residual limb nerves are rerouted towards intact muscles and skin regions to control a robotic limb.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-27T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-10-27T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Technology, Engineering and Computer Science</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-26:/445420</id>
	<link href="https://futurism.com/darpas-new-brain-device-increases-learning-speed-by-40/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">DARPAs New Brain Device Increases Learning Speed by 40%</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cheap and Non-Invasive
New research funded by the U.S. Department of Defense&rsquo;s Defense Advance...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Cheap and Non-Invasive</h2>
<p>New research funded by the U.S. Department of Defense&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.darpa.mil/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Defense Advanced Research Project Agency (DARPA)</a> has successfully demonstrated how a non-invasive method of stimulating the brain can boost cognitive performance. Working under DARPA&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.darpa.mil/program/restoring-active-memory" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Restoring Active Memory (RAM) program</a>, scientists from <a href="http://www.hrl.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">HRL Laboratories</a> in California, <a href="http://www.mcgill.ca/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">McGill University</a> in Montreal, Canada, and <a href="https://soterixmedical.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Soterix Medical</a> in New York tested their brain device on macaques and observed a substantial increase in the monkeys&rsquo; ability to quickly perform certain tasks.</p>
<figure><a href="https://futurism.com/images/reprogramming-the-human-mind-heres-how-well-make-humanity-2-0-infographic/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><img src="https://futurism.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Homepage-Thumbnail-900x600.jpg" alt="Reprogramming the Human Mind: Here&rsquo;s How We&rsquo;ll Make Humanity 2.0 [INFOGRAPHIC]"></a><figcaption><strong><a href="https://futurism.com/images/reprogramming-the-human-mind-heres-how-well-make-humanity-2-0-infographic/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Click to View Full Infographic</a></strong></figcaption></figure>
<p>In their study published, which has been published in the journal <i><a href="http://www.cell.com/current-biology/fulltext/S0960-9822(17)31185-5" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Current Biology,</a></i> the HRL team describes how they used non-invasive transcranial direct current stimulation (tDCS) to stimulate the prefrontal cortex in the macaques. They then prompted the animals to perform a task based on associative learning &mdash; learning associations between visual cues and a location &mdash; in order to get a reward.</p>
<p>The macaques that wore the tDCS brain device significantly outperformed the control group. The former needed only 12 trials to learn how to immediately get the reward, while the latter needed 21 trials, with the tDCS device accounting for the 40 percent increase in learning speed, according to the researchers.</p>
<p>&ldquo;In this experiment, we targeted the prefrontal cortex with individualized non-invasive stimulation montages,&rdquo; lead HRL researcher Praveen Pilly <a href="http://www.hrl.com/news/2017/10/12/hrl-and-mcgill-scientists-confirm-transcranial-stimulation-effects-and-determine-a-key-mechanism" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">said in a statement</a>. &ldquo;That is the region that controls many executive functions, including decision-making, cognitive control, and contextual memory retrieval. It is connected to almost all the other cortical areas of the brain, and stimulating it has widespread effects.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Based on the results of their study, the researchers say the increased learning speed was caused by the modulated connectivity between brain areas and not the rate at which neurons fired.</p>
<h2>All in the Mind</h2>
<p>The ability to <a href="https://futurism.com/do-not-edit-nootropics-and-the-future-of-brain-enhancing-smart-drugs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">increase one&rsquo;s brain function</a> almost instantaneously is no doubt appealing. As such, the concept has been a fixture of science fiction for decades (see: &ldquo;Flowers for Algernon,&rdquo; &ldquo;Limitless&rdquo;), but advancements in technology seem to be bringing us closer to a future in which quickly leveling-up intelligence is a real possibility.</p>
<p>In addition to this DARPA device, researchers from Boston University have developed their own <a href="https://futurism.com/scientists-just-used-brain-stimulation-to-literally-change-how-people-think/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">non-invasive method to improve learning</a> using high-definition transcranial alternating current stimulation (HD-tACS). However, the DARPA researchers claim their device is cheap, which may make it more appealing than other technologies like it.</p>
<p></p>
<p>Simply making people smarter is not the sole purpose of this type of research. A potentially more immediate application of DARPA&rsquo;s brain device is the treatment of people suffering from neural degeneration that causes a loss of memory function.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.cell.com/current-biology/fulltext/S0960-9822(17)31185-5" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">As the team noted in their study</a>, &ldquo;These results are consistent with the idea that tDCS leads to widespread changes in brain activity and suggest that it may be a valuable method for cheaply and non-invasively altering functional connectivity in humans.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com/darpas-new-brain-device-increases-learning-speed-by-40/" target="_blank">DARPA&rsquo;s New Brain Device Increases Learning Speed by 40%</a> appeared first on <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com" target="_blank">Futurism</a>.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-26T18:27:31+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Dom Galeon</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://futurism.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://futurism.com"/>
		<updated>2017-10-26T18:27:31+00:00</updated>
		<title>Futurism</title></source>

	<category term="hard science"/>

	<category term="brain stimulation"/>

	<category term="memory"/>

	<category term="mental health"/>

	<category term="neurobiology"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-26:/445423</id>
	<link href="https://futurism.com/crispr-can-now-be-used-to-edit-individual-bases/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">CRISPR Can Now Be Used to Edit Individual Bases</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Crisper Than CRISPR
CRISPR-Cas9 has been widely heralded as one of the most important scientific dev...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Crisper Than CRISPR</h2>
<p>CRISPR-Cas9 has been widely heralded as one of the most important scientific developments of recent years, thanks to its capacity to <a href="https://futurism.com/scientists-developed-a-way-to-precisely-edit-genes-in-the-human-brain/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">make edits to the human genome</a>. Now, a more precise version of the tool has been developed by a team of scientists from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology and Harvard.</p>
<p>The human genome is made up of chemical bases that are referred to as A, C, G, and T. The new technique is called base editing, and it allows individual bases to be modified without causing a break in the <a href="https://futurism.com/scientists-are-creating-materials-from-dna/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">DNA&rsquo;s overarching structure</a>.</p>
<p>Sometimes, only one base pair in a length of DNA is abnormal in some way &ndash; this is called a point mutation, and it accounts for 32,000 of the 50,000 changes in the human genome that have been associated with diseases. <a href="http://nature.com/articles/doi:10.1038/nature24644" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">A study published in <em>Nature</em></a> looked at changing an A base into a G; w process that could address around half of those mutations.</p>
<p></p>
<p>The modified version of CRISPR only targets a particular base, rearranging its atoms and prompting cells to adjust the corresponding strand to match. For instance, an A-T base pair is rewritten as G-C.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Standard genome-editing methods, including <a href="https://futurism.com/scientists-used-genetic-modification-to-create-low-fat-pigs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the use of CRISPR-Cas9</a>, make double-stranded breaks in DNA, which is especially useful when the goal is to insert or delete DNA bases,&rdquo; said David Liu, who led the research, speaking to the <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/s/609203/crispr-20-is-here-and-its-way-more-precise/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MIT Technology Review</a>. &ldquo;But when the goal is to simply fix a point mutation, base editing offers a more efficient and cleaner solution.&rdquo;</p>
<p>This project isn&rsquo;t necessarily a replacement for the CRISPR &ndash; it&rsquo;s a different tool that allows for a different kind of edit to be made. The results could have a profound impact on the effect that hereditary diseases can have on people&rsquo;s lives.</p>
<h2>DNA &amp; RNA</h2>
<p>While one study was looking into how base editing could be used to modify DNA, another group of researchers have been looking into how it could be <a href="https://futurism.com/rna-may-not-be-the-sole-originator-of-life-scientists-report/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">used to tweak RNA</a>. With RNA, the molecule naturally degrades in the body, so making adjustments to it doesn&rsquo;t result in permanent changes.</p>
<p>Liu projects that base editing both RNA and DNA in the same patient could offer up some novel possibilities for therapeutic treatments. He and his team are now going to investigate how base editing might be used to fix blood disorders, <a href="https://futurism.com/researchers-are-using-stem-cell-tech-to-end-neurological-disorders/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">neurological disorders</a>, hereditary deafness, and hereditary blindness.</p>
<p>Many hereditary diseases have no known treatment options, so this research could turn out to be life-changing for people that are affected.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com/crispr-can-now-be-used-to-edit-individual-bases/" target="_blank">CRISPR Can Now Be Used to Edit Individual Bases</a> appeared first on <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com" target="_blank">Futurism</a>.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-26T18:12:11+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Brad Jones</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://futurism.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://futurism.com"/>
		<updated>2017-10-26T18:12:11+00:00</updated>
		<title>Futurism</title></source>

	<category term="health &amp; medicine"/>

	<category term="crispr"/>

	<category term="dna"/>

	<category term="human genome"/>

	<category term="rna"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-26:/445196</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-10-climate-affects-blocks-health.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">How climate change affects the building blocks for health</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In August last year, a third of the residents of the North Island township Havelock North fell acute...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In August last year, a third of the residents of the North Island township Havelock North fell acutely ill with gastroenteritis after their water was contaminated with campylobacter.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-26T13:40:05+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-26T13:40:05+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="environment"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/5-howclimatech.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-26:/445207</id>
	<link href="http://www.skyandtelescope.com/astronomy-news/how-bright-moon-exactly/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">How Bright is the Moon . . . Exactly?</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new study will take the old standard of Moon brightness to a new level of precision.
A full Easter...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><span><strong><em>A new study will take the old standard of Moon brightness to a new level of precision.</em></strong></span></p>
<div><img src="http://wwwcdn.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/Full-Easter-Moon.jpg" alt="Full Easter Moon" width="400" height="228" srcset="http://wwwcdn.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/Full-Easter-Moon.jpg 480w, http://wwwcdn.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/Full-Easter-Moon-300x171.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px"><p>A full Easter Moon rising<br><em>Dave Dickinson</em></p></div>
<p>For many a deep-sky astrophotographer, the Moon is something to be avoided. But for Earth-observing satellites, the Moon serves as a crucial calibration source &mdash; and it's about to get an overhaul.</p>
<p>The Moon doesn't produce its own light, of course: Its surface reflects the light of the Sun. But even though the Moon is airless and practically unchanging, not every lunar reflection is the same. The brightness of the Moon depends on the exact angle between the Earth, Moon, and Sun.</p>
<p>For example, the brightness of a <a href="http://www.skyandtelescope.com/observing/celestial-objects-to-watch/the-phase-of-the-moon/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">full Moon</a> is usually quoted at magnitude around &ndash;13, about 14 magnitudes or 400,000 times fainter than the Sun. (With a mean <em>albedo</em>, or reflectivity, of just 13%, the Moon is actually as dark as worn asphalt.) Yet the full Moon is about six times brighter than a first- or last-quarter (half-illuminated) Moon. That's because, during the full Moon, sunlight strikes the lunar surface nearly straight on from Earth's perspective, with few shadows.</p>
<p>The Moon-Sun-Earth angles would be easy enough to calculate if the Moon were in a circular orbit, but not only does the Moon vary in distance during its elliptical orbit around Earth, it also rocks slowly back and forth (<em>libration</em>) and side to side (<em>nutation</em>) as it keeps one face turned perpetually Earthward. As a result, the angle of sunlight on the Moon's face follows a complex but predictable cycle that repeats roughly every 20 years.</p>
<p>Until now, the intricacy of those changes have limited the Moon's usefulness as a calibration source. A new <a href="https://www.nist.gov/news-events/news/2017/10/how-bright-moon-really" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">project from the National Institute of Standards and Technology</a> (NIST) plans to refine this standard in an ambitious project.</p>
<h3>Gazing Moonward</h3>
<div><img src="http://wwwcdn.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/moon-thumbnail-281x360.jpg" alt="moon NIST" width="281" height="360" srcset="http://wwwcdn.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/moon-thumbnail-281x360.jpg 281w, http://wwwcdn.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/moon-thumbnail-148x190.jpg 148w, http://wwwcdn.skyandtelescope.com/wp-content/uploads/moon-thumbnail.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 281px) 100vw, 281px"><p>The Moon over the NIST Maryland Campus. These white domes will house the equipment used in the Moon brightness experiment. Eventually the domes and equipment will be moved to the Mauna Loa Observatory in Hawai'i.<br> <em>Jennifer Lauren Lee/NIST</em></p></div>
<p>The current uncertainty for the brightness of the Moon lies between 5% and 10%. But Earth-observing satellites require narrower wiggle room of less than 1%. Otherwise, gaps between missions mean missing out on important information.</p>
<p>"You lose the ability to stitch together measurements from different satellites to determine long term trends," says Stephen Maxwell (NIST) in a <a href="https://www.nist.gov/news-events/news/2017/10/how-bright-moon-really" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">recent press release.</a></p>
<p>More precise measurements are feasible. "The Moon's reflectance is stable to 1 part in 100 million per year," says Joe Rice (NIST). "The sunlight that illuminates the Moon does vary over an 11-year cycle, but that amount is only 0.1% across the spectrum."</p>
<p>The heart of the effort, still under development, is a 6-inch (150-mm) telescope equipped with a calcium fluoride lens (often used in spectroscopic instruments), which will enable the telescope to focus the Moon's light across ultraviolet, visible, and infrared wavelengths. Color calibration will occur nightly against broad- and narrowband light sources placed 15 to 30 meters away.</p>
<p>The multi-wavelength information is crucial, as Earth-observing satellites utilize the Moon's light to ensure that one satellite's "red"&nbsp; isn't another satellite's "yellow." Color can help satellites investigate algal blooms, trends in crop health, and more.</p>
<p>The project is scheduled to begin operations under the clear skies of Mauna Loa Observatory on Hawai'i in 2018. Although the pattern of illumination angles varies over 20 years, researchers expect to collect enough data in just 3 to 5 years to cover 95% of the possible angles.</p>
<p>The monitoring results will come just in time for the next generation of Earth-observing satellites, including <a href="https://www.nesdis.noaa.gov/jpss-1" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">JPSS-1</a>, which is set to launch next month from Vandenberg Air Force Base in California on November 10th.</p>
<p>Perhaps we shouldn't curse the next bright full Moon after all.</p>
<p></p>
<p>The post <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://www.skyandtelescope.com/astronomy-news/how-bright-moon-exactly/" target="_blank">How Bright is the Moon . . . Exactly?</a> appeared first on <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://www.skyandtelescope.com" target="_blank">Sky &amp; Telescope</a>.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-26T13:00:10+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>David Dickinson</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.skyandtelescope.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.skyandtelescope.com"/>
		<updated>2017-10-26T13:00:10+00:00</updated>
		<title>Sky &amp; Telescope</title></source>

	<category term="astronomy blogs"/>

	<category term="astronomy in space with david dickinson"/>

	<category term="astronomy news"/>

	<category term="solar system"/>

	<category term="moon"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-26:/445198</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-10-letters-dna-functions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Researchers create new 'letters' to enhance DNA functions</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just like how letters are strung together to form words, our DNA is also strung together by letters ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just like how letters are strung together to form words, our DNA is also strung together by letters to encode proteins. The genetic alphabet contains only 4 natural letters - A, C, G and T, which hold the blueprint for the production of proteins that make our bodies work. Now, researchers from the Institute of Bioengineering and Nanotechnology (IBN) of the Agency for Science, Technology and Research (A*STAR) have created a DNA technology with two new genetic letters that could better detect infectious diseases, such as dengue and Zika.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-26T13:40:03+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-26T13:40:03+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="biotechnology"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/65-researchersc.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-10-25:/335090</id>
	<link href="http://www.livescience.com/56626-how-humans-first-populated-oceania.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Oceania: How Humans Populated One of Earth's Most Remote Places</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Researchers ran computer simulations that take into account environmental variability and geographic...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Researchers ran computer simulations that take into account environmental variability and geographical setting to investigate how early explorers made it to these tiny, remote islands in the Pacific.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-10-25T10:34:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.livescience.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.livescience.com"/>
		<updated>2016-10-25T10:34:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>LiveScience.com</title></source>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/jpeg" 
		length="1"
		href="http://www.livescience.com/images/i/000/087/078/original/palau-micronesia.jpg?interpolation=lanczos-none&amp;fit=around|160:100&amp;crop=160:100;*,*"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-10-02:/328313</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-09/iufc-low090216.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Latest ocean warming review reveals extent of impacts on nature and humans</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(International Union for Conservation of Nature) Ocean warming is affecting humans in direct ways an...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>International Union for Conservation of Nature</i>) Ocean warming is affecting humans in direct ways and the impacts are already being felt, including effects on fish stocks and crop yields, more extreme weather events and increased risk from water-borne diseases, according to what has been called the most comprehensive review available on the issue, launched today by the International Union for Conservation of Nature at the IUCN World Conservation Congress in Hawaii.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-09-05T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2016-09-05T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Oceanography</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-09-14:/323725</id>
	<link href="http://phys.org/news/2016-09-insights-impacts-ocean-acidification.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">New insights into the impacts of ocean acidification</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new study recently published in the journal Global Biogeochemical Cycles offers clues to the poten...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new study recently published in the journal Global Biogeochemical Cycles offers clues to the potential impact of ocean acidification deep-sea, shell-forming organisms.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-09-14T14:13:58+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2016-09-14T14:13:58+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="environment"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="http://cdn.phys.org/newman/csz/news/tmb/2016/13-newinsightsi.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2016-09-07:/321462</id>
	<link href="http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-09/miot-sfi090716.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Study finds increased ocean acidification due to human activities</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Massachusetts Institute of Technology) Oceanographers from MIT and Woods Hole Oceanographic Institu...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>Massachusetts Institute of Technology</i>) Oceanographers from MIT and Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution report that the northeast Pacific Ocean has absorbed an increasing amount of anthropogenic carbon dioxide over the last decade, at a rate that mirrors the increase of carbon dioxide emissions pumped into the atmosphere.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2016-09-07T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2016-09-07T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Atmospheric Science</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-25:/444573</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-10/unio-urd102517.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">UNIST researchers develop highly stable perovskite solar cells</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Ulsan National Institute of Science and Technology(UNIST)) South Korea's Ulsan Nationl Institute of...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>Ulsan National Institute of Science and Technology(UNIST)</i>) South Korea's Ulsan Nationl Institute of Science and Technology has recently introduced a highly stable perovskite solar cells (PSCs).</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-25T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-10-25T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Chemistry, Physics and Materials Sciences</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-26:/445108</id>
	<link href="http://www.esa.int/Our_Activities/Human_Spaceflight/Low-cost_clocks_for_landing_on_the_Moon" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Low-cost clocks for landing on the Moon</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A European clock accurate to a trillionth of a second is set to be used on satellites a...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.esa.int/var/esa/storage/images/esa_multimedia/images/2017/10/laser_to_the_moon/17222787-1-eng-GB/Laser_to_the_Moon_small.jpg" width="170" height="96" align="left" hspace="8"><br>
		<p>
A European clock accurate to a trillionth of a second is set to be used on satellites and missions to the Moon.
</p><p>
The ultra-precise time-keeper was conceived by a small company in Latvia, and ESA has recognised its potential for space.
</p><p>
&ldquo;We are the Ferrari of timers with the components of a tractor,&rdquo; says Nikolai Adamovitch of Eventech.&nbsp;
</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-26T09:17:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.esa.int/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.esa.int/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-26T09:17:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>ESA Top News</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-26:/444984</id>
	<link href="https://www.livescience.com/60777-testing-quantum-mechanics-in-space.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">There and Back Again: Scientists Beam Photons to Space to Test Quantum Theory</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Researchers have taken a famous quantum-physics experiment to new heights by sending light, in the f...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Researchers have taken a famous quantum-physics experiment to new heights by sending light, in the form of photons, to space and back, demonstrating the dual-particle-wave nature of light over much greater distances than scientists can achieve on Earth.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-25T14:04:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.livescience.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.livescience.com"/>
		<updated>2017-10-25T14:04:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>LiveScience.com</title></source>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/jpeg" 
		length="1"
		href="https://img.purch.com/rc/160x100/aHR0cDovL3d3dy5saXZlc2NpZW5jZS5jb20vaW1hZ2VzL2kvMDAwLzA5Ni8zOTcvb3JpZ2luYWwvdmVkb3ZhdG8xSFIuanBn"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-26:/444994</id>
	<link href="https://www.livescience.com/45005-banana-nutrition-facts.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Bananas: Health Benefits, Risks &amp; Nutrition Facts</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Bananas are packed with nutrients and are good for your heart, your eyes, your diet and your mood.</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Bananas are packed with nutrients and are good for your heart, your eyes, your diet and your mood.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-25T13:33:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.livescience.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.livescience.com"/>
		<updated>2017-10-25T13:33:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>LiveScience.com</title></source>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/jpeg" 
		length="1"
		href="https://img.purch.com/rc/160x100/aHR0cDovL3d3dy5saXZlc2NpZW5jZS5jb20vaW1hZ2VzL2kvMDAwLzA2NS8xNDkvb3JpZ2luYWwvYmFuYW5hcy5qcGc="/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-25:/444927</id>
	<link href="https://futurism.com/bill-gates-humanity-will-see-its-last-case-of-polio-this-year/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Bill Gates: Humanity Will See Its Last Case of Polio This Year</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Completely Eradicated
For a long time, polio was one of the most feared diseases around the world. A...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Completely Eradicated</h2>
<p>For a long time, polio was one of the most feared diseases around the world. And although its <a href="https://amhistory.si.edu/polio/timeline/index.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">first recorded case dates back to 1789</a>, polio epidemics actually predate recorded history. Currently, in 2017, it looks like polio&rsquo;s long reign of terror is about to officially end, according to updates on Tuesday from the Rotary International&rsquo;s fifth annual <a href="https://www.rotary.org/en/unsung-heroes-honored-world-polio-day-2017" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">World Polio Day celebration</a> co-hosted by the Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Progress in fighting polio might be one of the world&rsquo;s best-kept secrets in global health,&rdquo; Microsoft co-founder and billionaire philanthropist Bill Gates <a href="https://www.gatesnotes.com/2017-Annual-Letter#ALChapter2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wrote in his foundation&rsquo;s 2017 annual letter</a>. &ldquo;If things stay stable in the conflicted areas, humanity will see its last case of polio this year.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The head of the foundation&rsquo;s polio eradication efforts, Dr. Jay Wenger, is hopeful that polio could indeed disappear by this year&rsquo;s end &mdash; two years earlier than <a href="https://futurism.com/bill-gates-we-are-closer-than-ever-before-to-totally-eradicating-polio/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">what Gates previously predicted</a>. &ldquo;What we&rsquo;re looking at now is sort of the endgame of polio eradication. We are closer than ever, and we&rsquo;re optimistic that we can see the end of wild poliovirus disease by as early as this year,&rdquo; he said, <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/tech/news/2017/10/24/bill-gates-polio-eradicated-year/795856001/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">as reported by </a><i><a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/tech/news/2017/10/24/bill-gates-polio-eradicated-year/795856001/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">USA Today</a></i>.</p>
<p></p>
<h2>A Victory for Vaccines</h2>
<p>Polio could very well be the second disease eradicated in our lifetime, next to smallpox. Dr. Wenger said that there are now only 12 cases of polio in the entire world, and all of them are found within two countries: Afghanistan and Pakistan. &ldquo;In the last couple of years, we&rsquo;ve seen unprecedented progress. In 2015 we could only find 74 cases; in 2016 we found 37, and then this year so far we&rsquo;ve found only 12 in only two countries.&rdquo;</p>
<p>This success comes from the unsung heroes that World Polio Day celebrates, those that have helped to spread the first safe and effective oral vaccine against polio, developed by Jonas Salk in 1955. The Global Polio Eradication Initiative, launched in 1988 by the World Health Assembly, has since reduced polio incidence by 99.9 percent. This mass vaccination campaign, supported by numerous institutions around the world, made this victory against polio possible.</p>
<p>The Gates Foundation pledged $450 million in June to continue supporting efforts against polio. &ldquo;You might be wondering why we&rsquo;re spending so much money when there&rsquo;s only 12 cases,&rdquo; Dr. Wenger said. &ldquo;We want to be sure we finish it off.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com/bill-gates-humanity-will-see-its-last-case-of-polio-this-year/" target="_blank">Bill Gates: &ldquo;Humanity Will See Its Last Case of Polio This Year&rdquo;</a> appeared first on <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com" target="_blank">Futurism</a>.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-25T22:01:42+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Dom Galeon</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://futurism.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://futurism.com"/>
		<updated>2017-10-25T22:01:42+00:00</updated>
		<title>Futurism</title></source>

	<category term="health &amp; medicine"/>

	<category term="bill gates"/>

	<category term="polio"/>

	<category term="vaccines"/>

	<category term="world polio day"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-25:/444932</id>
	<link href="https://futurism.com/scientists-used-genetic-modification-to-create-low-fat-pigs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Scientists Used Genetic Modification to Create Low-Fat Pigs</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Low-Fat Pigs
Chinese scientists have successfully used CRISPR to create twelve healthy pigs that hav...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Low-Fat Pigs</h2>
<p>Chinese scientists have <a href="https://futurism.com/crispr-is-on-the-cusp-of-eradicating-a-host-of-diseases/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">successfully used CRISPR</a> to create twelve healthy pigs that have around 24 percent less body fat than normal. The genetically modified low-fat pigs are still capable of maintaining a healthy body temperature, which could allow farmers to ensure the animals&rsquo; welfare without spending as much money on feeding them and keeping them warm.</p>
<p>Most mammals possess a gene known as UCP1, which allows an organisms to regulate its body temperature when it&rsquo;s cold by burning fat&ndash;but pigs don&rsquo;t. The scientists took the gene from a mouse and <a href="https://futurism.com/experts-cast-doubt-on-groundbreaking-crispr-embryo-editing-research/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">used CRISPR to introduce it</a> into pig cells. These cells were used to create in excess of 2,553 cloned pig embryos.</p>
<p></p>
<p>Embryos were then implanted into thirteen pigs, three of which became pregnant, giving birth to twelve male pigs. These animals were found to be completely healthy, and one even managed to mate and produce healthy offspring.</p>
<p>This study offers up a lot of utility for farmers, giving them a means of raising healthy pigs more cheaply than current methods allow. However, there&rsquo;s also a health benefit to people eating pork that is less fatty as a result of the genetic modification.</p>
<p>The next question is whether or not animals that have been modified in this way could ever be legally sold for human consumption.</p>
<h2>You Are What You Eat</h2>
<p>There are <a href="https://futurism.com/new-genetically-engineered-corn-could-revolutionize-our-agriculture/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">significant advantages to genetically modified foods</a>, ranging from practical benefits for farmers, to the fact that hardier crops could help produce sustenance for areas where malnutrition is common. However, the US and other countries have proven to be reticent about signing off on official approval.</p>
<p>&ldquo;I very much doubt that this particular pig will ever be imported into the USA&mdash;one thing&mdash;and secondly, whether it would ever be allowed to enter the food chain,&rdquo; said animal sciences professor R. Michael Roberts in <a href="http://www.npr.org/sections/thesalt/2017/10/23/559060166/crispr-bacon-chinese-scientists-create-genetically-modified-low-fat-pigs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">an interview with NPR</a>.&nbsp;<figure><a href="https://futurism.com/images/how-crispr-works-the-future-of-genetic-engineering/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><img src="https://futurism.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/Crispr-Cas-9.jpg" alt="How CRISPR Works: The Future of Genetic Engineering and Designer Humans"></a><figcaption><strong><a href="https://futurism.com/images/how-crispr-works-the-future-of-genetic-engineering/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Click to View Full Infographic</a></strong></figcaption></figure>
</p><p>This year, the first genetically modified salmon <a href="https://futurism.com/you-can-now-buy-genetically-engineered-salmon-in-canada/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">was sold in North America</a>, but gaining approval from the Food and Drug Administration was a process that took a quarter of a century. Unlike these pigs, the salmon were designed to be sterile, and it was still mandated that they had to be properly contained to avoid the risk of them contaminating natural populations of the fish.</p>
<p>Despite the fact that studies have demonstrated that genetically modified foods <a href="https://futurism.com/expansive-report-on-gm-crops-finds-they-are-safe-pose-no-health-risks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pose no health risks</a>, there&rsquo;s still a great deal of pushback against their production and sale. However, as projects like these low-fat pigs demonstrate the breadth of what can be achieved, we might see the general consensus begin to change.</p>
<p>If we&rsquo;re this anxious about modifying animals on a genetic level, it seems likely that we&rsquo;re a way off doing the same to humans&ndash;even though CRISPR could be <a href="https://futurism.com/scientists-just-used-gene-editing-to-remove-a-fatal-blood-disorder-from-human-embryos/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">used to great effect</a> if we did choose to tinker with our own genetic make-up.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com/scientists-used-genetic-modification-to-create-low-fat-pigs/" target="_blank">Scientists Used Genetic Modification to Create Low-Fat Pigs</a> appeared first on <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://futurism.com" target="_blank">Futurism</a>.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-25T21:50:21+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Brad Jones</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://futurism.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://futurism.com"/>
		<updated>2017-10-25T21:50:21+00:00</updated>
		<title>Futurism</title></source>

	<category term="hard science"/>

	<category term="crispr"/>

	<category term="food"/>

	<category term="genetically modified food"/>

	<category term="pigs"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-25:/444820</id>
	<link href="http://news.mit.edu/2017/researchers-engineer-crispr-edit-single-rna-letters-human-cells-1015" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Researchers engineer CRISPR to edit single RNA letters in human cells</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Broad Institute and MIT scientists who first harnessed CRISPR for mammalian genome editing have ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Broad Institute and MIT scientists who first harnessed CRISPR for mammalian genome editing have engineered a new molecular system for efficiently editing RNA in human cells. RNA editing, which can alter gene products without making changes to the genome, has profound potential as a tool for both research and disease treatment.</p>



<p>In a paper published today in <em>Science</em>, senior author Feng Zhang and his team describe the new CRISPR-based system, called RNA Editing for Programmable A to I Replacement, or &ldquo;REPAIR.&rdquo; The system can change single RNA nucleotides in mammalian cells in a programmable and precise fashion. REPAIR has the ability to reverse disease-causing mutations at the RNA level, as well as other potential therapeutic and basic science applications.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The ability to correct disease-causing mutations is one of the primary goals of genome editing,&rdquo; says Zhang, a core institute member of the Broad Institute, an investigator at the McGovern Institute, and the James and Patricia Poitras &rsquo;63 Professor in Neuroscience and associate professor in the departments of Brain and Cognitive Sciences and Biological Engineering at MIT. &ldquo;So far, we&rsquo;ve gotten very good at inactivating genes, but actually recovering lost protein function is much more challenging. This new ability to edit RNA opens up more potential opportunities to recover that function and treat many diseases, in almost any kind of cell.&rdquo;</p>



<p>REPAIR has the ability to target individual RNA letters, or nucleosides, switching adenosines to inosines (read as guanosines by the cell). These letters are involved in single-base changes known to regularly cause disease in humans. In human disease, a mutation from G to A is extremely common; these alterations have been implicated in, for example, cases of focal epilepsy, Duchenne muscular dystrophy, and Parkinson&rsquo;s disease. REPAIR has the ability to reverse the impact of any pathogenic G-to-A mutation regardless of its surrounding nucleotide sequence, with the potential to operate in any cell type.</p>



<p>Unlike the permanent changes to the genome required for DNA editing, RNA editing offers a safer, more flexible way to make corrections in the cell. &ldquo;REPAIR can fix mutations without tampering with the genome, and because RNA naturally degrades, it&rsquo;s a potentially reversible fix,&rdquo; explains co-first author David Cox, a graduate student in Zhang&rsquo;s lab.</p>



<p>To create REPAIR, the researchers systematically profiled the CRISPR-Cas13 enzyme family for potential &ldquo;editor&rdquo; candidates (unlike Cas9, the Cas13 proteins target and cut RNA). They selected an enzyme from <em>Prevotella</em> bacteria, called PspCas13b, which was the most effective at inactivating RNA. The team engineered a deactivated variant of PspCas13b that still binds to specific stretches of RNA but lacks its &ldquo;scissor-like&rdquo; activity, and fused it to a protein called ADAR2, which changes the letters A to I in RNA transcripts.</p>



<p>In REPAIR, the deactivated Cas13b enzyme seeks out a target sequence of RNA, and the ADAR2 element performs the base conversion without cutting the transcript or relying on any of the cell&rsquo;s native machinery.</p>



<p>The team further modified the editing system to improve its specificity, reducing detectable off-target edits from 18,385 to only 20 in the whole transcriptome. The upgraded incarnation, REPAIRv2, consistently achieved the desired edit in 20 to 40 percent &mdash; and up to 51 percent &mdash; of a targeted RNA without signs of significant off-target activity. &ldquo;The success we had engineering this system is encouraging, and there are clear signs REPAIRv2 can be evolved even further for more robust activity while still maintaining specificity,&rdquo; says Omar Abudayyeh, co-first author and a graduate student in Zhang&rsquo;s lab. Cox and Abudayyeh are both students in the Harvard-MIT Program in Health Sciences and Technology.</p>



<p>To demonstrate REPAIR&rsquo;s therapeutic potential, the team synthesized the pathogenic mutations that cause Fanconi anemia and X-linked nephrogenic diabetes insipidus, introduced them into human cells, and successfully corrected these mutations at the RNA level. To push the therapeutic prospects further, the team plans to improve REPAIRv2&rsquo;s efficiency and to package it into a delivery system appropriate for introducing REPAIRv2 into specific tissues in animal models.</p>



<p>The researchers are also working on additional tools for other types of nucleotide conversions. &ldquo;There&rsquo;s immense natural diversity in these enzymes,&rdquo; says co-first author Jonathan Gootenberg, a graduate student in both Zhang&rsquo;s lab and the lab of Broad core institute member Aviv Regev. &ldquo;We&rsquo;re always looking to harness the power of nature to carry out these changes.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Zhang, along with the Broad Institute and MIT, plans to share the REPAIR system widely. As with earlier CRISPR tools, the groups will make this technology freely available for academic research via the <a href="https://www.addgene.org/Feng_Zhang/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Zhang lab&rsquo;s page</a> on the plasmid-sharing website Addgene, through which the Zhang lab has already shared reagents more than 42,000 times with researchers at more than 2,200 labs in 61 countries, accelerating research around the world.</p>



<p>This research was funded, in part, by the National Institutes of Health and the Poitras Center for Affective Disorders Research.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-25T18:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Broad Institute</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://news.mit.edu/mitresearch-rss.xml</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://news.mit.edu/mitresearch-rss.xml"/>
		<updated>2017-10-25T18:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>MIT Research News</title></source>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image" 
		length="1"
		href="http://news.mit.edu/sites/mit.edu.newsoffice/files/styles/article_cover_image_original/public/images/2017/MIT-CrisprRNA.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-25:/444664</id>
	<link href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-10/kift-nso102517.php" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Navigation system of brain cells decoded</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Karlsruher Institut f&uuml;r Technologie (KIT) ) The human brain contains roughly 100 billion neurons. I...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(<i>Karlsruher Institut f&uuml;r Technologie (KIT) </i>) The human brain contains roughly 100 billion neurons. Information among them is transmitted via a complex network of nerve fibers. Hardwiring of most of this network takes place before birth according to a genetic blueprint, that is without external influences playing a role. Researchers of Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT) have now found out more about how the navigation system guiding the axons during growth works. This is reported in the eLife magazine.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-25T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.eurekalert.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.eurekalert.org"/>
		<updated>2017-10-25T04:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>EurekAlert! - Technology, Engineering and Computer Science</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-25:/444771</id>
	<link href="https://inhabitat.com/italy-seeks-to-phase-out-coal-power-plants-by-2025" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Italy seeks to phase out coal power plants by 2025</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nation by nation, Europe is going green. The latest country to prove its commitment to sustainable ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img fl:hint-main-image="true" src="https://inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/10/Italy-seeks-to-phase-out-all-coal-power-plants-2025-889x593.jpg" alt="Italy, Europe, sustainability, coal, power plant, geothermal, alternative energy, environment, politics, News, "></p>
<p>Nation by nation, <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/Europe" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Europe</a> is going green. The latest country to prove its commitment to sustainable solutions is <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/Italy" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Italy</a>. On Tuesday, the Italian Industry Minister announced that by 2025, the country plans to phase out <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/coal" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">coal</a> power plants. Additionally, the country plans to meet 27 percent of &ldquo;gross overall energy consumption&rdquo; with renewable sources by the year 2030.</p>
<p><img src="https://inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/10/Italy-seeks-to-phase-out-all-coal-power-plants-2025-889x593.jpg" alt="Italy, Europe, sustainability, coal, power plant, geothermal, alternative energy, environment, politics, News, "></p>
<p>During a parliamentary hearing, Minister <a href="https://energy.economictimes.indiatimes.com/tag/carlo+calenda" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Carlo Calenda</a> asked the national grid company to identify the infrastructure needed to make the transition. Shortly after, the country&rsquo;s biggest utility, Enel, said it will not invest in new coal-fired power plants.</p>
<p>Unlike other countries in Europe, Italy&rsquo;s renewable sector is constantly growing. In 2015, for instance, <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/renewable-energy" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">renewable energy </a>sources generated just under 38 percent of the country&rsquo;s electricity. Hydro-electrical plants remain the biggest contributor (15.5 percent), and solar and <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/wind" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">wind</a> sources have reached nearly 13 percent, according to <a href="https://www.zmescience.com/ecology/renewable-energy-ecology/italy-phases-out-coal-25102017/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">ZME Science.</a> The country has no nuclear plants, as they were banned through a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Italian_referendums,_1987" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">referendum in 1987</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/10/Italy-seeks-to-phase-out-all-coal-power-plants-2025-2-889x592.jpg" alt="Italy, Europe, sustainability, coal, power plant, geothermal, alternative energy, environment, politics, News, "></p>
<p><a href="https://inhabitat.com/supervolcano-in-italy-is-becoming-more-dangerous-as-magma-builds-beneath-the-surface/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Related: Supervolcano in Italy is &ldquo;becoming more dangerous&rdquo; as magma builds beneath the surface</a></p>
<p>Chris Littlecott, who heads a fossil fuel transition program at <a href="https://www.e3g.org/docs/The_Coal_Phase_Out_Transition_-_Italys_Leadership_Opportunity%2C_E3G%2C_April_2017.pdf" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">think tank E3G</a>, applauded the development. &ldquo;Italy&rsquo;s positive commitment to phase out coal by 2025 demonstrates real international leadership as it completes its year holding the G7 Presidency,&rdquo; he said in a statement. &ldquo;Italy now joins its G7 peers in Canada, France, and the <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/UK" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">UK</a> in taking action to phase out coal power generation over the next decade. Together, they can lead a growing coalition of countries and regions that are now acting on coal,&rdquo; he said.</p>
<p><img src="https://inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/10/Italy-seeks-to-phase-out-all-coal-power-plants-2025-3-889x609.jpg" alt="Italy, Europe, sustainability, coal, power plant, geothermal, alternative energy, environment, politics, News, "></p>
<p>Though this development is commendable, nothing has been confirmed just yet. The strategy should receive governmental and parliamentary approval at the beginning of November. If it passes, the measure will also speed up the introduction of vehicles powered by <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/sustainability" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">alternative fuels</a>, and it will raise the number of <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/electric" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">EV</a> charging stations to 19,000 by 2020.</p>
<p>Via <a href="https://www.zmescience.com/ecology/renewable-energy-ecology/italy-phases-out-coal-25102017/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">ZME Science</a></p>
<p><em>Images via <a href="http://www.publicdomainpictures.net/view-image.php?image=208876&amp;picture=sorrento-italy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Public Domain Pictures, </a><a href="http://www.pixabay.com" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Pixabay</a></em></p><div>
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Inhabitat?a=P-2seFhNL2I:gVzY_X4pb7c:yIl2AUoC8zA" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Inhabitat?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Inhabitat?a=P-2seFhNL2I:gVzY_X4pb7c:DLYy-l-dIDg" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Inhabitat?d=DLYy-l-dIDg" border="0"></a>
</div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-25T17:10:25+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Amanda Froelich</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://inhabitat.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://inhabitat.com"/>
		<updated>2017-10-25T17:10:25+00:00</updated>
		<title>Inhabitat - Sustainable Design Innovation, Eco Architecture, Green Building  green technology</title></source>

	<category term="energy"/>

	<category term="policy"/>

	<category term="wind power"/>

	<category term="solar power"/>

	<category term="energy efficiency"/>

	<category term="uk"/>

	<category term="sustainability"/>

	<category term="environment"/>

	<category term="renewable energy"/>

	<category term="electric"/>

	<category term="europe"/>

	<category term="italy"/>

	<category term="coal"/>

	<category term="politics"/>

	<category term="news"/>

	<category term="climate change"/>

	<category term="alternative energy"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-26:/445095</id>
	<link href="https://fossbytes.com/linux-kernel-development-contributer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Who Contributes To Linux Kernel? How Has Its Development Evolved In Past 26 Years?</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>ny discussion involving the open source software cannot be completed without the mention of Linux ke...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>ny discussion involving the open source software cannot be completed without the mention of Linux kernel. This collaborative effort has become one of the most popular and successful open source development projects. If we talk about the current state, the Linux operating system runs 90% of the public cloud, has 62% embedded market share, and [&hellip;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://fossbytes.com/linux-kernel-development-contributer/" target="_blank">Who Contributes To Linux Kernel? How Has Its Development Evolved In Past 26 Years?</a> appeared first on <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://fossbytes.com" target="_blank">Fossbytes</a>.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-26T09:04:45+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Adarsh Verma</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://fossbytes.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://fossbytes.com"/>
		<updated>2017-10-26T09:04:45+00:00</updated>
		<title>fossBytes  linux</title></source>

	<category term="geek"/>

	<category term="news"/>

	<category term="linux"/>

	<category term="linux foundation"/>

	<category term="linux kernel"/>

	<category term="linux kernel contributors"/>

	<category term="linux kernel development"/>

	<category term="open source"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-25:/444846</id>
	<link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2017/10/171025140509.htm" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Flu forecasting tool uses evolution to make earlier predictions</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new flu forecasting tool aims to make better predictions by combining data about how the virus spr...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new flu forecasting tool aims to make better predictions by combining data about how the virus spreads with an estimate of how much the current virus evolved compared to recent years. The new model accurately predicted the total number of cases for each season in the US from 2002 to 2016, and produced an accurate, real-time prediction for the 2016-17 season before it started last year.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-25T18:05:09+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-25T18:05:09+00:00</updated>
		<title>Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-25:/444678</id>
	<link href="https://inhabitat.com/saudi-arabia-announces-plan-for-500b-megacity-powered-by-renewables" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Saudi Arabia announces plan for $500B megacity powered by renewables</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Saudi Arabia just announced plans for a futuristic megacity that will span 10,000 square miles and ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img fl:hint-main-image="true" src="//inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/10/NEOM-Full-Width-Tall-889x298.jpg" alt="NEOM, Public Investment Fund of Saudi Arabia, Saudi Arabia, Discover NEOM, land, zone, environment, Jordan, Egypt, global hub, technology, green technology, future"></p>
<p><a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/saudi-arabia/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Saudi Arabia</a> just announced plans for a futuristic megacity that will span 10,000 square miles and three countries near the Red Sea. <a href="http://www.discoverneom.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">NEOM</a> will be an independent economic zone owned by the <a href="http://pif.gov.sa/Governance.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Public Investment Fund of Saudi Arabia</a> &ndash; and the nation is calling out to innovators, scientists, and dreamers to form an aspirational society to pioneer <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/future/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">next-gen</a> technologies. The future of <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/food/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">food</a>, <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/energy/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">energy</a>, and <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/biotechnology/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">biotechnology</a>, to name a few, will be explored in this global community to be backed by over $500 billion.</p>
<p><img src="//inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/10/NEOM-889x592.jpg" alt="NEOM, Public Investment Fund of Saudi Arabia, Saudi Arabia, Discover NEOM, land, zone, environment, Jordan, Egypt, global hub, technology, green technology, future"></p>
<p>NEOM will be the world&rsquo;s first independent economic zone &ndash; supported by Saudi Arabia&rsquo;s investment, but the country said it will be developed independently of their current governmental framework. They want to transform NEOM into a global hub to pursue innovation in nine investment sectors: advanced manufacturing, food, biotech, mobility, media, technological and digital sciences, entertainment, energy and <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/water/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">water</a>, and livability.</p>
<p><a href="https://inhabitat.com/the-worlds-first-tesla-town-with-solar-roofs-and-powerwalls-is-coming-to-australia/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Related: The world&rsquo;s first &ldquo;Tesla Town&rdquo; with solar roofs and Powerwalls is coming to Australia</a></p>
<p><img src="//inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/10/NEOM-Land-889x592.jpg" alt="NEOM, Public Investment Fund of Saudi Arabia, Saudi Arabia, Discover NEOM, land, zone, environment, Jordan, Egypt, global hub, technology, green technology, future"></p>
<p>Saudi Arabia crown prince Mohammed bin Salman said, &ldquo;Future technologies form the cornerstone for NEOM&rsquo;s development: disruptive solutions for <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/transportation/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">transportation</a> from automated driving to passenger drones, new ways of growing and processing food, healthcare centered around the patient for their holistic well-being, wireless high-speed Internet as a free good called digital air, free world-class continuous online education, full-scale e-governance putting city services at your fingertips, building codes that make <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/net-zero/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">net-zero</a> carbon houses the standard, a city layout that encourages walking and <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/bicycling/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">bicycling</a>, and all solely powered by <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/renewable-energy/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">renewable energy</a>.&rdquo;</p>
<p><img src="//inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2017/10/NEOM-Future-889x592.jpg" alt="NEOM, Public Investment Fund of Saudi Arabia, Saudi Arabia, Discover NEOM, land, zone, environment, Jordan, Egypt, global hub, technology, green technology, future"></p>
<p>NEOM will be located in Saudi Arabia, Jordan, and Egypt, in a region with mountains, beaches, and coral reefs. As Saudi Arabia seeks to <a href="https://www.thenational.ae/business/economy/saudi-arabia-unveils-500bn-investment-zone-spanning-three-countries-1.669930" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">diversify away from oil</a>, <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/solar-power/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">solar</a> and <a href="https://inhabitat.com/tag/wind-energy/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">wind energy</a> will help power NEOM.</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia has already started communicating with potential partners and investors, and the frequently asked questions document for NEOM said its first phase will be finished in 2025.</p>
<p><big><a href="http://www.discoverneom.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">+ NEOM</a></big></p>
<p>Via the <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/hrh-the-crown-prince-mohammed-bin-salman-announces-neom---the-destination-for-the-future-652706393.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Public Investment Fund of Saudi Arabia</a> and NEOM (<a href="http://www.discoverneom.com/content/pdfs/NEOM_BROCHURE_ENGLISH.pdf" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">1</a>,<a href="http://www.discoverneom.com/content/pdfs/NEOM_FAQS_ENGLISH.pdf" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">2</a>,<a href="http://www.discoverneom.com/content/pdfs/NEOM_INFOGRAPHIC_ENGLISH.pdf" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">3</a>)</p>
<p><em>Images via <a href="http://www.discoverneom.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">NEOM</a></em></p><div>
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Inhabitat?a=QMx7x4R-YMU:ObzapiCPSJs:yIl2AUoC8zA" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Inhabitat?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Inhabitat?a=QMx7x4R-YMU:ObzapiCPSJs:DLYy-l-dIDg" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Inhabitat?d=DLYy-l-dIDg" border="0"></a>
</div>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-25T15:41:48+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Lacy Cooke</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://inhabitat.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://inhabitat.com"/>
		<updated>2017-10-25T15:41:48+00:00</updated>
		<title>Inhabitat - Sustainable Design Innovation, Eco Architecture, Green Building  green technology</title></source>

	<category term="future"/>

	<category term="renewable energy"/>

	<category term="technology"/>

	<category term="green technology"/>

	<category term="saudi arabia"/>

	<category term="news"/>

	<category term="neom"/>

	<category term="public investment fund of saudi arabia"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-25:/444381</id>
	<link href="https://www.linuxfoundation.org/press-release/linux-foundation-releases-annual-kernel-development-report/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">The Linux Foundation Releases Annual Kernel Development Report</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Latest version of annual report demonstrates the continued growth in interest and participation in t...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><i><span>Latest version of annual report demonstrates the continued growth in interest and participation in the Linux kernel, as well as accelerating rate of change</span></i></p>
<p><b>PRAGUE (Open Source Summit Europe) &ndash; October 25, 2017 &ndash;</b> <a href="http://www.linuxfoundation.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><span>The Linux Foundation</span></a><span>, the nonprofit organization enabling mass innovation through open source, </span><span>today announced the immediate release of its </span><a href="https://www.linuxfoundation.org/2017-linux-kernel-report-landing-page/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><span>2017 Linux Kernel Development Report</span></a><span>. The report analyzes the work done by 15,600 developers over more than a decade, as well as more recent trends. </span></p>
<p><span>This is the eighth such report that is released on a roughly annual basis to help illustrate the Linux kernel development process and the work that defines the largest collaborative project in the history of computing. This year&rsquo;s paper covers work completed through Linux kernel 4.13, with an emphasis on releases 4.8 to 4.13. The last report was released in August 2016 and focused on 3.19 to 4.7.</span></p>
<p><span>Key findings from this year&rsquo;s paper include:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span>Roughly 15,600 developers from more than 1,400 companies have contributed to the Linux kernel </span><span>since the adoption of Git made detailed tracking possible</span><span>. Since the last report, over 4,300 developers from more than 500 companies have contributed to the kernel; 1,670 of these developers contributed for the first time, comprising about a third of contributors. </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><span>The Top 10 organizations sponsoring Linux kernel development since the last report include Intel, Red Hat, Linaro, IBM, Samsung, SUSE, Google, AMD, Renesas and Mellanox. The complete top 30 contributing organizations can be seen in the full report.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><span>The rate of Linux development continues to increase, as does the number of developers and companies involved in the process. The average number of changes accepted into the kernel per hour is 8.5, a significant increase from the 7.8 changes in the last report, which translates to 204 changes every day and over 1,400 per week. The average days of development per release increased slightly to 67.66 days from 66 last year, with every release spaced either 63 or 70 days apart, providing significant predictability. The 4.9 and 4.12 development cycles featured the highest patch rates ever seen in the history of the kernel project.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><span>The number of unpaid developers may be stabilizing, with these developers contributing 8.2% of contributions, a slight increase from 7.7% in last year&rsquo;s report. This is still significantly down from the 11.8% reported in 2014. This is likely due to kernel developers being in short supply, leading those who demonstrate the ability to submit quality patches to not have trouble finding job offers.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span>The report is co-authored by </span><span>Jonathan</span><span> Corbet, Linux kernel developer and editor of LWN.net, and Greg Kroah-Hartman, Linux kernel maintainer and Linux Foundation fellow. This year&rsquo;s report also features interviews with 17 Linux kernel developers and maintainers.</span></p>
<p><span>&ldquo;The incredible rates of contribution and participation in the Linux kernel demonstrate the continued strength and scalability of the kernel community,&rdquo; said Jim Zemlin, executive director of The Linux Foundation. &ldquo;This report provides important information that helps show how incredibly effective the collaborative development model can be for one of the most essential software projects in history.&rdquo;</span></p>
<p><span>To download the full report, please visit </span><a href="https://www.linuxfoundation.org/2017-linux-kernel-report-landing-page/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><span>https://www.linuxfoundation.org/2017-linux-kernel-report-landing-page/</span></a><span>. </span></p>
<p><span>The paper is being released today at the invitation-only Linux Kernel Summit, taking place alongside Open Source Summit Europe, hosted by The Linux Foundation. Open Source Summit is a technical conference where 2,000+ developers, operators, and community leadership professionals convene to collaborate, share information and learn about the latest in open technologies, including Linux, containers, cloud computing and more. The event combines the existing LinuxCon, ContainerCon and CloudOpen conferences with the all new Open Community Conference and Diversity Empowerment Summit. For more information and keynote session livestream, visit </span><a href="http://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/open-source-summit-europe/program/live-video-stream" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><span>http://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/open-source-summit-europe/program/live-video-stream</span></a><span>. </span></p>
<p><span>Additional Resources</span></p>
<p><span>Video: Greg Kroah-Hartman: Linux Kernel Development &ndash; </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mmu0pkSI5sw" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><span>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mmu0pkSI5sw</span></a></p>
<p><b>About The Linux Foundation</b></p>
<p><span>The Linux Foundation is the organization of choice for the world&rsquo;s top developers and companies to build ecosystems that accelerate open technology development and commercial adoption. Together with the worldwide open source community, it is solving the hardest technology problems by creating the largest shared technology investment in history. Founded in 2000, The Linux Foundation today provides tools, training and events to scale any open source project, which together deliver an economic impact not achievable by any one company. More information can be found at </span><a href="http://www.linuxfoundation.org" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><span>www.linuxfoundation.org</span></a><span>.</span></p>
<p><span># # #</span></p>
<p><i><span>The Linux Foundation has registered trademarks and uses trademarks. For a list of trademarks of The Linux Foundation, please see our trademark usage page:</span></i><a href="https://www.linuxfoundation.org/trademark-usage" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><i><span> https://www.linuxfoundation.org/trademark-usage</span></i></a><i><span>. Linux is a registered trademark of Linus Torvalds.</span></i></p>
<p>The post <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.linuxfoundation.org/press-release/linux-foundation-releases-annual-kernel-development-report/" target="_blank">The Linux Foundation Releases Annual Kernel Development Report</a> appeared first on <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.linuxfoundation.org" target="_blank">The Linux Foundation</a>.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-25T06:35:25+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Linux Foundation</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://www.linuxfoundation.org</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://www.linuxfoundation.org"/>
		<updated>2017-10-25T06:35:25+00:00</updated>
		<title>The Linux Foundation</title></source>

	<category term="linux foundation"/>

	<category term="press release"/>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-25:/444391</id>
	<link href="https://phys.org/news/2017-10-explore-affects-teeth-nanoscale.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Researchers explore how chewing affects teeth on the nanoscale</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Food leaves permanent traces on teeth. Cows chewing on grass, tigers tearing up a piece of raw meat ...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Food leaves permanent traces on teeth. Cows chewing on grass, tigers tearing up a piece of raw meat and humans munching on tortilla chips all end up with tiny scratches and nicks on the enamel of their teeth. Examining these marks on the microscale&mdash;what researchers call "microwear"&mdash;has led to new discoveries about the nature of teeth and the diet of our human ancestors.</p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-25T06:28:37+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>https://phys.org/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="https://phys.org/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-25T06:28:37+00:00</updated>
		<title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title></source>

	<category term="nanomaterials"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/generic" 
		length="1"
		href="https://3c1703fe8d.site.internapcdn.net/newman/csz/news/tmb/2017/36-researcherse.jpg"/>

</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-24:/444288</id>
	<link href="http://physicsworld.com/cws/article/news/2017/oct/24/photonic-nanostructures-bring-bees-to-flowers" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Photonic nanostructures bring bees to flowers</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Flash Physics: need-to-know updates from the world of physics</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Flash Physics: need-to-know updates from the world of physics<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/PhysicsWorld/~4/Wq4GP-uw9U8" height="1" width="1" alt=""></p>]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-24T13:00:36+00:00</updated>
	<author><name>Marric Stephens</name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://physicsworld.com/</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://physicsworld.com/"/>
		<updated>2017-10-24T13:00:36+00:00</updated>
		<title>physicsworld.com: all content</title></source>


</entry>

<entry>
	<id>tag:localhost,2017-10-24:/444107</id>
	<link href="http://www.renewableenergyworld.com/articles/2017/10/li-ion-tech-get-first-testing-platform-for-battery-lifetime.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<title type="html">Li-ion Tech Gets First Testing Platform for Battery Lifetime</title>
	<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>DNV GL yesterday said that it has created the first testing-based verification of battery lifetime f...</p>]]></summary>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>DNV GL yesterday said that it has created the first testing-based verification of battery lifetime for lithium-ion batteries.</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RenewableEnergyNewsRssFeed/~4/jOdwbMoSvag" height="1" width="1" alt="">]]></content>
	<updated>2017-10-24T16:46:00+00:00</updated>
	<author><name></name></author>
	<source>
		<id>http://www.renewableenergyworld.com</id>
		<link rel="self" href="http://www.renewableenergyworld.com"/>
		<updated>2017-10-24T16:46:00+00:00</updated>
		<title>Renewable Energy News RSS Feed</title></source>

	<category term="storage"/>

	<category term="news"/>


	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/png" 
		length="1"
		href="http://www.renewableenergyworld.com/content/rew/en/articles/2017/10/li-ion-tech-get-first-testing-platform-for-battery-lifetime/_jcr_content/leftcolumn/article/thumbnailimage.img.jpg"/>

	<link rel="enclosure" 
		type="image/png" 
		length="1"
		href="http://www.renewableenergyworld.com/content/rew/en/articles/2017/10/li-ion-tech-get-first-testing-platform-for-battery-lifetime/_jcr_content/leftcolumn/article/headerimage.img.jpg"/>

</entry>


</feed>
<!-- vim:ft=xml
	  -->
