<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-07-18T12:15:44+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">data-1.science</title><subtitle>Science and Technology Articles</subtitle><entry><title type="html">What Are Data Science and Machine Learning?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/what-are-data-science-and-machine-learning/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Are Data Science and Machine Learning?" /><published>2018-07-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-07-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/what-are-data-science-and-machine-learning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/what-are-data-science-and-machine-learning/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Machine learning, data science, and data analytics or scientists are emerging fields growing into various sub-fields, helping companies improve their efficiency and performance at certain stages during the operations and services. Hence, understanding these technologies is very important to realize their right use and benefits into various sectors. So, here we have discussed what data science is and what is machine learning with few sets of examples.        
What Is Data Science?…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dzone.com/articles/what-are-data-science-and-machine-learning?utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rohan Agrawal</name></author><summary type="html">Extract Machine learning, data science, and data analytics or scientists are emerging fields growing into various sub-fields, helping companies improve their efficiency and performance at certain stages during the operations and services. Hence, understanding these technologies is very important to realize their right use and benefits into various sectors. So, here we have discussed what data science is and what is machine learning with few sets of examples.         What Is Data Science?…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UK delivers super-cool kit to USA for Next-Generation Dark Matter Experiment</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/uk-delivers-super-cool-kit-to-usa-for-next-generation-dark-matter-experiment/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UK delivers super-cool kit to USA for Next-Generation Dark Matter Experiment" /><published>2018-07-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-07-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/uk-delivers-super-cool-kit-to-usa-for-next-generation-dark-matter-experiment</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/uk-delivers-super-cool-kit-to-usa-for-next-generation-dark-matter-experiment/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A huge U.K.-built titanium chamber designed to keep its contents at a cool -100C and weighing as much as an SUV has been shipped to the United States, where it will soon become part of a next-generation dark matter detector to hunt for the long-theorised elusive dark matter particle called a WIMP (Weakly Interacting Massive Particle)….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://phys.org/news/2018-07-uk-super-cool-kit-usa-next-generation.html&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="Weakly-interacting massive particles" /><category term="Large Underground Xenon experiment" /><category term="Dark matter" /><category term="Physics" /><category term="Matter" /><category term="Physical sciences" /><category term="Nature" /><category term="Particle physics" /><category term="Chemistry" /><category term="Applied and interdisciplinary physics" /><category term="Science" /><summary type="html">Extract A huge U.K.-built titanium chamber designed to keep its contents at a cool -100C and weighing as much as an SUV has been shipped to the United States, where it will soon become part of a next-generation dark matter detector to hunt for the long-theorised elusive dark matter particle called a WIMP (Weakly Interacting Massive Particle)….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Top 8 Deep Learning Frameworks</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/top-8-deep-learning-frameworks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Top 8 Deep Learning Frameworks" /><published>2018-07-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-07-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/top-8-deep-learning-frameworks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/top-8-deep-learning-frameworks/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;With more and more businesses looking to scale up their operations, it has become integral for them to imbibe both machine learning as well as predictive analytics. AI coupled with the right deep learning framework has truly amplified the overall scale of what businesses can achieve and obtain within their domains.
The machine learning paradigm is continuously evolving. The key is to shift towards developing machine learning models that run on mobile in order to make applications smarter and far more intelligent. Deep learning is what makes solving complex problems possible….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dzone.com/articles/8-best-deep-learning-frameworks?utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mitul Makadia</name></author><summary type="html">Extract With more and more businesses looking to scale up their operations, it has become integral for them to imbibe both machine learning as well as predictive analytics. AI coupled with the right deep learning framework has truly amplified the overall scale of what businesses can achieve and obtain within their domains. The machine learning paradigm is continuously evolving. The key is to shift towards developing machine learning models that run on mobile in order to make applications smarter and far more intelligent. Deep learning is what makes solving complex problems possible….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Future of Automated Testing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-future-of-automated-testing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Future of Automated Testing" /><published>2018-07-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-07-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-future-of-automated-testing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-future-of-automated-testing/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To gather insights for the current and future state of automated testing, we asked 31 executives from 27 companies, &quot;What’s the future of automated testing from your point of view - where do the greatest opportunities lie?&quot; Here’s what they told us:
AI/ML&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Distributed systems traceability as part of the testing cycle. How does the change in one component affect the behavior of other things? See this in cloud-native architecture. Quality of the code versus the quality of the network. Measurability of system behavior. 2) Systems that can leverage ML since there are more things to keep up with than a human can see. Compare to previous behavior and other known systems. 
 Testing is designed for AI/ML to build predictable…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dzone.com/articles/the-future-of-automated-testing?utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tom Smith</name></author><summary type="html">Extract To gather insights for the current and future state of automated testing, we asked 31 executives from 27 companies, &quot;What’s the future of automated testing from your point of view - where do the greatest opportunities lie?&quot; Here’s what they told us: AI/ML</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The big ethical questions for artificial intelligence in healthcare</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-big-ethical-questions-for-artificial-intelligence-in-healthcare/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The big ethical questions for artificial intelligence in healthcare" /><published>2018-07-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-07-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-big-ethical-questions-for-artificial-intelligence-in-healthcare</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-big-ethical-questions-for-artificial-intelligence-in-healthcare/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(Nuffield Council on Bioethics) AI in healthcare is developing rapidly, with many applications currently in use or in development in the UK and worldwide. The Nuffield Council on Bioethics examines the current and potential applications of AI in healthcare, and the ethical issues arising from its use, in a new briefing note, artificial intelligence (AI) in healthcare and research, published today….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2018-05/ncob-tbe051418.php&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="Artificial intelligence" /><category term="Health care" /><category term="Bioethics" /><category term="Medical ethics" /><category term="Nuffield Council on Bioethics" /><category term="Ethics" /><category term="Risk" /><category term="American Association for the Advancement of Science" /><category term="Research" /><category term="Health" /><category term="Human activities" /><category term="Medicine" /><category term="Science" /><summary type="html">Extract (Nuffield Council on Bioethics) AI in healthcare is developing rapidly, with many applications currently in use or in development in the UK and worldwide. The Nuffield Council on Bioethics examines the current and potential applications of AI in healthcare, and the ethical issues arising from its use, in a new briefing note, artificial intelligence (AI) in healthcare and research, published today….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Team develops new generation of artificial neural networks able to predict properties of organic compounds</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/team-develops-new-generation-of-artificial-neural-networks-able-to-predict-properties-of-organic-compounds/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Team develops new generation of artificial neural networks able to predict properties of organic compounds" /><published>2018-07-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-07-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/team-develops-new-generation-of-artificial-neural-networks-able-to-predict-properties-of-organic-compounds</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/team-develops-new-generation-of-artificial-neural-networks-able-to-predict-properties-of-organic-compounds/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Scientists from Russia, Estonia and the United Kingdom have created a new method for predicting the bioconcentration factor (BCF) of organic molecules. Leveraging the classical models of physicochemical interactions between the solvent and the solute and advanced machine learning methods, the new approach makes it possible to predict complex properties of a substance based on a minimum set of input data. The results of the study were published in Journal of Physics: Condensed Matter….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://phys.org/news/2018-07-team-artificial-neural-networks-properties.html&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="Solubility" /><category term="Solution" /><category term="Bioconcentration" /><category term="Machine learning" /><category term="Chemical substance" /><category term="Prediction" /><category term="Molecule" /><category term="Physics" /><category term="Chemistry" /><category term="Applied and interdisciplinary physics" /><category term="Nature" /><category term="Physical sciences" /><summary type="html">Extract Scientists from Russia, Estonia and the United Kingdom have created a new method for predicting the bioconcentration factor (BCF) of organic molecules. Leveraging the classical models of physicochemical interactions between the solvent and the solute and advanced machine learning methods, the new approach makes it possible to predict complex properties of a substance based on a minimum set of input data. The results of the study were published in Journal of Physics: Condensed Matter….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stephen Hawking reveals what existed before the Big Bang</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/stephen-hawking-reveals-what-existed-before-the-big-bang/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stephen Hawking reveals what existed before the Big Bang" /><published>2018-07-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-07-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/stephen-hawking-reveals-what-existed-before-the-big-bang</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/stephen-hawking-reveals-what-existed-before-the-big-bang/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In an interview with astrophysicist Neil deGrasse Tyson, iconic physicist Stephen Hawking recently revealed what he believes existed prior to the Big Bang. “Nothing was around,” said Hawking, who fortunately elaborated on this point. “The Euclidean space-time is a closed surface without end, like the surface of the Earth,” said Hawking, referring to the four-dimensional conceptual model that incorporates the three dimensions of space with time. “One can regard imaginary and real time as beginning at the South Pole, which is a smooth point of space-time where the normal laws of physics hold. There is nothing south of the South Pole so there was nothing around before the Big Bang.” At least, there was noth…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://inhabitat.com/stephen-hawking-reveals-what-existed-before-the-big-bang&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Greg Beach</name></author><category term="Time" /><category term="Stephen Hawking" /><category term="Space" /><category term="Physical quantities" /><category term="Metaphysics" /><category term="Science" /><category term="Physical sciences" /><category term="Spacetime" /><category term="Physics" /><summary type="html">Extract In an interview with astrophysicist Neil deGrasse Tyson, iconic physicist Stephen Hawking recently revealed what he believes existed prior to the Big Bang. “Nothing was around,” said Hawking, who fortunately elaborated on this point. “The Euclidean space-time is a closed surface without end, like the surface of the Earth,” said Hawking, referring to the four-dimensional conceptual model that incorporates the three dimensions of space with time. “One can regard imaginary and real time as beginning at the South Pole, which is a smooth point of space-time where the normal laws of physics hold. There is nothing south of the South Pole so there was nothing around before the Big Bang.” At least, there was noth…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Satellites, supercomputers, and machine learning provide real-time crop type data</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/satellites-supercomputers-and-machine-learning-provide-real-time-crop-type-data/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Satellites, supercomputers, and machine learning provide real-time crop type data" /><published>2018-07-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-07-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/satellites-supercomputers-and-machine-learning-provide-real-time-crop-type-data</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/satellites-supercomputers-and-machine-learning-provide-real-time-crop-type-data/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(University of Illinois College of Agricultural, Consumer and Environmental Sciences) Corn and soybean fields look similar from space – at least they used to. But now, scientists have proven a new technique for distinguishing the two crops using satellite data and the processing power of supercomputers….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2018-04/uoic-ssa040418.php&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="National Center for Supercomputing Applications" /><category term="Infrared" /><category term="American Association for the Advancement of Science" /><category term="Landsat program" /><category term="Technology" /><category term="Science and technology" /><summary type="html">Extract (University of Illinois College of Agricultural, Consumer and Environmental Sciences) Corn and soybean fields look similar from space – at least they used to. But now, scientists have proven a new technique for distinguishing the two crops using satellite data and the processing power of supercomputers….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Platform uses artificial intelligence to diagnose Zika and other pathogens</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/platform-uses-artificial-intelligence-to-diagnose-zika-and-other-pathogens/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Platform uses artificial intelligence to diagnose Zika and other pathogens" /><published>2018-07-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-07-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/platform-uses-artificial-intelligence-to-diagnose-zika-and-other-pathogens</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/platform-uses-artificial-intelligence-to-diagnose-zika-and-other-pathogens/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(Fundação de Amparo à Pesquisa do Estado de São Paulo) Method created in Brazil combines mass spectrometry analysis of blood serum with an algorithm that recognizes patterns associated with diseases from various origins. Adoption of machine learning technique allows the program to adapt itself to possible viral mutations….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2018-06/fda-pua061218.php&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="Zika fever" /><category term="Infection" /><category term="Virus" /><category term="Reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction" /><category term="Biomarker" /><category term="Research" /><category term="Biology" /><category term="Clinical medicine" /><category term="Medical specialties" /><category term="Life sciences" /><category term="Medicine" /><category term="Health sciences" /><summary type="html">Extract (Fundação de Amparo à Pesquisa do Estado de São Paulo) Method created in Brazil combines mass spectrometry analysis of blood serum with an algorithm that recognizes patterns associated with diseases from various origins. Adoption of machine learning technique allows the program to adapt itself to possible viral mutations….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">NYSCF researchers develop novel bioengineering technique for personalized bone grafts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/nyscf-researchers-develop-novel-bioengineering-technique-for-personalized-bone-grafts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NYSCF researchers develop novel bioengineering technique for personalized bone grafts" /><published>2018-07-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-07-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nyscf-researchers-develop-novel-bioengineering-technique-for-personalized-bone-grafts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/nyscf-researchers-develop-novel-bioengineering-technique-for-personalized-bone-grafts/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(New York Stem Cell Foundation) Scientists from the New York Stem Cell Foundation (NYSCF) Research Institute have developed a new bone engineering technique called Segmental Additive Tissue Engineering (SATE). The technique, described in a paper published online today in Scientific Reports, allows researchers to combine segments of bone engineered from stem cells to create large scale, personalized grafts that will enhance treatment for those suffering from bone disease or injury through regenerative medicine….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2018-07/nysc-nrd071718.php&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="Tissue engineering" /><category term="Bone" /><category term="Regenerative medicine" /><category term="Health" /><category term="Biotechnology" /><category term="Medicine" /><category term="Biology" /><category term="Health sciences" /><category term="Medical specialties" /><category term="Life sciences" /><category term="Clinical medicine" /><summary type="html">Extract (New York Stem Cell Foundation) Scientists from the New York Stem Cell Foundation (NYSCF) Research Institute have developed a new bone engineering technique called Segmental Additive Tissue Engineering (SATE). The technique, described in a paper published online today in Scientific Reports, allows researchers to combine segments of bone engineered from stem cells to create large scale, personalized grafts that will enhance treatment for those suffering from bone disease or injury through regenerative medicine….</summary></entry></feed>