<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-01-14T14:14:54+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">data-1.science</title><subtitle>Science and Technology Articles</subtitle><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2017-06-09-revolutionary-supercomputer-code-simulates-entire-cosmos-25-billion-virtual-galaxies.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2018-01-14T14:14:54+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-14T14:14:54+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2017-06-09-revolutionary-supercomputer-code-simulates-entire-cosmos-25-billion-virtual-galaxies</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2017-06-09-revolutionary-supercomputer-code-simulates-entire-cosmos-25-billion-virtual-galaxies.html">#### Extract
&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Over a period of three years, a group of astrophysicists from the University of Zurich has developed and optimised a revolutionary code to describe with unprecedented accuracy the dynamics of dark matter and the formation of large-scale structures in the Universe. From the data, researchers will obtain new information on the nature of this mysterious dark energy, but also hope to discover new physics beyond the standard model, such as a modified version of general relativity or a new type of particle. The researchers have simulated the formation of our entire Universe with a large supercomputer. A gigantic catalog of about 25 billion virtual galaxies has been generated from 2 trillion digital particles. This catalogue is being used to calibrate the experiments on board the Euclid satellite, that will be launched in 2020 with the objective of investigating the nature of dark matter and dark energy. The image below shows a section of the virtual universe, a billion light...

#### Factsheet
&gt;factsheet unavailable

[Visit Link](http://www.dailygalaxy.com/my_weblog/2017/06/-revolutionary-supercomputer-code-simulates-entire-cosmos-25-billion-virtual-galaxies.html)

id:  399823</content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-11-11-google-s-deepmind-ai-grasps-basic-laws-of-physics.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2018-01-14T14:14:54+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-14T14:14:54+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-11-11-google-s-deepmind-ai-grasps-basic-laws-of-physics</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-11-11-google-s-deepmind-ai-grasps-basic-laws-of-physics.html">#### Extract
&gt;     Google DeepMind’s artificial intelligence team, along with researchers at the University of California, Berkeley, has trained AI machines to interact with objects in order to evaluate their properties without any prior awareness of physical laws. The team set about various trials in different virtual environments in which the AI was faced with a series of blocks and tasked with assessing their properties. Advances in artificial intelligence have yielded intelligent machines that can achieve superhuman performance in Go, Atari, natural language processing, and complex control problems,but it is not clear that these systems can rival the scientific intuition of even a young child. The new reserach embraced the view in developmental science that human babies are endowed with a small number of separable systems of core knowledge for reasoning about objects, actions, number, space, and possibly social interactions. When encountering novel object, humans and other animals are able...

#### Factsheet
&gt;factsheet unavailable

[Visit Link](http://www.dailygalaxy.com/my_weblog/2016/11/googles-deepmind-ai-grasps-basic-laws-of-physics.html)

id:  340164</content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-11-08-radical-new-theory-of-gravity-an-emergent-phenomenon-not-a-fundamental-force-of-the-universe.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2018-01-14T14:14:54+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-14T14:14:54+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-11-08-radical-new-theory-of-gravity-an-emergent-phenomenon-not-a-fundamental-force-of-the-universe</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-11-08-radical-new-theory-of-gravity-an-emergent-phenomenon-not-a-fundamental-force-of-the-universe.html">#### Extract
&gt;     A new theory of gravity might explain the curious motions of stars in galaxies. Emergent gravity, as the new theory is called, predicts the exact same deviation of motions that is usually explained by invoking dark matter. Erik Verlinde, renowned expert in string theory at the University of Amsterdam and the Delta Institute for Theoretical Physics, published a new research paper today in which he expands his groundbreaking views on the nature of gravity. In 2010, Erik Verlinde surprised the world with a completely new theory of gravity. According to Verlinde, gravity is not a fundamental force of nature, but an emergent phenomenon. In the same way that temperature arises from the movement of microscopic particles, gravity emerges from the changes of fundamental bits of information, stored in the very structure of spacetime.    In his 2010 article (On the origin of gravity and the laws of Newton), Verlinde showed how Newton's famous second law, which describes how apples f...

#### Factsheet
&gt;factsheet unavailable

[Visit Link](http://www.dailygalaxy.com/my_weblog/2016/11/radical-new-theory-of-gravity-an-emergent-phenomenon-not-a-fundamental-force-of-the-universe.html)

id:  339217</content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-09-10-china-to-launch-spacelab-next-week-1st-step-toward-being-the-world-s-de-facto-space-station.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2018-01-14T14:14:54+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-14T14:14:54+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-09-10-china-to-launch-spacelab-next-week-1st-step-toward-being-the-world-s-de-facto-space-station</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-09-10-china-to-launch-spacelab-next-week-1st-step-toward-being-the-world-s-de-facto-space-station.html">#### Extract
&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; “The vast majority of space technology being developed is dual-use, and so serves Chinese security interests as well,&quot; says Johnson-Freese, an expert on the Chinese space program and a professor at the US Naval War College.&amp;nbsp;&quot;China understands the military advantages reaped by US space capabilities for many years, and wants those same capabilities”. China’s second orbiting spacelab Tiangong-2 and its carrier rocket, Long March 2F, were transferred to the launch pad yesterday at the Jiuquan Satellite Launch Center. China will launch its second spacelab &amp;nbsp;to test life support systems and refueling technology for its 60 ton modular space station. It will be visited in October by two astronauts aboard Shenzhou-11. The mission will bring China one step closer to the ultimate goal of its three-step human spaceflight program, a large, permanently inhabited space station. The future of the International Space Station (ISS) is in question and is not guaranteed to operate...

#### Factsheet
&gt;factsheet unavailable

[Visit Link](http://www.dailygalaxy.com/my_weblog/2016/09/chinas-spacelab-to-launch-next-week-1st-step-toward-a-perpetually-inhabited-space-station-as-the-wor.html)

id:  322549</content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-09-06-new-cern-lhc-experiments-predict-a-boson-beyond-the-higgs-that-could-unlock-clues-to-existence-of-dark-matter.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2018-01-14T14:14:54+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-14T14:14:54+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-09-06-new-cern-lhc-experiments-predict-a-boson-beyond-the-higgs-that-could-unlock-clues-to-existence-of-dark-matter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-09-06-new-cern-lhc-experiments-predict-a-boson-beyond-the-higgs-that-could-unlock-clues-to-existence-of-dark-matter.html">#### Extract
&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Two separate experiments at the Large Hadron Collider at the European Organisation for Nuclear Research, on the French-Swiss border, appear to confirm the existence of a subatomic particle, the Madala boson, that for the first time could shed light on one of the great mysteries of the universe - dark matter. The Madala boson follows the discovery of the Higgs boson in 2012 &quot;but the particles differ remarkably,&quot; said the team leader Bruce Mellado of South Africa's Witwatersrand University School of Physics. The Madala boson is heavier and disintegrates into the Higgs boson. &quot;The Higgs boson in the Standard Model of physics is not able to explain several things, such as dark matter,&quot; Mellado added. &quot;The Madala boson is important for our understanding of the universe. Through this we can communicate with dark matter - we don't have an object that can do that. This could be the first,&quot; said Mellado. The boson appears to interact with energy that cannot be explained. Mellado...

#### Factsheet
&gt;factsheet unavailable

[Visit Link](http://www.dailygalaxy.com/my_weblog/2016/09/new-cern-lhc-experiments-predict-a-boson-beyond-the-higgs-that-could-unlock-clues-to-dark-matter.html)

id:  320971</content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-08-24-china-unveils-plans-for-a-manned-radar-station-on-the-moon-leading-space-scientists-have-joined-the-project.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2018-01-14T14:14:54+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-14T14:14:54+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-08-24-china-unveils-plans-for-a-manned-radar-station-on-the-moon-leading-space-scientists-have-joined-the-project</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-08-24-china-unveils-plans-for-a-manned-radar-station-on-the-moon-leading-space-scientists-have-joined-the-project.html">#### Extract
&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; The Chinese government has unveiled plans to build a permanently manned radar station on the moon to monitor Earth. The project was launched earlier this year and received funding from the National Natural Science Foundation of China. The proposed facility, which may include quarters for astronauts and a powerful radar antenna array at least 50 meters high, could monitor wider areas of our planet than existing satellites, according to scientists involved in the study. The base, which would be used for scientific research and defense monitoring, could also produce more powerful and clearer images of earth as the high-frequency microwaves emitted by the radar station could not only penetrate cloud, but also the earth’s surface, allowing it to monitor areas on land, under the sea and underground. &amp;nbsp; Leading space scientists in China have joined the radar station project. The team held a two-day brainstorming session at the Fragrant Hill Hotel in Beijing last month. Tho...

#### Factsheet
&gt;factsheet unavailable

[Visit Link](http://www.dailygalaxy.com/my_weblog/2016/08/china-unveils-plans-for-a-manned-radar-station-on-the-moon-leading-space-scientists-have-joined-the-.html)

id:  317254</content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-07-12-earth-is-leaking-its-atmosphere-weakness-found-in-our-magnetic-field-european-space-agency.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2018-01-14T14:14:54+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-14T14:14:54+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-07-12-earth-is-leaking-its-atmosphere-weakness-found-in-our-magnetic-field-european-space-agency</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-07-12-earth-is-leaking-its-atmosphere-weakness-found-in-our-magnetic-field-european-space-agency.html">#### Extract
&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Earth's atmosphere is leaking. Every day, around 90 tons of material escapes from our planet's upper atmosphere and streams out into space. Although missions such as ESA's Cluster fleet have long been investigating this leakage, there are still many open questions. How and why is Earth losing its atmosphere – and how is this relevant in our hunt for life elsewhere in the Universe? &quot;The question of plasma transport and atmospheric loss is relevant for both planets and stars, and is an incredibly fascinating and important topic. Understanding how atmospheric matter escapes is crucial to understanding how life can develop on a planet,&quot; said Arnaud Masson, ESA's Deputy Project Scientist for the Cluster mission. &quot;The interaction between incoming and outgoing material in Earth's magnetosphere is a hot topic at the moment; where exactly is this stuff coming from? How did it enter our patch of space?&quot; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Given the expanse of our atmosphere, 90 tons per day am...

#### Factsheet
&gt;factsheet unavailable

[Visit Link](http://www.dailygalaxy.com/my_weblog/2016/07/-earth-is-losing-its-atmosphere-weakness-found-in-our-magnetic-field-european-space-agency.html)

id:  303340</content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-07-02-listen-jupiter-s-eerie-roar-as-juno-spacecraft-enters-gas-giant-s-magnetic-field-strongest-in-solar-system.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2018-01-14T14:14:54+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-14T14:14:54+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-07-02-listen-jupiter-s-eerie-roar-as-juno-spacecraft-enters-gas-giant-s-magnetic-field-strongest-in-solar-system</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-07-02-listen-jupiter-s-eerie-roar-as-juno-spacecraft-enters-gas-giant-s-magnetic-field-strongest-in-solar-system.html">#### Extract
&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Listen to Jupiter's strange voice as the robotic explorer moves into the magnetic field and enters into a polar orbit around the gas giant. &quot;We have over five years of spaceflight experience and only 10 days to Jupiter orbit insertion,&quot; said Rick Nybakken, Juno project manager from NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory in Pasadena, California. &quot;It is a great feeling to put all the interplanetary space in the rearview mirror and have the biggest planet in the solar system in our windshield.&quot; In three days, July 4th, the spacecraft Juno will arrive at Jupiter, the culmination of a five-year, billion-dollar journey. It's mission: to peer deep inside the gas giant and unravel its origin and evolution. One of the biggest mysteries surrounding Jupiter is how it generates its powerful magnetic field, the strongest in the solar system. &amp;nbsp; One theory is that about halfway to Jupiter's core, the pressures and temperatures become so intense that the hydrogen that makes up 90 perce...

#### Factsheet
&gt;factsheet unavailable

[Visit Link](http://www.dailygalaxy.com/my_weblog/2016/07/listen-jupiters-eerie-roar-as-juno-spacecraft-moves-into-orbit-weekend-audio-feature.html)

id:  301114</content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-06-30-create-your-own-neural-paintings-using-deep-learning.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2018-01-14T14:14:54+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-14T14:14:54+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-06-30-create-your-own-neural-paintings-using-deep-learning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-06-30-create-your-own-neural-paintings-using-deep-learning.html">#### Extract
&gt;Title:&amp;nbsp;Create Your Own &amp;quot;Neural Paintings&amp;quot; using Deep Learning30 JunLearn more...

#### Factsheet
&gt;factsheet unavailable

[Visit Link](https://www.linux.com/blog/create-your-own-neural-paintings-using-deep-learning)

id:  300698</content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-06-22-extreme-physics-nebula-observed-around-a-neutron-star-for-first-time.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2018-01-14T14:14:54+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-14T14:14:54+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-06-22-extreme-physics-nebula-observed-around-a-neutron-star-for-first-time</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/14/2016-06-22-extreme-physics-nebula-observed-around-a-neutron-star-for-first-time.html">#### Extract
&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Astronomers have discovered a vast cloud of high-energy particles called a wind nebula around a rare ultra-magnetic neutron star, or magnetar, for the first time. The find offers a unique window into the properties, environment and outburst history of magnetars, which are the strongest magnets in the universe. A neutron star is the crushed core of a massive star that ran out of fuel, collapsed under its own weight, and exploded as a supernova. Each one compresses the equivalent mass of half a million Earths into a ball just 12 miles (20 kilometers) across, or about the length of New York's Manhattan Island. Neutron stars are most commonly found as pulsars, which produce radio, visible light, X-rays and gamma rays at various locations in their surrounding magnetic fields. When a pulsar spins these regions in our direction, astronomers detect pulses of emission, hence the name. &amp;nbsp; The X-ray image above shows extended emission around a source known as Swi...

#### Factsheet
&gt;factsheet unavailable

[Visit Link](http://www.dailygalaxy.com/my_weblog/2016/06/extreme-physics-nebula-observed-around-a-neutron-star-for-first-time.html)

id:  297603</content><author><name></name></author></entry></feed>