<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-08-18T15:19:55+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">data-1.science</title><subtitle>Science and Technology Articles</subtitle><entry><title type="html">WSU researchers build alien ocean to test NASA outer space submarine</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/wsu-researchers-build-alien-ocean-to-test-nasa-outer-space-submarine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WSU researchers build alien ocean to test NASA outer space submarine" /><published>2018-08-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/wsu-researchers-build-alien-ocean-to-test-nasa-outer-space-submarine</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/wsu-researchers-build-alien-ocean-to-test-nasa-outer-space-submarine/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(Washington State University) Building a submarine gets tricky when the temperature drops to -300 Fahrenheit and the ocean is made of methane and ethane. Washington State University researchers are working with NASA to determine how a submarine might work on Titan, the largest of Saturn’s many moons and the second largest in the solar system. The space agency plans to launch a real submarine into Titan seas in the next 20 years….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2018-02/wsu-wrb020718.php&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="Titan (moon)" /><category term="Ocean" /><category term="Cryogenics" /><category term="Saturn" /><category term="Planetary science" /><category term="Nature" /><category term="Physical sciences" /><category term="Outer space" /><summary type="html">Extract (Washington State University) Building a submarine gets tricky when the temperature drops to -300 Fahrenheit and the ocean is made of methane and ethane. Washington State University researchers are working with NASA to determine how a submarine might work on Titan, the largest of Saturn’s many moons and the second largest in the solar system. The space agency plans to launch a real submarine into Titan seas in the next 20 years….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">World’s first ocean pollution-eating Seabin launches in the UK</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/world-s-first-ocean-pollution-eating-seabin-launches-in-the-uk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="World's first ocean pollution-eating Seabin launches in the UK" /><published>2018-08-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/world-s-first-ocean-pollution-eating-seabin-launches-in-the-uk</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/world-s-first-ocean-pollution-eating-seabin-launches-in-the-uk/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;UK waterways are about to get a lot cleaner with the launch of the world’s first production Seabin in Portsmouth harbor. The device, which was developed by a pair of Australian surfers, works by sucking in various kinds of pollution (including oil) and spitting out clean water. The Seabin can collect approximately 1.5 kg of waste each day and has a capacity of 12 kg — and in a given year, a single bin can collect 20,000 plastic bottles or 83,000 plastic bags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Seabin was first unveiled in December 2015. To fund the invention, founders Andrew Turton and Pete Ceglinski created an IndieGoGo campaign. With little time to spare, the campaign exceeded its goal. 
Equipped with $250,000, Turton and Ceglinski are now prepared to follow through…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://inhabitat.com/worlds-first-ocean-pollution-eating-seabin-launches-in-the-uk&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Amanda Froelich</name></author><category term="Natural environment" /><summary type="html">Extract UK waterways are about to get a lot cleaner with the launch of the world’s first production Seabin in Portsmouth harbor. The device, which was developed by a pair of Australian surfers, works by sucking in various kinds of pollution (including oil) and spitting out clean water. The Seabin can collect approximately 1.5 kg of waste each day and has a capacity of 12 kg — and in a given year, a single bin can collect 20,000 plastic bottles or 83,000 plastic bags.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">When Machine Learning Meets the Business World</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/when-machine-learning-meets-the-business-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When Machine Learning Meets the Business World" /><published>2018-08-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/when-machine-learning-meets-the-business-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/when-machine-learning-meets-the-business-world/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Businesses have always been at the forefront as early adopters of new technologies. Advancements in computing like Machine Learning have already made a notable impact on the business world. With business operations and processes spread across varying levels, the inclusion of a Machine Learning framework can prove worthwhile in increasing efficiency, productivity, and speed. 
Machine Learning has found widespread acceptance among enterprises. MIT Technology Review and Google Cloud recently published a report based on their studies in Machine Learning and its adoption. The reports state that about 60 percent of the respondents have already implemented Machine Learning into their business….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dzone.com/articles/when-machine-learning-meets-the-business-world?utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vinod Saratchandran</name></author><summary type="html">Extract Businesses have always been at the forefront as early adopters of new technologies. Advancements in computing like Machine Learning have already made a notable impact on the business world. With business operations and processes spread across varying levels, the inclusion of a Machine Learning framework can prove worthwhile in increasing efficiency, productivity, and speed. Machine Learning has found widespread acceptance among enterprises. MIT Technology Review and Google Cloud recently published a report based on their studies in Machine Learning and its adoption. The reports state that about 60 percent of the respondents have already implemented Machine Learning into their business….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Submarine volcanoes add to ocean soundscape</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/submarine-volcanoes-add-to-ocean-soundscape/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Submarine volcanoes add to ocean soundscape" /><published>2018-08-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/submarine-volcanoes-add-to-ocean-soundscape</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/submarine-volcanoes-add-to-ocean-soundscape/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Most volcanoes erupt beneath the ocean, but scientists know little about them compared to what they know about volcanoes that eject their lava on dry land. …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2017/12/171204091205.htm&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="Volcano" /><category term="Types of volcanic eruptions" /><category term="Submarine volcano" /><category term="Sound" /><category term="Nature" /><category term="Volcanology" /><category term="Earth sciences" /><category term="Applied and interdisciplinary physics" /><summary type="html">Extract Most volcanoes erupt beneath the ocean, but scientists know little about them compared to what they know about volcanoes that eject their lava on dry land. …</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Regulators vote to protect more corals in Atlantic Ocean</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/regulators-vote-to-protect-more-corals-in-atlantic-ocean/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Regulators vote to protect more corals in Atlantic Ocean" /><published>2018-08-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/regulators-vote-to-protect-more-corals-in-atlantic-ocean</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/regulators-vote-to-protect-more-corals-in-atlantic-ocean/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Federal fishing regulators on Tuesday approved a compromise they said would expand the amount of coral habitat preserved in the Atlantic Ocean while also protecting fishing interests….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://phys.org/news/2018-01-vote-corals-atlantic-ocean.html&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="Fishing" /><category term="Cancer vaccine" /><category term="Ecological niche" /><category term="Deep-water coral" /><category term="Georges Bank" /><category term="Evolution" /><category term="Coral" /><category term="Oceanography" /><summary type="html">Extract Federal fishing regulators on Tuesday approved a compromise they said would expand the amount of coral habitat preserved in the Atlantic Ocean while also protecting fishing interests….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Primordial oceans had oxygen 250 million years before the atmosphere</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/primordial-oceans-had-oxygen-250-million-years-before-the-atmosphere/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Primordial oceans had oxygen 250 million years before the atmosphere" /><published>2018-08-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/primordial-oceans-had-oxygen-250-million-years-before-the-atmosphere</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/primordial-oceans-had-oxygen-250-million-years-before-the-atmosphere/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(University of Minnesota) Research by a University of Minnesota Duluth (UMD) graduate student Mojtaba Fakhraee and Associate Professor Sergei Katsev has pushed a major milestone in the evolution of the Earth’s environment back by about 250 million years….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2018-01/uom-poh012418.php&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="Earth" /><category term="American Association for the Advancement of Science" /><category term="Oxygen" /><category term="Science" /><category term="Natural environment" /><category term="Ocean" /><category term="University of Minnesota Duluth" /><category term="Engineering" /><category term="Research" /><category term="Physical sciences" /><category term="Nature" /><summary type="html">Extract (University of Minnesota) Research by a University of Minnesota Duluth (UMD) graduate student Mojtaba Fakhraee and Associate Professor Sergei Katsev has pushed a major milestone in the evolution of the Earth’s environment back by about 250 million years….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Over 200 nations commit to ending ocean plastic waste</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/over-200-nations-commit-to-ending-ocean-plastic-waste/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Over 200 nations commit to ending ocean plastic waste" /><published>2018-08-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/over-200-nations-commit-to-ending-ocean-plastic-waste</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/over-200-nations-commit-to-ending-ocean-plastic-waste/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Over 200 countries just signed a United Nations resolution in Nairobi, Kenya to eliminate plastic waste in the world’s oceans. The resolution is an important step towards establishing a legally binding treaty that would deal with the plastic pollution problem afflicting the world’s oceans. According to the United Nations Environment Programme (UNEP), there will be more plastic by weight in the world’s oceans than fish by 2050 if current trends continue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The resolution offers hope for the future: “There is very strong language in this resolution,” said Vidar Helgesen, Norway’s environment minister, in an interview with Reuters. “We now have an agreement to explore a legally binding instrument and other measures and that …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://inhabitat.com/over-200-nations-commit-to-ending-ocean-plastic-waste&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Greg Beach</name></author><category term="Plastic pollution" /><category term="United Nations Environment Programme" /><category term="United Nations" /><summary type="html">Extract Over 200 countries just signed a United Nations resolution in Nairobi, Kenya to eliminate plastic waste in the world’s oceans. The resolution is an important step towards establishing a legally binding treaty that would deal with the plastic pollution problem afflicting the world’s oceans. According to the United Nations Environment Programme (UNEP), there will be more plastic by weight in the world’s oceans than fish by 2050 if current trends continue.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">OpenAI’s Robotic Hand Learned to Make Precise, Human-like Movements</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/openai-s-robotic-hand-learned-to-make-precise-human-like-movements/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OpenAI’s Robotic Hand Learned to Make Precise, Human-like Movements" /><published>2018-08-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/openai-s-robotic-hand-learned-to-make-precise-human-like-movements</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/openai-s-robotic-hand-learned-to-make-precise-human-like-movements/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In order to consistently perform with high-precision the robotic hand needs to be able to react to a variety of objects.
The post OpenAI’s Robotic Hand Learned to Make Precise, Human-like Movements appeared first on Futurism….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://futurism.com/videos/openai-robotic-hand/&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jacob Banas</name></author><category term="Artificial intelligence" /><category term="Technology" /><category term="Emerging technologies" /><category term="Cybernetics" /><category term="Futurology" /><category term="Computational neuroscience" /><category term="Cognitive science" /><category term="Areas of computer science" /><summary type="html">Extract In order to consistently perform with high-precision the robotic hand needs to be able to react to a variety of objects. The post OpenAI’s Robotic Hand Learned to Make Precise, Human-like Movements appeared first on Futurism….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On the way to plastic-free oceans</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/on-the-way-to-plastic-free-oceans/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On the way to plastic-free oceans" /><published>2018-08-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/on-the-way-to-plastic-free-oceans</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/on-the-way-to-plastic-free-oceans/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Four days since leaving port, Dr. Katsiaryna Pabortsava reaches her destination. She’s in the middle of the North Atlantic, thousands of miles from land, and she’s looking for microplastics….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://phys.org/news/2018-01-plastic-free-oceans.html&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="Microplastics" /><category term="Microbead" /><category term="Sea" /><category term="Sustainability" /><category term="Natural environment" /><category term="Earth sciences" /><category term="Nature" /><category term="Environmental science" /><summary type="html">Extract Four days since leaving port, Dr. Katsiaryna Pabortsava reaches her destination. She’s in the middle of the North Atlantic, thousands of miles from land, and she’s looking for microplastics….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ocean acidification research makes a strong case for limiting climate change</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ocean-acidification-research-makes-a-strong-case-for-limiting-climate-change/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ocean acidification research makes a strong case for limiting climate change" /><published>2018-08-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ocean-acidification-research-makes-a-strong-case-for-limiting-climate-change</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ocean-acidification-research-makes-a-strong-case-for-limiting-climate-change/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Experiments and analyses carried out by more than 250 scientists from 20 German institutions clearly indicate that ocean acidification and warming, along with other environmental stressors, impair life in the ocean. A brochure summarises major outcomes of the project for policymakers and the public. Members of the project Biological Impacts of Ocean Acidification (BIOACID) will also be present at the United Nations climate change conference COP23 in Bonn….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://phys.org/news/2017-10-ocean-acidification-strong-case-limiting.html&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="Ocean acidification" /><category term="Global warming" /><category term="Carbon dioxide" /><category term="Greenhouse gas" /><category term="Nature" /><category term="Physical geography" /><category term="Earth sciences" /><category term="Natural environment" /><category term="Oceanography" /><category term="Environmental science" /><summary type="html">Extract Experiments and analyses carried out by more than 250 scientists from 20 German institutions clearly indicate that ocean acidification and warming, along with other environmental stressors, impair life in the ocean. A brochure summarises major outcomes of the project for policymakers and the public. Members of the project Biological Impacts of Ocean Acidification (BIOACID) will also be present at the United Nations climate change conference COP23 in Bonn….</summary></entry></feed>