<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-05-26T11:18:46+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">data-1.science</title><subtitle>Science and Technology Articles</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Lung-on-a-chip simulates pulmonary fibrosis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lung-on-a-chip-simulates-pulmonary-fibrosis/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lung-on-a-chip simulates pulmonary fibrosis" /><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lung-on-a-chip-simulates-pulmonary-fibrosis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lung-on-a-chip-simulates-pulmonary-fibrosis/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(University at Buffalo) New biotechnology reported in the journal Nature Communications could make testing potential medicine for pulmonary fibrosis, one of the most common and serious forms of lung disease, quicker and less expensive. The innovation, lung-on-a-chip technology, relies on the same technology used to print electronic chips, photolithography….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2018-05/uab-lsp052518.php&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="Lung" /><category term="Pulmonary fibrosis" /><category term="Pulmonary alveolus" /><category term="Biotechnology" /><category term="Medicine" /><category term="Pirfenidone" /><category term="Health" /><category term="Clinical medicine" /><category term="Life sciences" /><category term="Biology" /><category term="Health sciences" /><summary type="html">Extract (University at Buffalo) New biotechnology reported in the journal Nature Communications could make testing potential medicine for pulmonary fibrosis, one of the most common and serious forms of lung disease, quicker and less expensive. The innovation, lung-on-a-chip technology, relies on the same technology used to print electronic chips, photolithography….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Faster genome evolution methods to transform yeast for industrial biotechnology</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/faster-genome-evolution-methods-to-transform-yeast-for-industrial-biotechnology/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Faster genome evolution methods to transform yeast for industrial biotechnology" /><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/faster-genome-evolution-methods-to-transform-yeast-for-industrial-biotechnology</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/faster-genome-evolution-methods-to-transform-yeast-for-industrial-biotechnology/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(Chinese Academy of Sciences Headquarters) A research team led by Professor DAI Junbiao at the Shenzhen Institutes of Advanced Technology (SIAT) of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, in collaboration with Professor Patrick Cai from the Manchester Institute of Biotechnology, developed a ‘rapid, efficient and universal’ way of transforming yeast at the molecular level using a method called SCRaMbLE (Synthetic Chromosome Rearrangement and Modification by LoxP-mediated Evolution)….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2018-05/caos-fge052518.php&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="Yeast" /><category term="Evolution" /><category term="Saccharomyces cerevisiae" /><category term="Genome" /><category term="Biotechnology" /><category term="Life sciences" /><category term="Biology" /><category term="Organisms" /><category term="Genetics" /><category term="Molecular biology" /><summary type="html">Extract (Chinese Academy of Sciences Headquarters) A research team led by Professor DAI Junbiao at the Shenzhen Institutes of Advanced Technology (SIAT) of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, in collaboration with Professor Patrick Cai from the Manchester Institute of Biotechnology, developed a ‘rapid, efficient and universal’ way of transforming yeast at the molecular level using a method called SCRaMbLE (Synthetic Chromosome Rearrangement and Modification by LoxP-mediated Evolution)….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to measure the impact of your open source project</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/how-to-measure-the-impact-of-your-open-source-project/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to measure the impact of your open source project" /><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/how-to-measure-the-impact-of-your-open-source-project</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/how-to-measure-the-impact-of-your-open-source-project/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This article was co-authored by Don Marti, Georg Link, Matt Germonprez, and Sean Goggins.
Conventional metrics of open source projects lack the power to predict their impact. The bad news is, there is no significant correlation between open source activity metrics and project impact. The good news? There are paths forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;read more…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.com/article/18/5/metrics-project-success&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vinod Kumar Ahuja</name></author><category term="Open-source software" /><category term="JQuery" /><category term="Bootstrap (front-end framework)" /><category term="Software" /><category term="H-index" /><category term="Software quality" /><category term="Library (computing)" /><category term="Technology" /><category term="Communication" /><category term="Computing" /><summary type="html">Extract This article was co-authored by Don Marti, Georg Link, Matt Germonprez, and Sean Goggins. Conventional metrics of open source projects lack the power to predict their impact. The bad news is, there is no significant correlation between open source activity metrics and project impact. The good news? There are paths forward.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Open Source AI: Projects, Insights, and Trends</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/open-source-ai-projects-insights-and-trends/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Open Source AI: Projects, Insights, and Trends" /><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/open-source-ai-projects-insights-and-trends</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/open-source-ai-projects-insights-and-trends/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;		Open Source AI: Projects, Insights, and Trends

	


		 
	
 

	  

	
		
			

	
		The Linux Foundation surveyed 16 popular open source AI projects – looking in depth at their histories, codebases, and GitHub contributions. Our conclusion? Building the right community around your open source AI project is critical to its success. Here’s why:
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incubators work. We identify several examples of projects that have benefited dramatically from joining an incubator.
Community governance matters. Open source projects with more diverse contributor patterns last longer and are more likely to survive when a major contributor changes strategy.
Consolidation is happening. We discuss several examples of projects that …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxfoundation.org/publications/open-source-ai-projects-insights-and-trends/&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>The Linux Foundation</name></author><category term="Artificial intelligence" /><summary type="html">Extract Open Source AI: Projects, Insights, and Trends</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Quantum effects observed in photosynthesis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/quantum-effects-observed-in-photosynthesis/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quantum effects observed in photosynthesis" /><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/quantum-effects-observed-in-photosynthesis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/quantum-effects-observed-in-photosynthesis/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(University of Groningen) Molecules that are involved in photosynthesis exhibit the same quantum effects as non-living matter, concludes an international team of scientists including University of Groningen theoretical physicist Thomas la Cour Jansen. This is the first time that quantum mechanical behavior was proven to exist in biological systems that are involved in photosynthesis. The interpretation of these quantum effects in photosynthesis may help in the development of nature-inspired light-harvesting devices. The results were published in Nature Chemistry….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2018-05/uog-qeo051818.php&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="Quantum mechanics" /><category term="Schrdingers cat" /><category term="Molecule" /><category term="Fenna-Matthews-Olson complex" /><category term="Scientific method" /><category term="Physics" /><category term="Condensed matter physics" /><category term="Scientific theories" /><category term="Science" /><category term="Applied and interdisciplinary physics" /><category term="Theoretical physics" /><category term="Particle physics" /><category term="Chemistry" /><category term="Solid state engineering" /><category term="Modern physics" /><category term="Mechanics" /><category term="Physical sciences" /><summary type="html">Extract (University of Groningen) Molecules that are involved in photosynthesis exhibit the same quantum effects as non-living matter, concludes an international team of scientists including University of Groningen theoretical physicist Thomas la Cour Jansen. This is the first time that quantum mechanical behavior was proven to exist in biological systems that are involved in photosynthesis. The interpretation of these quantum effects in photosynthesis may help in the development of nature-inspired light-harvesting devices. The results were published in Nature Chemistry….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Quantum Dots Synthesized From Tea Leaves Could Be The Future Of Nanomedicine</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/quantum-dots-synthesized-from-tea-leaves-could-be-the-future-of-nanomedicine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quantum Dots Synthesized From Tea Leaves Could Be The Future Of Nanomedicine" /><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/quantum-dots-synthesized-from-tea-leaves-could-be-the-future-of-nanomedicine</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/quantum-dots-synthesized-from-tea-leaves-could-be-the-future-of-nanomedicine/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We now have a clean, cheap way of manufacturing quantum dots, an advanced, microscopic tool that scientists are learning how to use to enhance everything from solar panels to cancer treatments. All they needed was green tea leaf extract, along with a couple other chemicals.
But let’s back up, because that’s a lot to take in. Quantum dots are a kind of nanoparticle that span from two to five nanometers. For reference, the antibodies that your immune system uses to swarm harmful viruses or bacteria are ten nanometers wide, and a human hair is about 40,000 nanometers wide. Lately, researchers have been trying to find new ways of using them in biomedical research and other advanced nanotechnology that requires the smallest possible particles.
I…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://futurism.com/cheap-quantum-dots-synthesized-tea-leaves-future-nanomedicine/&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dan Robitzski</name></author><category term="Camellia sinensis" /><category term="Quantum dot" /><category term="Cancer" /><category term="Biology" /><category term="Chemistry" /><summary type="html">Extract We now have a clean, cheap way of manufacturing quantum dots, an advanced, microscopic tool that scientists are learning how to use to enhance everything from solar panels to cancer treatments. All they needed was green tea leaf extract, along with a couple other chemicals. But let’s back up, because that’s a lot to take in. Quantum dots are a kind of nanoparticle that span from two to five nanometers. For reference, the antibodies that your immune system uses to swarm harmful viruses or bacteria are ten nanometers wide, and a human hair is about 40,000 nanometers wide. Lately, researchers have been trying to find new ways of using them in biomedical research and other advanced nanotechnology that requires the smallest possible particles. I…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Computer redesigns enzyme</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/computer-redesigns-enzyme/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Computer redesigns enzyme" /><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/computer-redesigns-enzyme</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/computer-redesigns-enzyme/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(University of Groningen) University of Groningen biotechnologists used a computational method to redesign aspartase and convert it to a catalyst for asymmetric hydroamination reactions. Their colleagues in China scaled up the production of this enzyme and managed to produce kilograms of very pure building blocks for pharmaceuticals and other bioactive compounds. This successful proof of principle study was published in Nature Chemical Biology on May 21….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2018-05/uog-cre051718.php&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="Enzyme" /><category term="Catalysis" /><category term="Chemical biology" /><category term="Protein" /><category term="Protein design" /><category term="Life sciences" /><category term="Biotechnology" /><category term="Biochemistry" /><category term="Molecular biology" /><category term="Physical sciences" /><category term="Biology" /><category term="Chemistry" /><summary type="html">Extract (University of Groningen) University of Groningen biotechnologists used a computational method to redesign aspartase and convert it to a catalyst for asymmetric hydroamination reactions. Their colleagues in China scaled up the production of this enzyme and managed to produce kilograms of very pure building blocks for pharmaceuticals and other bioactive compounds. This successful proof of principle study was published in Nature Chemical Biology on May 21….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Orange Takes Leading Role in 5G with Help of LFN</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/orange-takes-leading-role-in-5g-with-help-of-lfn/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Orange Takes Leading Role in 5G with Help of LFN" /><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/orange-takes-leading-role-in-5g-with-help-of-lfn</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/orange-takes-leading-role-in-5g-with-help-of-lfn/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As a  leading global telecommunications company, Orange understands the importance of 5G in today’s networks. The company announced 5G trials in France for 2018 and aims to deliver an operational 5G network by 2020. This is no small feat when looking at Orange’s 273M customers worldwide, including 152,000 employees. Orange also has wireless deployments in 13 countries, 46 million 4G customers worldwide, over 4.7M fibre customers and 450,000 km of undersea cable. One of the largest telecoms operators in Europe, the bulk of Orange’s operations expand through Europe, Africa and the Middle East.
In order to efficiently accomplish its aggressive 5G goals by 2020, Orange has opted to leverage new SDN and NFV technologies to improve agility and re…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxfoundation.org/networking-orchestration/orange-takes-leading-role-in-5g-with-help-of-lfn/&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>The Linux Foundation</name></author><category term="Network function virtualization" /><category term="5G" /><category term="Orange SA" /><category term="Digital technology" /><category term="Telecommunications" /><category term="Computing" /><category term="Networks" /><category term="Communication" /><category term="Science and technology" /><category term="Artificial objects" /><category term="Intellectual works" /><category term="Electronics" /><category term="Computer networking" /><category term="Technology" /><summary type="html">Extract As a  leading global telecommunications company, Orange understands the importance of 5G in today’s networks. The company announced 5G trials in France for 2018 and aims to deliver an operational 5G network by 2020. This is no small feat when looking at Orange’s 273M customers worldwide, including 152,000 employees. Orange also has wireless deployments in 13 countries, 46 million 4G customers worldwide, over 4.7M fibre customers and 450,000 km of undersea cable. One of the largest telecoms operators in Europe, the bulk of Orange’s operations expand through Europe, Africa and the Middle East. In order to efficiently accomplish its aggressive 5G goals by 2020, Orange has opted to leverage new SDN and NFV technologies to improve agility and re…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The First 10 Years of Software Defined Networking</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-first-10-years-of-software-defined-networking/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The First 10 Years of Software Defined Networking" /><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-first-10-years-of-software-defined-networking</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-first-10-years-of-software-defined-networking/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Wendy Cartee, Nick McKeown, Guru Parulkar, and Chris Wright discuss the first 10 years of software defined networking at Open Networking Summit North America.
In 2008, if you wanted to build a network, you had to build it from the same switch and router equipment that everyone else had, according to Nick McKeown, co-founder of Barefoot Networks, speaking as part of a panel of networking experts at Open Networking Summit North America.  
Equipment was closed, proprietary, and vertically integrated with features already baked in, McKeown noted. And, “network management was a dirty word. If you wanted to manage a network of switches, you had to write your own scripts over a lousy, cruddy CLI, and everybody had their own way of doing it in orde…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxfoundation.org/blog/the-first-10-years-of-software-defined-networking/&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Esther Shein</name></author><category term="Software-defined networking" /><category term="Computer network" /><category term="OpenFlow" /><category term="Open-source model" /><category term="Nick McKeown" /><category term="Computer networking" /><category term="Areas of computer science" /><category term="Information technology" /><category term="Intellectual works" /><category term="Computers" /><category term="Telecommunications" /><category term="Computing" /><category term="Computer engineering" /><category term="Computer architecture" /><category term="Digital technology" /><category term="Technology" /><summary type="html">Extract Wendy Cartee, Nick McKeown, Guru Parulkar, and Chris Wright discuss the first 10 years of software defined networking at Open Networking Summit North America. In 2008, if you wanted to build a network, you had to build it from the same switch and router equipment that everyone else had, according to Nick McKeown, co-founder of Barefoot Networks, speaking as part of a panel of networking experts at Open Networking Summit North America.  Equipment was closed, proprietary, and vertically integrated with features already baked in, McKeown noted. And, “network management was a dirty word. If you wanted to manage a network of switches, you had to write your own scripts over a lousy, cruddy CLI, and everybody had their own way of doing it in orde…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Open Source AI For Everyone: Three Projects to Know</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/open-source-ai-for-everyone-three-projects-to-know/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Open Source AI For Everyone: Three Projects to Know" /><published>2018-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/open-source-ai-for-everyone-three-projects-to-know</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/open-source-ai-for-everyone-three-projects-to-know/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We look at three open source AI projects aimed at simplifying access to AI tools and insights.
At the intersection of open source and artificial intelligence, innovation is flourishing, and companies ranging from Google to Facebook to IBM are open sourcing AI and machine learning tools. 
According to research from IT Intelligence Markets, the global artificial intelligence software market is expected to reach 13.89 billion USD by the end of 2022. However, talk about AI has accelerated faster than actual deployments. According to a detailed McKinsey report on the growing impact of AI, “only about 20 percent of AI-aware companies are currently using one or more of its technologies in a core business process or at scale.” Here, we look at thre…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxfoundation.org/blog/open-source-ai-for-everyone-three-projects-to-know/&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sam Dean</name></author><category term="Artificial intelligence" /><category term="Open-source model" /><category term="Apache Spark" /><category term="Machine learning" /><category term="TensorFlow" /><category term="Amazon Web Services" /><category term="Areas of computer science" /><category term="Digital technology" /><category term="Computing" /><category term="Information technology" /><category term="Software" /><category term="Computer science" /><category term="Technology" /><summary type="html">Extract We look at three open source AI projects aimed at simplifying access to AI tools and insights. At the intersection of open source and artificial intelligence, innovation is flourishing, and companies ranging from Google to Facebook to IBM are open sourcing AI and machine learning tools. According to research from IT Intelligence Markets, the global artificial intelligence software market is expected to reach 13.89 billion USD by the end of 2022. However, talk about AI has accelerated faster than actual deployments. According to a detailed McKinsey report on the growing impact of AI, “only about 20 percent of AI-aware companies are currently using one or more of its technologies in a core business process or at scale.” Here, we look at thre…</summary></entry></feed>