<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-05-01T14:16:44+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">data-1.science</title><subtitle>Science and Technology Articles</subtitle><entry><title type="html">NOAA’s Mission Toward Open Data Sharing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/noaa-s-mission-toward-open-data-sharing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NOAA’s Mission Toward Open Data Sharing" /><published>2018-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/noaa-s-mission-toward-open-data-sharing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/noaa-s-mission-toward-open-data-sharing/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;NOAA is working to make all of its data available to an even wider group of people and make it more easily understood (Image: NOAA).
The goal of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) is to put all of its data — data about weather, climate, ocean coasts, fisheries, and ecosystems – into the hands of the people who need it most. The trick is translating the hard data and making it useful to people who aren’t necessarily subject matter experts, said Edward Kearns, the NOAA’s first ever data officer, speaking at the recent Open Source Leadership Summit (OSLS).  
NOAA’s mission is similar to NASA’s in that it is science based, but “our mission is operations; to get the quality information to the American people t…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxfoundation.org/blog/noaas-mission-toward-open-data-sharing/&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Esther Shein</name></author><category term="National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration" /><category term="World Meteorological Organization" /><category term="Computing" /><category term="Technology" /><summary type="html">Extract NOAA is working to make all of its data available to an even wider group of people and make it more easily understood (Image: NOAA). The goal of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) is to put all of its data — data about weather, climate, ocean coasts, fisheries, and ecosystems – into the hands of the people who need it most. The trick is translating the hard data and making it useful to people who aren’t necessarily subject matter experts, said Edward Kearns, the NOAA’s first ever data officer, speaking at the recent Open Source Leadership Summit (OSLS).   NOAA’s mission is similar to NASA’s in that it is science based, but “our mission is operations; to get the quality information to the American people t…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Datanami: Linux Foundation Launches Open AI Effort</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/datanami-linux-foundation-launches-open-ai-effort/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Datanami: Linux Foundation Launches Open AI Effort" /><published>2018-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/datanami-linux-foundation-launches-open-ai-effort</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/datanami-linux-foundation-launches-open-ai-effort/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The Linux Foundation launched a deep learning initiative this week designed to create a “neutral space for harmonization and acceleration” of AI, machine learning and deep learning technologies. The initial focus will be an AI standardization effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read More
The post Datanami: Linux Foundation Launches Open AI Effort appeared first on The Linux Foundation….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxfoundation.org/news/eweek-linux-foundation-deep-learning-advance-ai-usage-5/&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gracie Gregory</name></author><summary type="html">Extract The Linux Foundation launched a deep learning initiative this week designed to create a “neutral space for harmonization and acceleration” of AI, machine learning and deep learning technologies. The initial focus will be an AI standardization effort.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SpaceChain, Arch Aim to Archive Human Knowledge in Space</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spacechain-arch-aim-to-archive-human-knowledge-in-space/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SpaceChain, Arch Aim to Archive Human Knowledge in Space" /><published>2018-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spacechain-arch-aim-to-archive-human-knowledge-in-space</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spacechain-arch-aim-to-archive-human-knowledge-in-space/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;		SpaceChain has entered a partnership with the Arch Mission Foundation to use open source technology to launch an ambitious project involving the storage of large data sets in spacecraft and on other planets. Arch Mission will load large quantities of data onto SpaceChain's satellite vehicles with the eventual aim of storing data on other planets. &quot;The goal of archiving and preserving knowledge of future generations will advance archiving science and human knowledge by itself,&quot; SpaceChain cofounder Zheng Zuo said.
		
		...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linuxinsider.com/story/85196.html?rss=1&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>David Jones</name></author><summary type="html">Extract SpaceChain has entered a partnership with the Arch Mission Foundation to use open source technology to launch an ambitious project involving the storage of large data sets in spacecraft and on other planets. Arch Mission will load large quantities of data onto SpaceChain's satellite vehicles with the eventual aim of storing data on other planets. &quot;The goal of archiving and preserving knowledge of future generations will advance archiving science and human knowledge by itself,&quot; SpaceChain cofounder Zheng Zuo said. ...</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Microsoft Gives Devs More Open Source Quantum Computing Goodies</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/microsoft-gives-devs-more-open-source-quantum-computing-goodies/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Microsoft Gives Devs More Open Source Quantum Computing Goodies" /><published>2018-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/microsoft-gives-devs-more-open-source-quantum-computing-goodies</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/microsoft-gives-devs-more-open-source-quantum-computing-goodies/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;		Microsoft has announced the first major upgrade to its Quantum Development Kit since its introduction last year. It has added several new features designed to open the platform to a wider array of developers, including support for Linux and macOS, as well as additional open source libraries. Further, the kit will be interoperable with the Python computing language. Microsoft announced the Quantum Development Kit at its Ignite conference last fall. It launched the free preview about three months later, featuring the new Q# programming language.
		
		...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linuxinsider.com/story/85173.html?rss=1&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>David Jones</name></author><summary type="html">Extract Microsoft has announced the first major upgrade to its Quantum Development Kit since its introduction last year. It has added several new features designed to open the platform to a wider array of developers, including support for Linux and macOS, as well as additional open source libraries. Further, the kit will be interoperable with the Python computing language. Microsoft announced the Quantum Development Kit at its Ignite conference last fall. It launched the free preview about three months later, featuring the new Q# programming language. ...</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">9 Best Linux Distros For Programming And Developers (2018 Edition)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/9-best-linux-distros-for-programming-and-developers-2018-edition/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="9 Best Linux Distros For Programming And Developers (2018 Edition)" /><published>2018-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/9-best-linux-distros-for-programming-and-developers-2018-edition</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/9-best-linux-distros-for-programming-and-developers-2018-edition/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;inux-based operating systems are often used by developers to get their work done and create something new. Their major concerns while choosing a Linux distro for programming are compatibility, power, stability, and flexibility. Distros like Ubuntu and Debian have managed to establish themselves as the top picks. Some of the other great choices are openSUSE, Arch […]
The post 9 Best Linux Distros For Programming And Developers (2018 Edition) appeared first on Fossbytes….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fossbytes.com/best-linux-distros-for-programming-developers/&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adarsh Verma</name></author><category term="Linux distribution" /><category term="Red Hat Enterprise Linux" /><category term="CentOS" /><category term="Fedora (operating system)" /><category term="Ubuntu (operating system)" /><category term="Arch Linux" /><category term="OpenSUSE" /><category term="Debian" /><category term="Finnish computer programmers" /><category term="Software distribution" /><category term="Finnish computer scientists" /><category term="Linux kernel programmers" /><category term="Computer engineering" /><category term="Linux kernel" /><category term="Computers" /><category term="Operating system families" /><category term="Open-source movement" /><category term="Operating system technology" /><category term="Linux Foundation" /><category term="Linux people" /><category term="Free software projects" /><category term="Unix variants" /><category term="Free software distributions" /><category term="Linux distributions" /><category term="Free software" /><category term="System software" /><category term="Linus Torvalds" /><category term="Linux" /><category term="Computing" /><category term="Software" /><summary type="html">Extract inux-based operating systems are often used by developers to get their work done and create something new. Their major concerns while choosing a Linux distro for programming are compatibility, power, stability, and flexibility. Distros like Ubuntu and Debian have managed to establish themselves as the top picks. Some of the other great choices are openSUSE, Arch […] The post 9 Best Linux Distros For Programming And Developers (2018 Edition) appeared first on Fossbytes….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nvidia Containerizes GPU-Accelerated Deep Learning</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/nvidia-containerizes-gpu-accelerated-deep-learning/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nvidia Containerizes GPU-Accelerated Deep Learning" /><published>2018-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nvidia-containerizes-gpu-accelerated-deep-learning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/nvidia-containerizes-gpu-accelerated-deep-learning/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;		We often talk about hybrid cloud business models, but virtually always in the context of traditional processor-bound applications. What if deep learning developers and service operators could run their GPU-accelerated model training or inference delivery service anywhere they wanted? What if they could do so without having to worry about which Nvidia graphics processor unit they were using, whether their software development environment was complete, or whether their development environment had all the latest updates?
		
		...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linuxinsider.com/story/84928.html?rss=1&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Paul Teich</name></author><summary type="html">Extract We often talk about hybrid cloud business models, but virtually always in the context of traditional processor-bound applications. What if deep learning developers and service operators could run their GPU-accelerated model training or inference delivery service anywhere they wanted? What if they could do so without having to worry about which Nvidia graphics processor unit they were using, whether their software development environment was complete, or whether their development environment had all the latest updates? ...</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Open Source Program at Microsoft: How Open Source Thrives</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-open-source-program-at-microsoft-how-open-source-thrives/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Open Source Program at Microsoft: How Open Source Thrives" /><published>2018-04-29T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-open-source-program-at-microsoft-how-open-source-thrives</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-open-source-program-at-microsoft-how-open-source-thrives/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Open source is a thriving part of Microsoft’s global works. And, the company’s open source journey has been neither as abrupt nor unexpected as it may have appeared.
Microsoft is now an accepted big player in the open source space, but just a few years ago such a role for the software giant, seemed inconceivable. Many people were thus surprised when Microsoft emerged from its market lead as a proprietary software maker to make a move towards open source in a big way. Although the company’s story is remarkable, its open source journey has been neither as abrupt nor unexpected as it may have appeared. 
“Despite perception, Microsoft has been doing open source for quite a while. At first, it was experimental pieces here and there but abo…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxfoundation.org/blog/open-source-program-microsoft-open-source-thrives/&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pam Baker</name></author><category term="Open-source model" /><category term="GitHub" /><category term="Microsoft" /><category term="Software" /><category term="Computing" /><category term="Technology" /><summary type="html">Extract Open source is a thriving part of Microsoft’s global works. And, the company’s open source journey has been neither as abrupt nor unexpected as it may have appeared. Microsoft is now an accepted big player in the open source space, but just a few years ago such a role for the software giant, seemed inconceivable. Many people were thus surprised when Microsoft emerged from its market lead as a proprietary software maker to make a move towards open source in a big way. Although the company’s story is remarkable, its open source journey has been neither as abrupt nor unexpected as it may have appeared. “Despite perception, Microsoft has been doing open source for quite a while. At first, it was experimental pieces here and there but abo…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">FSF News: Free Software Foundation releases FY2016 Annual Report</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/fsf-news-free-software-foundation-releases-fy2016-annual-report/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FSF News: Free Software Foundation releases FY2016 Annual Report" /><published>2018-04-29T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/fsf-news-free-software-foundation-releases-fy2016-annual-report</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/fsf-news-free-software-foundation-releases-fy2016-annual-report/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;BOSTON, Massachusetts, USA – Wednesday, February 28, 2018 – The Free Software
Foundation (FSF) today published its Fiscal Year (FY) 2016 Annual Report.
The report is available in low-resolution (11.5 MB PDF) and
high-resolution (207.2 MB PDF).
The Annual Report reviews the Foundation’s activities,
accomplishments, and financial picture from October 1, 2015 to
September 30, 2016. It is the result of a full external financial
audit, along with a focused study of program results. It examines the
impact of the FSF’s programs, and FY2016’s major events, including
LibrePlanet, the creation of ethical criteria for code-hosting
repositories, and the expansion of the Respects Your Freedom computer
hardware product certification program.
“More pe…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fsf.org/news/free-software-foundation-releases-fy2016-annual-report&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><summary type="html">Extract BOSTON, Massachusetts, USA – Wednesday, February 28, 2018 – The Free Software Foundation (FSF) today published its Fiscal Year (FY) 2016 Annual Report. The report is available in low-resolution (11.5 MB PDF) and high-resolution (207.2 MB PDF). The Annual Report reviews the Foundation’s activities, accomplishments, and financial picture from October 1, 2015 to September 30, 2016. It is the result of a full external financial audit, along with a focused study of program results. It examines the impact of the FSF’s programs, and FY2016’s major events, including LibrePlanet, the creation of ethical criteria for code-hosting repositories, and the expansion of the Respects Your Freedom computer hardware product certification program. “More pe…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Free Software Foundation releases FY2016 Annual Report</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/free-software-foundation-releases-fy2016-annual-report/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Free Software Foundation releases FY2016 Annual Report" /><published>2018-04-29T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/free-software-foundation-releases-fy2016-annual-report</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/free-software-foundation-releases-fy2016-annual-report/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;BOSTON, Massachusetts, USA – Wednesday, February 28, 2018 – The Free Software
Foundation (FSF) today published its Fiscal Year (FY) 2016 Annual Report.
The report is available in low-resolution (11.5 MB PDF) and
high-resolution (207.2 MB PDF).
The Annual Report reviews the Foundation’s activities,
accomplishments, and financial picture from October 1, 2015 to
September 30, 2016. It is the result of a full external financial
audit, along with a focused study of program results. It examines the
impact of the FSF’s programs, and FY2016’s major events, including
LibrePlanet, the creation of ethical criteria for code-hosting
repositories, and the expansion of the Respects Your Freedom computer
hardware product certification program.
“More peop…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fsf.org/news/free-software-foundation-releases-fy2016-annual-report&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="Free Software Foundation" /><category term="Free software" /><category term="Digital media" /><category term="Applied ethics" /><category term="Intellectual property activism" /><category term="Communication" /><category term="Open content" /><category term="Software" /><category term="Computing" /><category term="Open-source movement" /><category term="Free content" /><category term="Intellectual works" /><category term="Public commons" /><summary type="html">Extract BOSTON, Massachusetts, USA – Wednesday, February 28, 2018 – The Free Software Foundation (FSF) today published its Fiscal Year (FY) 2016 Annual Report. The report is available in low-resolution (11.5 MB PDF) and high-resolution (207.2 MB PDF). The Annual Report reviews the Foundation’s activities, accomplishments, and financial picture from October 1, 2015 to September 30, 2016. It is the result of a full external financial audit, along with a focused study of program results. It examines the impact of the FSF’s programs, and FY2016’s major events, including LibrePlanet, the creation of ethical criteria for code-hosting repositories, and the expansion of the Respects Your Freedom computer hardware product certification program. “More peop…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Automotive Grade Linux Kicks Off Open Source Speech Recognition and Vehicle-to-Cloud Connectivity</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/automotive-grade-linux-kicks-off-open-source-speech-recognition-and-vehicle-to-cloud-connectivity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Automotive Grade Linux Kicks Off Open Source Speech Recognition and Vehicle-to-Cloud Connectivity" /><published>2018-04-29T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/automotive-grade-linux-kicks-off-open-source-speech-recognition-and-vehicle-to-cloud-connectivity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/automotive-grade-linux-kicks-off-open-source-speech-recognition-and-vehicle-to-cloud-connectivity/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Led by Amazon Alexa, Nuance and Voicebox Technologies, the AGL Speech Expert Group is developing open APIs to voice-enable every application in the vehicle
SAN FRANCISCO, Feb. 28, 2018 – Automotive Grade Linux (AGL), a collaborative cross-industry effort developing an open platform for the connected car, today announced the launch of two new Expert Groups (EG) focused on Speech Recognition and Vehicle-to-Cloud (V2C) connectivity. 
“Our goal is to voice-enable every application in the vehicle, but the challenge today is that developers have to manually integrate with each automaker’s preferred speech recognition engine,” said Dan Cauchy, Executive Director of Automotive Grade Linux at The Linux Foundation. “We plan to provide a standard set …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxfoundation.org/press-release/automotive-grade-linux-kicks-off-open-source-speech-recognition-vehicle-cloud-connectivity/&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Linux Foundation</name></author><category term="Linux Foundation" /><category term="Technology" /><category term="Computing" /><category term="Artificial objects" /><category term="Intellectual works" /><summary type="html">Extract Led by Amazon Alexa, Nuance and Voicebox Technologies, the AGL Speech Expert Group is developing open APIs to voice-enable every application in the vehicle SAN FRANCISCO, Feb. 28, 2018 – Automotive Grade Linux (AGL), a collaborative cross-industry effort developing an open platform for the connected car, today announced the launch of two new Expert Groups (EG) focused on Speech Recognition and Vehicle-to-Cloud (V2C) connectivity. “Our goal is to voice-enable every application in the vehicle, but the challenge today is that developers have to manually integrate with each automaker’s preferred speech recognition engine,” said Dan Cauchy, Executive Director of Automotive Grade Linux at The Linux Foundation. “We plan to provide a standard set …</summary></entry></feed>