<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-03-30T17:14:20+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">data-1.science</title><subtitle>Science and Technology Articles</subtitle><entry><title type="html">SpaceX’s rocket to Mars blasts off, puts sports car in space</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spacex-s-rocket-to-mars-blasts-off-puts-sports-car-in-space/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SpaceX's rocket to Mars blasts off, puts sports car in space" /><published>2018-03-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-03-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spacex-s-rocket-to-mars-blasts-off-puts-sports-car-in-space</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spacex-s-rocket-to-mars-blasts-off-puts-sports-car-in-space/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Falcon Heavy became the most powerful rocket in use today, doubling the liftoff punch of its closest competitor. …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/technology/spacexs-rocket-to-mars-blasts-off-puts-sports-car-in-space/article22673997.ece?utm_source=RSS_Feed&amp;amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;amp;utm_campaign=RSS_Syndication&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>AP</name></author><category term="Featured" /><summary type="html">Extract Falcon Heavy became the most powerful rocket in use today, doubling the liftoff punch of its closest competitor. …</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Watch Live as the World’s Most Powerful Rocket Prepares for Liftoff</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/watch-live-as-the-world-s-most-powerful-rocket-prepares-for-liftoff/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Watch Live as the World’s Most Powerful Rocket Prepares for Liftoff" /><published>2018-03-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-03-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/watch-live-as-the-world-s-most-powerful-rocket-prepares-for-liftoff</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/watch-live-as-the-world-s-most-powerful-rocket-prepares-for-liftoff/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;SpaceX is conducting a test flight of its most powerful rocket to date. The Falcon Heavy is twice as powerful as any rocket operating on Earth and outmatched in power only by one rocket in history.
The post Watch Live as the World’s Most Powerful Rocket Prepares for Liftoff appeared first on Futurism….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://futurism.com/videos/watch-live-worlds-most-powerful-rocket-prepares-liftoff/&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jacob Banas</name></author><summary type="html">Extract SpaceX is conducting a test flight of its most powerful rocket to date. The Falcon Heavy is twice as powerful as any rocket operating on Earth and outmatched in power only by one rocket in history. The post Watch Live as the World’s Most Powerful Rocket Prepares for Liftoff appeared first on Futurism….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rocket Lab Has Successfully Launched Its Electron Rocket Into Orbit</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/rocket-lab-has-successfully-launched-its-electron-rocket-into-orbit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rocket Lab Has Successfully Launched Its Electron Rocket Into Orbit" /><published>2018-03-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-03-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/rocket-lab-has-successfully-launched-its-electron-rocket-into-orbit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/rocket-lab-has-successfully-launched-its-electron-rocket-into-orbit/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Rocket Race
The United States-based space flight startup, Rocket Lab, launched its Electron rocket for a second time on January 21, 2018. The launch successfully deployed three small commercial satellites — each the size of a loaf of bread — into orbit in just eight and a half minutes after liftoff.
Peter Beck, Rocket Lab’s CEO, said in a statement: “Rocket Lab was founded on the principle of opening access to space to better understand our planet and improve life on it. Today we took a significant step towards that.”
Rocket Lab is hoping to carve out a niche in a satellite launch market dominated by companies like SpaceX. But SpaceX launches that use a Falcon 9 rocket — which tends to have a larger payload — can cost up to $60 millio…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://futurism.com/rocket-lab-successfully-launched-electron-rocket-orbit/&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Patrick Caughill</name></author><summary type="html">Extract Rocket Race The United States-based space flight startup, Rocket Lab, launched its Electron rocket for a second time on January 21, 2018. The launch successfully deployed three small commercial satellites — each the size of a loaf of bread — into orbit in just eight and a half minutes after liftoff. Peter Beck, Rocket Lab’s CEO, said in a statement: “Rocket Lab was founded on the principle of opening access to space to better understand our planet and improve life on it. Today we took a significant step towards that.” Rocket Lab is hoping to carve out a niche in a satellite launch market dominated by companies like SpaceX. But SpaceX launches that use a Falcon 9 rocket — which tends to have a larger payload — can cost up to $60 millio…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Galileo liftoff replay</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/galileo-liftoff-replay/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Galileo liftoff replay" /><published>2018-03-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-03-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/galileo-liftoff-replay</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/galileo-liftoff-replay/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;	Rewatch the liftoff of Galileo satellites 19–22 by Ariane 5 from Europe's Spaceport in French Guiana on 12 December
...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.esa.int/spaceinvideos/Videos/2017/12/Galileo_19-22_-_liftoff_replay&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="Featured" /><summary type="html">Extract Rewatch the liftoff of Galileo satellites 19–22 by Ariane 5 from Europe's Spaceport in French Guiana on 12 December ...</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Spaceport prepares</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spaceport-prepares/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spaceport prepares" /><published>2018-03-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-03-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spaceport-prepares</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spaceport-prepares/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;	The Ariane 6 launch zone is taking shape at Europe's Spaceport in French Guiana, preparing for liftoff in July 2020
...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.esa.int/ESA_Multimedia/Videos/2017/11/Ariane_6_-_a_reality_in_Kourou&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="Featured" /><summary type="html">Extract The Ariane 6 launch zone is taking shape at Europe's Spaceport in French Guiana, preparing for liftoff in July 2020 ...</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Watch Live As SpaceX Launches the Koreasat-5A on a Falcon 9 Rocket</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/watch-live-as-spacex-launches-the-koreasat-5a-on-a-falcon-9-rocket/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Watch Live As SpaceX Launches the Koreasat-5A on a Falcon 9 Rocket" /><published>2018-03-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-03-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/watch-live-as-spacex-launches-the-koreasat-5a-on-a-falcon-9-rocket</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/watch-live-as-spacex-launches-the-koreasat-5a-on-a-falcon-9-rocket/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Today, SpaceX is planning to launch the Koreasat-5A communications satellite from Launch Complex 39A (LC-39A) at NASA’s Kennedy Space Center in Florida. Takeoff is set for 3:34 p.m. EDT. A backup launch window opens on Tuesday, October 31 at 3:34 p.m. EDT. The satellite will be deployed approximately 36 minutes after liftoff.
The post Watch Live As SpaceX Launches the Koreasat-5A on a Falcon 9 Rocket appeared first on Futurism….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://futurism.com/videos/watch-spacex-launch-koreasat-falcon-rocket/&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jolene Creighton</name></author><category term="Featured" /><summary type="html">Extract Today, SpaceX is planning to launch the Koreasat-5A communications satellite from Launch Complex 39A (LC-39A) at NASA’s Kennedy Space Center in Florida. Takeoff is set for 3:34 p.m. EDT. A backup launch window opens on Tuesday, October 31 at 3:34 p.m. EDT. The satellite will be deployed approximately 36 minutes after liftoff. The post Watch Live As SpaceX Launches the Koreasat-5A on a Falcon 9 Rocket appeared first on Futurism….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stephen Hawking, 1942–2018</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/stephen-hawking-1942-2018/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stephen Hawking, 1942–2018" /><published>2018-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/stephen-hawking-1942-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/stephen-hawking-1942-2018/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Stephen Hawking, renowned physicist, famed science communicator, and all-around inspiration, has passed away at the age of 76.
The post Stephen Hawking, 1942–2018 appeared first on Sky &amp;amp; Telescope….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.skyandtelescope.com/astronomy-news/stephen-hawking-1942-2018/&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Monica Young</name></author><category term="Black hole" /><category term="Hawking radiation" /><category term="Stephen Hawking" /><category term="Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis" /><category term="Physical sciences" /><category term="Physical cosmology" /><category term="Physics" /><category term="Mechanics" /><category term="Featured" /><summary type="html">Extract Stephen Hawking, renowned physicist, famed science communicator, and all-around inspiration, has passed away at the age of 76. The post Stephen Hawking, 1942–2018 appeared first on Sky &amp;amp; Telescope….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Understanding Shared Libraries in Linux</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/understanding-shared-libraries-in-linux/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Understanding Shared Libraries in Linux" /><published>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/understanding-shared-libraries-in-linux</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/understanding-shared-libraries-in-linux/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;digest&quot;&gt;Digest&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In programming, a library is an assortment of pre-compiled pieces of code that can be reused in a program. Libraries simplify life for programmers, in that they provide reusable functions, routines, classes, data structures and so on (written by a another programmer), which they can use in their programs. For instance, if you are building an application that needs to perform math operations, you don’t have to create a new math function for that, you can simply use existing functions in libraries for that programming language. Examples of libraries in Linux include libc (the standard C library) or glibc (GNU version of the standard C library), libcurl (multiprotocol file transfer library), libcrypt (library used for encryption, hashing, and encoding in C) and many more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;factsheet&quot;&gt;Factsheet&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In programming, a library is an assortment of pre-compiled pieces of code that can be reused in a program. Libraries simplify life for programmers, in that they provide reusable functions, routines, classes, data structures and so on (written by a another programmer), which they can use in their programs. Linux supports two classes of libraries, namely: Static libraries – are bound to a program statically at compile time; Dynamic or shared libraries – are loaded when a program is launched and loaded into memory and binding occurs at run time. Dynamic or shared libraries can further be categorized into: Dynamically linked libraries – here a program is linked with the shared library and the kernel loads the library (in case it’s not in memory) upon execution; Dynamically loaded libraries – the program takes full control by calling functions with the library. Shared libraries are named in two ways: the library name (a.k.a soname) and a “filename” (absolute path to file which stores library code). For example, the soname for libc is libc.so.6: where lib is the prefix, c is a descriptive name, so means shared object, and 6 is the version. And its filename is: /lib64/libc.so.6. Note that the soname is actually a symbolic link to the filename.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linux.com/news/understanding-shared-libraries-linux&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tecmint</name></author><category term="C standard library" /><category term="Library (computing)" /><category term="C (programming language)" /><category term="Digital technology" /><category term="Computing" /><category term="Computer programming" /><category term="Software" /><category term="Areas of computer science" /><category term="Software engineering" /><category term="Computers" /><category term="Computer engineering" /><category term="Software development" /><category term="Information technology management" /><summary type="html">Digest In programming, a library is an assortment of pre-compiled pieces of code that can be reused in a program. Libraries simplify life for programmers, in that they provide reusable functions, routines, classes, data structures and so on (written by a another programmer), which they can use in their programs. For instance, if you are building an application that needs to perform math operations, you don’t have to create a new math function for that, you can simply use existing functions in libraries for that programming language. Examples of libraries in Linux include libc (the standard C library) or glibc (GNU version of the standard C library), libcurl (multiprotocol file transfer library), libcrypt (library used for encryption, hashing, and encoding in C) and many more.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Migrating to Linux: An Introduction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/migrating-to-linux-an-introduction/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Migrating to Linux: An Introduction" /><published>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/migrating-to-linux-an-introduction</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/migrating-to-linux-an-introduction/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;digest&quot;&gt;Digest&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Computer systems running Linux are everywhere. Linux runs our Internet services, from Google search to Facebook, and more. Linux also runs in a lot of devices, including our smartphones, televisions, and even cars. Of course, Linux can also run on your desktop system. If you are new to Linux, or you would just like to try something different on your desktop computer, this series of guides will briefly cover the basics and help you in migrating to Linux from another system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;factsheet&quot;&gt;Factsheet&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In other operating systems, many things are bundled together and are just a part of the package. In Linux, however, each component is called out separately. For example, under Windows, the graphical interface is just a part of Windows. With Linux, you can choose from multiple graphical environments, like GNOME, KDE Plasma, Cinnamon, and MATE, to name a few. At a high level, a Linux installation includes the following things: The kernel; System programs and files residing on disk; A graphical environment; A package manager; Applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linux.com/blog/learn/intro-to-linux/2017/10/migrating-linux-introduction&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>JohnBonesio</name></author><category term="Linux" /><category term="Operating system" /><category term="Linux distribution" /><category term="Package manager" /><category term="Graphical user interface" /><category term="Application software" /><category term="Desktop environment" /><category term="Microsoft Windows" /><category term="Digital technology" /><category term="Operating system technology" /><category term="Computer architecture" /><category term="Operating system families" /><category term="Computer engineering" /><category term="Computers" /><category term="Software" /><category term="Digital media" /><category term="Computing" /><category term="System software" /><summary type="html">Digest Computer systems running Linux are everywhere. Linux runs our Internet services, from Google search to Facebook, and more. Linux also runs in a lot of devices, including our smartphones, televisions, and even cars. Of course, Linux can also run on your desktop system. If you are new to Linux, or you would just like to try something different on your desktop computer, this series of guides will briefly cover the basics and help you in migrating to Linux from another system.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How open science evolved in 2017</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/how-open-science-evolved-in-2017/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How open science evolved in 2017" /><published>2018-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/how-open-science-evolved-in-2017</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/how-open-science-evolved-in-2017/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;extract&quot;&gt;Extract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The scientific community has embraced openness since long before computers came on the scene. The ideals of sharing knowledge and building on the work of others are fundamental to how scientific discovery happens. This year, Opensource.com contributors shared some of the ways open source software and science teamed up. Check out the top six science articles on the site in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;3 open source alternatives to MATLAB&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;read more…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.com/article/17/12/best-open-science&quot;&gt;Visit Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>bcotton</name></author><category term="Open-source software" /><category term="Science" /><category term="Computing" /><category term="Red Hat" /><category term="Information Age" /><category term="Digital technology" /><category term="Software" /><category term="Technology" /><category term="Cyberspace" /><category term="Intellectual works" /><category term="Digital media" /><summary type="html">Extract The scientific community has embraced openness since long before computers came on the scene. The ideals of sharing knowledge and building on the work of others are fundamental to how scientific discovery happens. This year, Opensource.com contributors shared some of the ways open source software and science teamed up. Check out the top six science articles on the site in 2017. 3 open source alternatives to MATLAB</summary></entry></feed>