<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-08-01T10:58:33+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">data-1.science</title><subtitle>Science and Technology Articles</subtitle><entry><title type="html">United Nations recognizes first-ever carbon-neutral soccer club</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/united-nations-recognizes-first-ever-carbon-neutral-soccer-club/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="United Nations recognizes first-ever carbon-neutral soccer club" /><published>2018-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/united-nations-recognizes-first-ever-carbon-neutral-soccer-club</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/united-nations-recognizes-first-ever-carbon-neutral-soccer-club/">#### Extract
&gt;
The Forest Green Rovers, a Gloucestershire-based team in the English Football League that prides itself as &amp;#8220;the world&amp;#8217;s greenest football club,&amp;#8221; has been recognized by the United Nations carbon-neutral &amp;#8211; a world first. The team joined the Football League last year in its first-ever debut in the 129-year history of the club and is part of Britain&amp;#8217;s League Two.
In addition to receiving the prestigious UN designation, the professional soccer club has signed up for the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change&amp;#8217;s (UNFCCC) Climate Neutral Now initiative for the upcoming 2018-2019 season. The Climate Neutral Now initiative was developed in the wake of the Paris Agreement to encourage climate action ...



[Visit Link](https://inhabitat.com/united-nations-recognizes-first-ever-carbon-neutral-soccer-club)</content><author><name>Luciana Pricop</name></author><category term="Forest Green Rovers FC" /><category term="Carbon neutrality" /><category term="Natural environment" /><category term="Sustainability" /><category term="Nature" /><category term="Sustainable development" /><category term="Energy" /><category term="Economy" /><category term="Natural resources" /><summary type="html">Extract The Forest Green Rovers, a Gloucestershire-based team in the English Football League that prides itself as “the world’s greenest football club,” has been recognized by the United Nations carbon-neutral – a world first. The team joined the Football League last year in its first-ever debut in the 129-year history of the club and is part of Britain’s League Two. In addition to receiving the prestigious UN designation, the professional soccer club has signed up for the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change’s (UNFCCC) Climate Neutral Now initiative for the upcoming 2018-2019 season. The Climate Neutral Now initiative was developed in the wake of the Paris Agreement to encourage climate action …</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">This AI-Operated Robotic Hand Moves With “Unprecedented Dexterity”</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/this-ai-operated-robotic-hand-moves-with-unprecedented-dexterity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="This AI-Operated Robotic Hand Moves With “Unprecedented Dexterity”" /><published>2018-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/this-ai-operated-robotic-hand-moves-with-unprecedented-dexterity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/this-ai-operated-robotic-hand-moves-with-unprecedented-dexterity/">#### Extract
&gt;ROBOTIC HIGH FIVE. On Monday, researchers at OpenAI, the nonprofit AI research company co-founded by Elon Musk, introduced Dactyl, an AI system trained to control a robotic hand. According to the researchers, the system can manipulate physical objects in the hand with dexterity never before possible for AI.
The task Dactyl tackled might sound like something you&amp;#8217;d teach a toddler: take this six-sided block and move it around until a certain side is on top. Unlike a toddler, though, Dactyl needed more than a century&amp;#8217;s worth of experience to learn how to expertly complete the task. But thanks to powerful computers, the researchers were able to pack all that experience into just 50 &amp;#8220;real-world&amp;#8221; hours.
PRACTICE MAKES (ALM...



[Visit Link](https://futurism.com/openai-general-purpose-algorithms/)</content><author><name>Kristin Houser</name></author><category term="Artificial intelligence" /><category term="OpenAI" /><category term="Learning" /><category term="Cognition" /><category term="Areas of computer science" /><category term="Cognitive science" /><category term="Cybernetics" /><category term="Technology" /><category term="Computing" /><category term="Futurology" /><category term="Applied mathematics" /><category term="Computational neuroscience" /><category term="Computer science" /><category term="Emerging technologies" /><category term="Neuroscience" /><category term="Systems science" /><category term="Systems thinking" /><category term="Artificial objects" /><summary type="html">Extract ROBOTIC HIGH FIVE. On Monday, researchers at OpenAI, the nonprofit AI research company co-founded by Elon Musk, introduced Dactyl, an AI system trained to control a robotic hand. According to the researchers, the system can manipulate physical objects in the hand with dexterity never before possible for AI. The task Dactyl tackled might sound like something you’d teach a toddler: take this six-sided block and move it around until a certain side is on top. Unlike a toddler, though, Dactyl needed more than a century’s worth of experience to learn how to expertly complete the task. But thanks to powerful computers, the researchers were able to pack all that experience into just 50 “real-world” hours. PRACTICE MAKES (ALM…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Reasons Behind AI Companies’ Growth</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-reasons-behind-ai-companies-growth/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Reasons Behind AI Companies’ Growth" /><published>2018-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-reasons-behind-ai-companies-growth</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-reasons-behind-ai-companies-growth/">#### Extract
&gt;Artificial intelligence companies are growing at a much faster rate than expected. Technological giants in artificial intelligence predicted AI to be the technology of the future. Even they are surprised by the rapid growth of artificial intelligence. Now, artificial intelligence is touching almost every field of concern like a business, translation, advertising, photography and many more. 
What Is Artificial Intelligence? 
Artificial Intelligence is the branch of computer science that deals with making intelligent machines. These machines simulate human behavior and perform tasks that would require human intelligence. Artificial intelligence machines have the capability of reasoning, perception, problem-solving and decision making. Machine...



[Visit Link](https://dzone.com/articles/why-ai-companies-are-considered-as-the-best-growin?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone)</content><author><name>Ajay Thakur</name></author><summary type="html">Extract Artificial intelligence companies are growing at a much faster rate than expected. Technological giants in artificial intelligence predicted AI to be the technology of the future. Even they are surprised by the rapid growth of artificial intelligence. Now, artificial intelligence is touching almost every field of concern like a business, translation, advertising, photography and many more. What Is Artificial Intelligence? Artificial Intelligence is the branch of computer science that deals with making intelligent machines. These machines simulate human behavior and perform tasks that would require human intelligence. Artificial intelligence machines have the capability of reasoning, perception, problem-solving and decision making. Machine…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Researchers review the rapid progress in machine learning for the chemical sciences</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/researchers-review-the-rapid-progress-in-machine-learning-for-the-chemical-sciences/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Researchers review the rapid progress in machine learning for the chemical sciences" /><published>2018-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/researchers-review-the-rapid-progress-in-machine-learning-for-the-chemical-sciences</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/researchers-review-the-rapid-progress-in-machine-learning-for-the-chemical-sciences/">#### Extract
&gt;A new tool is drastically changing the face of chemical research – artificial intelligence. In a new paper published in Nature, researchers review the rapid progress in machine learning for the chemical sciences....



[Visit Link](https://phys.org/news/2018-07-rapid-machine-chemical-sciences.html)</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="Artificial intelligence" /><category term="Machine learning" /><category term="Science" /><category term="Scientific method" /><category term="Technology" /><category term="Intelligence" /><category term="Research" /><category term="Chemical substance" /><category term="Learning" /><category term="Computer" /><category term="Artificial objects" /><category term="Science and technology" /><category term="Cognition" /><category term="Culture" /><category term="Cognitive science" /><summary type="html">Extract A new tool is drastically changing the face of chemical research – artificial intelligence. In a new paper published in Nature, researchers review the rapid progress in machine learning for the chemical sciences….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Next-generation photodetector camera to deploy during robotic servicing demonstration mission</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/next-generation-photodetector-camera-to-deploy-during-robotic-servicing-demonstration-mission/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Next-generation photodetector camera to deploy during robotic servicing demonstration mission" /><published>2018-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/next-generation-photodetector-camera-to-deploy-during-robotic-servicing-demonstration-mission</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/next-generation-photodetector-camera-to-deploy-during-robotic-servicing-demonstration-mission/">#### Extract
&gt;Testing tools and technologies for refueling and repairing satellites in orbit won't be the only demonstration taking place aboard the International Space Station during NASA's next Robotic Refueling Mission 3, or RRM3....



[Visit Link](https://phys.org/news/2018-07-next-generation-photodetector-camera-deploy-robotic.html)</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="Landsat 8" /><category term="NASA" /><category term="Infrared" /><category term="Physical sciences" /><summary type="html">Extract Testing tools and technologies for refueling and repairing satellites in orbit won’t be the only demonstration taking place aboard the International Space Station during NASA’s next Robotic Refueling Mission 3, or RRM3….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mars terraforming not possible using present-day technology</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mars-terraforming-not-possible-using-present-day-technology/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mars terraforming not possible using present-day technology" /><published>2018-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mars-terraforming-not-possible-using-present-day-technology</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mars-terraforming-not-possible-using-present-day-technology/">#### Extract
&gt;(NASA/Goddard Space Flight Center) Science fiction writers have long featured terraforming, the process of creating an Earth-like or habitable environment on another planet, in their stories. Scientists themselves have proposed terraforming to enable the long-term colonization of Mars. A solution common to both groups is to release carbon dioxide gas trapped in the Martian surface to thicken the atmosphere and act as a blanket to warm the planet....



[Visit Link](https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2018-07/nsfc-mtn073018.php)</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="Mars" /><category term="Water on Mars" /><category term="Atmosphere of Earth" /><category term="Atmosphere of Mars" /><category term="MAVEN" /><category term="Terraforming" /><category term="Water" /><category term="Astronomy" /><category term="Solar System" /><category term="Space science" /><category term="Physical sciences" /><category term="Nature" /><category term="Planets of the Solar System" /><category term="Planetary science" /><category term="Outer space" /><summary type="html">Extract (NASA/Goddard Space Flight Center) Science fiction writers have long featured terraforming, the process of creating an Earth-like or habitable environment on another planet, in their stories. Scientists themselves have proposed terraforming to enable the long-term colonization of Mars. A solution common to both groups is to release carbon dioxide gas trapped in the Martian surface to thicken the atmosphere and act as a blanket to warm the planet….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mapping of magnetic particles in the human brain</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mapping-of-magnetic-particles-in-the-human-brain/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mapping of magnetic particles in the human brain" /><published>2018-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mapping-of-magnetic-particles-in-the-human-brain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mapping-of-magnetic-particles-in-the-human-brain/">#### Extract
&gt;(Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität München) LMU researchers have for the first time mapped the distribution of magnetic particles in the human brain. The study reveals that the particles are primarily located in the cerebellum and the brainstem, which are the more ancient parts of the brain....



[Visit Link](https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2018-07/lm-mom073118.php)</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="Brain" /><category term="Science" /><category term="Research" /><category term="Magnetism" /><category term="American Association for the Advancement of Science" /><category term="Ludwig Maximilian University of Munich" /><category term="Neuroscience" /><category term="Cognitive science" /><category term="Nervous system" /><category term="Cognition" /><summary type="html">Extract (Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität München) LMU researchers have for the first time mapped the distribution of magnetic particles in the human brain. The study reveals that the particles are primarily located in the cerebellum and the brainstem, which are the more ancient parts of the brain….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Machine Learning: In Plain English</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/machine-learning-in-plain-english/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Machine Learning: In Plain English" /><published>2018-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/machine-learning-in-plain-english</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/machine-learning-in-plain-english/">#### Extract
&gt;In this article, I will describe how analytics is related to Machine Learning. I'll try to demystify some of the nonsense around ML, and explain the process and types of machine learning. Finally, I'll share a couple of videos which describe the next level of Artificial Intelligence - Deep Learning.
Don’t worry if you're not an artificial intelligence expert — I won’t ever mention Linear Regression and K-Means Clustering again. This is an article in plain English....



[Visit Link](https://dzone.com/articles/machine-learning-in-plain-english?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone)</content><author><name>John Ryan</name></author><summary type="html">Extract In this article, I will describe how analytics is related to Machine Learning. I’ll try to demystify some of the nonsense around ML, and explain the process and types of machine learning. Finally, I’ll share a couple of videos which describe the next level of Artificial Intelligence - Deep Learning. Don’t worry if you’re not an artificial intelligence expert — I won’t ever mention Linear Regression and K-Means Clustering again. This is an article in plain English….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LHC accelerates its first ‘atoms’</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lhc-accelerates-its-first-atoms/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LHC accelerates its first 'atoms'" /><published>2018-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lhc-accelerates-its-first-atoms</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lhc-accelerates-its-first-atoms/">#### Extract
&gt;Protons might be the Large Hadron Collider's bread and butter, but that doesn't mean it can't crave more exotic tastes from time to time. On Wednesday, 25 July, for the very first time, operators injected not just atomic nuclei but lead &quot;atoms&quot; containing a single electron into the LHC. This was one of the first proof-of-principle tests for a new idea called the Gamma Factory, part of CERN's Physics Beyond Colliders project....



[Visit Link](https://phys.org/news/2018-07-lhc-atoms.html)</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="Large Hadron Collider" /><category term="Particle accelerator" /><category term="CERN" /><category term="Particle beam" /><category term="Super Proton Synchrotron" /><category term="Electron" /><category term="Gamma ray" /><category term="Synchrotron" /><category term="Proton" /><category term="Electrodynamics" /><category term="Electromagnetic radiation" /><category term="Nature" /><category term="Chemistry" /><category term="Particle physics" /><category term="Physical sciences" /><category term="Applied and interdisciplinary physics" /><category term="Physics" /><summary type="html">Extract Protons might be the Large Hadron Collider’s bread and butter, but that doesn’t mean it can’t crave more exotic tastes from time to time. On Wednesday, 25 July, for the very first time, operators injected not just atomic nuclei but lead “atoms” containing a single electron into the LHC. This was one of the first proof-of-principle tests for a new idea called the Gamma Factory, part of CERN’s Physics Beyond Colliders project….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Homo sapiens developed a new ecological niche that separated it from other hominins</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/homo-sapiens-developed-a-new-ecological-niche-that-separated-it-from-other-hominins/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Homo sapiens developed a new ecological niche that separated it from other hominins" /><published>2018-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/homo-sapiens-developed-a-new-ecological-niche-that-separated-it-from-other-hominins</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/homo-sapiens-developed-a-new-ecological-niche-that-separated-it-from-other-hominins/">#### Extract
&gt;Critical review of growing archaeological and palaeoenvironmental datasets relating to the Middle and Late Pleistocene (300-12 thousand years ago) hominin dispersals within and beyond Africa, published today in Nature Human Behaviour, demonstrates unique environmental settings and adaptations for Homo sapiens relative to previous and coexisting hominins such as Homo neanderthalensis and Homo erectus. Our species' ability to occupy diverse and 'extreme' settings around the world stands in stark contrast to the ecological adaptations of other hominin taxa, and may explain how our species became the last surviving hominin on the planet....



[Visit Link](https://phys.org/news/2018-07-homo-sapiens-ecological-niche-hominins.html)</content><author><name>unknown author</name></author><category term="Homo" /><category term="Human" /><category term="Homo sapiens" /><category term="Homo erectus" /><category term="Ecology" /><category term="Homo floresiensis" /><category term="Human evolution" /><category term="Neanderthal" /><summary type="html">Extract Critical review of growing archaeological and palaeoenvironmental datasets relating to the Middle and Late Pleistocene (300-12 thousand years ago) hominin dispersals within and beyond Africa, published today in Nature Human Behaviour, demonstrates unique environmental settings and adaptations for Homo sapiens relative to previous and coexisting hominins such as Homo neanderthalensis and Homo erectus. Our species’ ability to occupy diverse and ‘extreme’ settings around the world stands in stark contrast to the ecological adaptations of other hominin taxa, and may explain how our species became the last surviving hominin on the planet….</summary></entry></feed>